[
    {
        "question": "A 50 ton twin engine aeroplane performs a straight , steady , wings level climb. If the lift/drag ratio is 12 and the thrust is\n60.000 N per engine , the climb gradient is ; ( assume g = 10 m/s\u00b2 )\n",
        "answer": "15.7%.\n",
        "choiceone": "12%.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3.7%.\n",
        "choicethree": "24%.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A body is placed in a certain airstream. The airstream velocity increases by a factor 4. The aerodynamic drag will increase\nwith a factor ;\n",
        "answer": "16.\n",
        "choiceone": "12.\n",
        "choicetwo": "8.\n",
        "choicethree": "4.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A body is placed in a certain airstream. The density of the airstream decreases to half of the original value. The aerodynamic\ndrag will decrease with a factor ;\n",
        "answer": "2.\n",
        "choiceone": "1.4.\n",
        "choicetwo": "4.\n",
        "choicethree": "8.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A boundary layer fence on a swept wing will ;\n",
        "answer": "improve the low speed characteristics.\n",
        "choiceone": "improve the lift coefficient of the trailing edge flap.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase the critical Mach Number.\n",
        "choicethree": "improve the high speed characteristics.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A CG location beyond the aft limit leads to ;\n",
        "answer": "an unacceptable low value of the manoeuvre stability ( stick force per g , Fe/g ).\n",
        "choiceone": "a too high pulling stick force during rotation in the take off.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an increasing static longitudinal stability.\n",
        "choicethree": "a better recovery performance in the spin.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A commercial jet aeroplane is performing a straight descent at a constant Mach number with constant mass. The operational\nspeed limit that may be exceeded is ;\n",
        "answer": "VMO.\n",
        "choiceone": "VNE.\n",
        "choicetwo": "MMO.\n",
        "choicethree": "VD.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A conventional stabiliser on a stable aeroplane in a normal cruise condition ;\n 1. always provides negative lift.\n 2. contributes to the total lift of the aeroplane.\n 3. may stall before the wing , in icing conditions , with large flap settings , unless adequate design and/or\n operational precautions are taken.\n 4. is necessary to balance the total pitch moment of the aeroplane.\n Which of the following lists all the correct statements ?\n",
        "answer": "2 , 3 and 4.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 and 4.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 , 3 and 4.\n",
        "choicethree": "1 and 3.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A downward adjustment of a trim tab in the longitudinal control system , has the following effect ;\n",
        "answer": "the stick position stability remains constant.\n",
        "choiceone": "the stick position stability increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the stick force stability remains constant.\n",
        "choicethree": "the stick force stability decreases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A flat plate , when positioned in the airflow at a small angle of attack , will produce ;\n",
        "answer": "both lift and drag.\n",
        "choiceone": "lift but no drag.\n",
        "choicetwo": "neither lift nor drag.\n",
        "choicethree": "drag but no lift.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A forward CG shift ;\n",
        "answer": "increases static longitudinal stability.\n",
        "choiceone": "decreases static longitudinal stability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "has no influence on longitudinal manoeuvrability.\n",
        "choicethree": "increases longitudinal manoeuvrability.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A forward CG shift ;\n",
        "answer": "decreases longitudinal manoeuvrability.\n",
        "choiceone": "increases longitudinal manoeuvrability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decreases static longitudinal stability.\n",
        "choicethree": "has no influence on static longitudinal stability.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A fundamental difference between the manoeuvring limit load factor and the gust limit load factor is , that ;\n",
        "answer": "the gust limit load factor can be higher than the manoeuvring limit load factor.\n",
        "choiceone": "the gust limit load factor has a fixed value for every transport aeroplane , whereas the manoeuvring limit load\n factor has not.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the gust limit load factor is independent of the wing\u2019s aspect ratio , whereas the manoeuvring limit load factor\n is not.\n",
        "choicethree": "the manoeuvring limit load factor is independent of the size of the aeroplane , whereas the numerical value of\n the gust limit load factor is laid down in the regulations.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A high aspect ratio wing produces ;\n",
        "answer": "a decrease in induced drag\n",
        "choiceone": "less sensitivity to gust effects\n",
        "choicetwo": "an increase in induced drag\n",
        "choicethree": "a decrease in stall speed\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A horn balance in a control system has the following purpose ;\n",
        "answer": "to decrease stick forces.\n",
        "choiceone": "to obtain mass balancing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "to decrease the effective longitudinal dihedral of the aeroplane.\n",
        "choicethree": "to prevent flutter.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A jet aeroplane cruises buffet free at high constant altitude. Which type of stall can occur if this aeroplane decelerates during\nan inadvertent increase in load factor ?\n",
        "answer": "Accelerated stall.\n",
        "choiceone": "Deep stall.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Shock stall.\n",
        "choicethree": "Low speed stall.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A jet aeroplane equipped with inboard and outboard ailerons is cruising at its normal cruise Mach number. In this case ;\n",
        "answer": "only the inboard ailerons are active.\n",
        "choiceone": "only the outboard aileron are active.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only the spoilers will be active , not the ailerons.\n",
        "choicethree": "the inboard and outboard ailerons are active.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A jet aeroplane is cruising at high altitude with a Mach-number , that provides a buffet margin of 0.3 g incremental. In order\nto increase the buffet margin to 0.4 g incremental the pilot must ;\n",
        "answer": "fly at a lower altitude and the same Mach-number\n",
        "choiceone": "fly at a larger angle of attack\n",
        "choicetwo": "extend the flaps to the first selection\n",
        "choicethree": "fly at a higher Mach-number\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A jet transport aeroplane exhibits pitch up when thrust is suddenly increased from an equilibrium condition , because the\nthrust line is below the ;\n",
        "answer": "CG.\n",
        "choiceone": "drag line of action.\n",
        "choicetwo": "neutral point.\n",
        "choicethree": "centre of pressure.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A jet transport aeroplane is in a straight climb at a constant IAS and constant weight. The operational limit that may be\nexceeded is ;\n",
        "answer": "MMO.\n",
        "choiceone": "VMO.\n",
        "choicetwo": "MD.\n",
        "choicethree": "VA.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use Image 1 )\n FL350\n 0.84\n Image 1\n A jet transport aeroplane weighing 100 tons carries out a steady level 50 degree bank turn at FL350. The buffet free speed\nrange from low speed to high speed buffet extends from ;\n",
        "answer": "M 0.69 to > M 0.84\n",
        "choiceone": "M 0.65 to > M 0.84\n",
        "choicetwo": "M 0.72 to > M 0.84\n",
        "choicethree": "M 0.74 to M 0.84\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A laminar boundary layer is a layer , in which ;\n",
        "answer": "no velocity components exist , normal to the surface.\n",
        "choiceone": "the temperature varies constantly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the vortices are weak.\n",
        "choicethree": "the velocity is constant.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A large jet transport aeroplane has the following four flap positions : Up , Take-off , Approach and Landing and two slat\npositions : Retracted and Extended. Generally speaking , the selection that provides the highest positive contribution to CLMAX is ;\n",
        "answer": "slats from Retracted to Extended.\n",
        "choiceone": "flaps from Up to Take-off.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flaps from Take-off to Approach.\n",
        "choicethree": "flaps from Approach to Landing.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A light twin is in a turn at 20 degrees bank and 150 kt TAS. A more heavy aeroplane at the same bank and the same speed\nwill ;\n",
        "answer": "turn at the same turn radius.\n",
        "choiceone": "turn at a bigger turn radius.\n",
        "choicetwo": "turn at a smaller turn radius.\n",
        "choicethree": "turn at a higher turn rate.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cA line connecting the leading- and trailing edge midway between the upper and lower surface of a aerofoil\u201d. This definition\nis applicable for ;\n",
        "answer": "the camber line.\n",
        "choiceone": "the chord line.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the mean aerodynamic chord line.\n",
        "choicethree": "the upper camber line.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A Machtrimmer ;\n",
        "answer": "corrects insufficient stick force stability at high Mach Numbers.\n",
        "choiceone": "increases the stick force per g at high Mach Numbers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is necessary for compensation of the autopilot at high Mach Numbers.\n",
        "choicethree": "has no effect on the shape of the elevator position versus speed ( IAS ) curve for a fully hydraulic controlled\n aeroplane.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A negative contribution to the static longitudinal stability of conventional jet transport aeroplanes is provided by ;\n",
        "answer": "the fuselage.\n",
        "choiceone": "a fixed elevator deflection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the tail.\n",
        "choicethree": "a fixed trim position.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A normal shock wave ;\n",
        "answer": "can occur at different points on the aeroplane in transonic flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "is a discontinuity plane in an airflow , in which the pressure drops suddenly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is a discontinuity plane in an airflow , which is always normal to the surface.\n",
        "choicethree": "is a discontinuity plane in an airflow , in which the temperature drops suddenly.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A normal shock wave is a discontinuity plane ;\n",
        "answer": "that is always normal to the local flow.\n",
        "choiceone": "that is always normal to the surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "across which the temperature drops suddenly.\n",
        "choicethree": "across which the pressure drops suddenly.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A plain flap will increase CLmax by ;\n",
        "answer": "increasing the camber of the aerofoil.\n",
        "choiceone": "boundary layer control.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increasing angle of attack.\n",
        "choicethree": "centre of lift movement.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A positively cambered aerofoil will generate zero lift ;\n",
        "answer": "at a negative angle of attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "at zero angle of attack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "at a positive angle of attack.\n",
        "choicethree": "it can never generate zero lift.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A propeller is turning to the right when viewed from behind. The asymmetric blade effect in the climb at low speed will ;\n",
        "answer": "yaw the aeroplane to the left.\n",
        "choiceone": "roll the aeroplane to the right.\n",
        "choicetwo": "yaw the aeroplane to the right.\n",
        "choicethree": "roll the aeroplane to the left.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 7 )\n Image 7\n A rotating propeller blade element produces an aerodynamic force F that may be resolved into two components ; - a force T\nperpendicular to the plane of rotation ( thrust ) , - a force R generating a torque absorbed by engine power. The diagram representing a\nrotating propeller blade element during reverse operation is ;\n",
        "answer": "diagram 2.\n",
        "choiceone": "diagram 1.\n",
        "choicetwo": "diagram 4.\n",
        "choicethree": "diagram 3.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 7 )\n Image 7\n A rotating propeller blade element produces an aerodynamic force F that may be resolved into two components ; - a force T\nperpendicular to the plane of rotation ( thrust ) , - a force R generating a torque absorbed by engine power. The diagram representing a\nrotating propeller blade element during the cruise is ;\n",
        "answer": "diagram 1.\n",
        "choiceone": "diagram 2.\n",
        "choicetwo": "diagram 3.\n",
        "choicethree": "diagram 4.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 7 )\n Image 7\n A rotating propeller blade element produces an aerodynamic force F that may be resolved into two components ; - a force T\nperpendicular to the plane of rotation ( thrust ) , - a force R generating a torque absorbed by engine power. The diagram representing a\nwindmilling propeller is ;\n",
        "answer": "diagram 4.\n",
        "choiceone": "diagram 1.\n",
        "choicetwo": "diagram 3.\n",
        "choicethree": "diagram 2.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 7 )\n Image 7\n A rotating propeller blade element produces an aerodynamic force F that may be resolved into two components ; - a force T\nperpendicular to the plane of rotation ( thrust ) , - a force R generating a torque absorbed by engine power. Which diagram is correct\nduring the cruise ?\n",
        "answer": "diagram 1.\n",
        "choiceone": "diagram 3.\n",
        "choicetwo": "diagram 2.\n",
        "choicethree": "diagram 4.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A shock wave on a lift generating wing will ;\n",
        "answer": "move slightly aft in front of a downward deflecting aileron.\n",
        "choiceone": "reach its highest strength when flying at the critical Mach number.\n",
        "choicetwo": "move forward as Mach number is increased.\n",
        "choicethree": "be situated at the greatest wing thickness when the aeroplane reaches the speed of sound.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A slat will ;\n",
        "answer": "prolongs the stall to a higher angle of attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase the lift by increasing the wing area and the camber of the aft portion of the wing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase the camber of the aerofoil and divert the flow around the sharp leading edge.\n",
        "choicethree": "provide a boundary layer suction on the upper surface of the wing.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A slotted flap will increase the CLmax by ;\n",
        "answer": "increasing the camber of the aerofoil and re-energising the airflow.\n",
        "choiceone": "increasing the critical angle of attack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increasing only the camber of the aerofoil.\n",
        "choicethree": "decreasing the skin friction.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A statically stable aeroplane ;\n",
        "answer": "can show positive , neutral or negative dynamic longitudinal stability.\n",
        "choiceone": "will never show positive dynamic longitudinal stability , but always neutral dynamic longitudinal stability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is never dynamically stable.\n",
        "choicethree": "is always dynamically stable.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A statically unstable aeroplane is ;\n",
        "answer": "never dynamically stable.\n",
        "choiceone": "sometimes dynamically stable.\n",
        "choicetwo": "always dynamically stable.\n",
        "choicethree": "sometimes dynamically unstable.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A stick pusher ;\n",
        "answer": "pushes the elevator control forward when a specified value of angle of attack is exceeded.\n",
        "choiceone": "vibrates the elevator control.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pushes the elevator control forward prior to stick shaker activation.\n",
        "choicethree": "pushes the elevator control to avoid a stall at a negative load factor.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A supercritical wing ;\n",
        "answer": "will develop no noticeable shock waves when flying just above Mcrit.\n",
        "choiceone": "will be free of Mach buffet in the transonic range.\n",
        "choicetwo": "always cruises at Mcrit.\n",
        "choicethree": "will develop no transonic flow just above Mcrit.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A transonic Mach number is a Mach number ;\n",
        "answer": "at which both subsonic and supersonic local speeds occur.\n",
        "choiceone": "in the range between Mcrit and MMO.\n",
        "choicetwo": "at which only supersonic local speeds occur.\n",
        "choicethree": "between the buffet onset Mach number and the Mach number corresponding to total supersonic flow.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 28 )\n Image 28\n A typical curve representing propeller efficiency of a fixed pitch propeller versus TAS at constant RPM is ;\n",
        "answer": "diagram 1.\n",
        "choiceone": "diagram 3.\n",
        "choicetwo": "diagram 2.\n",
        "choicethree": "diagram 4.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 29 )\n Image 29\n A typical curve representing propeller efficiency of a fixed pitch propeller versus TAS at constant RPM is ;\n",
        "answer": "diagram 4.\n",
        "choiceone": "diagram 1.\n",
        "choicetwo": "diagram 2.\n",
        "choicethree": "diagram 3.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "A windmilling propeller ;\n",
        "answer": "produces drag instead of thrust.\n",
        "choiceone": "has a greater blade angle than a feathered propeller.\n",
        "choicetwo": "improves the glide performance of an aeroplane.\n",
        "choicethree": "produces neither thrust nor drag.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aeroplane manoeuvrability decreases for a given control surface deflection when ;\n",
        "answer": "IAS decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "IAS increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flaps are retracted at constant IAS.\n",
        "choicethree": "the CG moves aft.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aeroplane manoeuvrability increases for a given control surface deflection when ;\n",
        "answer": "IAS increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "the CG moves forward.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flaps are retracted at constant IAS.\n",
        "choicethree": "IAS decreases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "After an aeroplane has been trimmed ;\n",
        "answer": "the stick position stability will be unchanged.\n",
        "choiceone": "the stick position stability will be increased.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the trim-tab will always be deflected in the same direction as the control surface itself.\n",
        "choicethree": "the stick force per g is reduced.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "After take-off the slats ( when installed ) are always retracted later than the flaps. Why ?\n",
        "answer": "Because SLATS EXTENDED gives a large decrease in stall speed with relatively less drag.\n",
        "choiceone": "Because FLAPS EXTENDED gives a large decrease in stall speed with relatively less drag.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Because VMCA with SLATS EXTENDED is more favourable compared to the FLAPS EXTENDED\n situation.\n",
        "choicethree": "Because SLATS EXTENDED provides a better view from the cockpit than FLAPS EXTENDED.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "After the transition point between the laminar and turbulent boundary layer ;\n",
        "answer": "the mean speed and friction drag increases\n",
        "choiceone": "the boundary layer gets thinner and the speed increases\n",
        "choicetwo": "the mean speed increases and the friction drag decreases\n",
        "choicethree": "the boundary layer gets thicker and the speed decreases\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aileron deflection causes a rotation around the longitudinal axis by ;\n",
        "answer": "changing the wing camber and two wings therefore produce different lift values resulting in a moment about\n the longitudinal axis.\n",
        "choiceone": "causing sideslip , which generates a rolling moment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "changing the wing drag and two wings therefore produce different lift values resulting in a moment about the\n longitudinal axis.\n",
        "choicethree": "aieron secondary effect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aileron flutter can be caused by ;\n",
        "answer": "cyclic deformations generated by aerodynamic , inertial and elastic loads on the wing.\n",
        "choiceone": "aileron reversal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the elastic centre of the wing section coinciding with the centre of gravity of that wing section.\n",
        "choicethree": "continuous deformations in one direction generated by bending and twisting of the wing.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Air passes a normal shock wave. Which of the following statements is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The static temperature increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "The velocity increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The static pressure decreases.\n",
        "choicethree": "The static temperature decreases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "All gust lines in the V-n graph originate from a point where the ;\n",
        "answer": "speed = 0 , load factor = +1\n",
        "choiceone": "speed = VB , load factor = +1\n",
        "choicetwo": "speed = VS , load factor = 0\n",
        "choicethree": "speed = 0 , load factor = 0\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Amongst the following factors , which will decrease the ground distance covered during a glide ( assume zero\npower/thrust ) ?\n",
        "answer": "Headwind.\n",
        "choiceone": "Tailwind.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An increase in aeroplane mass.\n",
        "choicethree": "A decrease in aeroplane mass.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 1 )\n FL35\n 0.8\n Image 1\n An A 310 aeroplane weighing 100 tons is turning at FL 350 at constant altitude with a bank of 50 degrees. Its flight Mach\nrange between low-speed buffeting and high-speed buffeting goes from ;\n",
        "answer": "M = 0.69 to M higher than 0.84\n",
        "choiceone": "M = 0.72 to M higher than 0.84\n",
        "choicetwo": "M = 0.65 to M higher than 0.84\n",
        "choicethree": "M = 0.74 to M = 0.84\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An advantage of locating the engines at the rear of the fuselage , in comparison to a location beneath the wing , is ;\n",
        "answer": "less influence of thrust changes on longitudinal control.\n",
        "choiceone": "a wing which is less sensitive to flutter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "easier maintenance of the engines.\n",
        "choicethree": "less influence on lateral/directional stability characteristics such as dutch roll.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aerofoil is cambered when ;\n",
        "answer": "the line , which connects the centres of all inscribed circles , is curved.\n",
        "choiceone": "the upper surface of the aerofoil is curved.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the maximum thickness is large compared with the length of the chord.\n",
        "choicethree": "the chord line is curved.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aerofoil with positive camber at a positive angle of attack will have the highest flow velocity ;\n",
        "answer": "on the upper side.\n",
        "choiceone": "at the trailing edge.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on the lower side.\n",
        "choicethree": "in front of the stagnation point.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane accelerates from 80 kt to 160 kt at a load factor equal to 1. The induced drag coefficient (i) and the induced\ndrag (ii) alter with the following factors ;\n",
        "answer": "(i) 1/16 , (ii) 1/4\n",
        "choiceone": "(i) 1/2 , (ii) 1/16\n",
        "choicetwo": "(i) 1/4 , (ii) 2\n",
        "choicethree": "(i) 4 , (ii) 1/2\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane , being manually flown in the speed unstable region , experiences a disturbance that causes a speed reduction.\nIf the altitude is maintained and thrust remains constant , the aeroplane speed will ;\n",
        "answer": "further decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "initially increase and thereafter decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase.\n",
        "choicethree": "initially further decrease and thereafter increase.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane climbs to cruising level with a constant pitch attitude and maximum climb thrust , ( assume no supercharger ).\nHow do the following variables change during the climb ? ( gamma = flight path angle )\n",
        "answer": "gamma decreases , angle of attack increases , IAS decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "gamma decreases , angle of attack increases , IAS remains constant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "gamma decreases , angle of attack remains constant , IAS decreases.\n",
        "choicethree": "gamma remains constant , angle of attack remains constant , IAS decreases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane enters a horizontal turn with a load factor n = 2 from straight and level flight whilst maintaining constant\nindicated airspeed. The ;\n",
        "answer": "lift doubles.\n",
        "choiceone": "lift becomes four times its original value.\n",
        "choicetwo": "induced drag doubles.\n",
        "choicethree": "total drag becomes four times its original value.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane exhibits static longitudinal stability , if , when the angle of attack changes ;\n",
        "answer": "the change in total aeroplane lift acts aft of the centre of gravity.\n",
        "choiceone": "the change in total aeroplane lift acts through the centre of gravity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the change in wing lift is equal to the change in tail lift.\n",
        "choicethree": "the resulting moment is positive.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane flying at 100 kt in straight and level flight is subjected to a disturbance that suddenly increases the speed by 20\nkt. Assuming the angle of attack remains constant , the load factor will initially ;\n",
        "answer": "increase to 1.44.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase to 1.10.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase to 1.21.\n",
        "choicethree": "remain unchanged , since the angle of attack does not change.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane has a servo tab controlled elevator. What will happen if the elevator jams during flight ?\n",
        "answer": "Pitch control sense is reversed.\n",
        "choiceone": "The servo-tab now works as a negative trim-tab.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The pitch control forces double.\n",
        "choicethree": "Pitch control is lost.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane has a stall speed of 78 KCAS at its gross weight of 6850 Ibs. What is the stall speed when the weight is 5000\nIbs ?\n",
        "answer": "67 KCAS\n",
        "choiceone": "78 KCAS\n",
        "choicetwo": "57 KCAS\n",
        "choicethree": "91 KCAS\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane has a stall speed of 78 kt at its mass of 6850 kg. What is the stall speed when the mass is 5000 kg ?\n",
        "answer": "67 kt.\n",
        "choiceone": "91 kt.\n",
        "choicetwo": "78 kt.\n",
        "choicethree": "57 kt.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane has a stall speed of 100 kt at a load factor n = 1. In a turn with a load factor of n = 2 , the stall speed is ;\n",
        "answer": "141 kt\n",
        "choiceone": "282 kt\n",
        "choicetwo": "200 kt\n",
        "choicethree": "70 kt\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane has a stall speed of 100 kt at a mass of 1000 kg. If the mass is increased to 2000 kg , the new value of the stall\nspeed will be ;\n",
        "answer": "141 kt.\n",
        "choiceone": "123 kt.\n",
        "choicetwo": "150 kt.\n",
        "choicethree": "200 kt.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane has a stall speed of 100 kt. When the aeroplane is flying a level co-ordinated turn with a load factor of 1.5 , the\nstall speed is ;\n",
        "answer": "122 kt.\n",
        "choiceone": "141 kt.\n",
        "choicetwo": "150 kt.\n",
        "choicethree": "82 kt.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane has a stalling speed of 100 kt in a steady level flight. When the aeroplane is flying a level turn with a load\nfactor of 1.5 , the stalling speed is ;\n",
        "answer": "122 kt.\n",
        "choiceone": "82 kt.\n",
        "choicetwo": "141 kt.\n",
        "choicethree": "150 kt.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane has static directional stability if , when in a sideslip with the relative airflow coming from the left , initially\nthe ;\n",
        "answer": "nose of the aeroplane tends to yaw left.\n",
        "choiceone": "nose of the aeroplane does not move.\n",
        "choicetwo": "nose of the aeroplane tends to yaw right.\n",
        "choicethree": "right wing tnds to go down.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane has static directional stability , in a side-slip to the right , initially the ;\n",
        "answer": "nose of the aeroplane tends to move to the right.\n",
        "choiceone": "nose of the aeroplane will remain in the same direction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "nose of the aeroplane tends to move to the left.\n",
        "choicethree": "right wing tends to go down.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane has the following flap positions : 0\u00b0 , 15\u00b0 , 30\u00b0 , 45\u00b0. Slats can also be selected. Generally speaking , which\nselection provides the highest positive contribution to the CLMAX ?\n",
        "answer": "The slats from the retracted to the take-off position.\n",
        "choiceone": "The flaps from 30\u00b0 to 45\u00b0.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The flaps from 0\u00b0 to 15\u00b0.\n",
        "choicethree": "The flaps from 15\u00b0 to 30\u00b0.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane has the following flap settings : 0\u00b0 , 15\u00b0 , 30\u00b0 and 45\u00b0. Slats can also be selected. Which of the following\nselections will most adversely affect the CL/CD ratio ?\n",
        "answer": "Flaps from 30\u00b0 to 45\u00b0.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flaps from 15\u00b0 to 30\u00b0.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The slats.\n",
        "choicethree": "Flaps from 0\u00b0 to 15\u00b0.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane in straight and level flight at 300 kt is subjected to a sudden disturbance in speed. Assuming the angle of attack\nremains constant initially and the load factor reaches a value of approximately 1.2 ;\n",
        "answer": "the speed will have increased by 30 kt.\n",
        "choiceone": "the speed will have decreased by 60 kt.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the speed will have decreased by 30 kt.\n",
        "choicethree": "the speed will have increased by 60 kt.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane in straight and level flight is subjected to a strong vertical gust. The point on the wing , where the instantaneous\nvariation in wing lift effectively acts is known as the ;\n",
        "answer": "aerodynamic centre of the wing.\n",
        "choiceone": "centre of thrust.\n",
        "choicetwo": "neutral point.\n",
        "choicethree": "centre of gravity.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane is descending at a constant Mach number from FL 350. What is the effect on true airspeed ?\n",
        "answer": "It increases as temperature increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "It decreases as altitude decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It decreases as pressure increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "It remains constant.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane is fitted with a constant speed propeller. If the aeroplane speed increases while manifold pressure remains\nconstant (1) propeller pitch and the (2) propeller torque will ;\n",
        "answer": "(1) increase , (2) remain constant.\n",
        "choiceone": "(1) decrease , (2) decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "(1) decrease , (2) remain constant.\n",
        "choicethree": "(1) increase , (2) increase.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane is flying through the transonic range. As the Mach Number increases the centre of pressure of the wing will\nmove aft. This movement requires ;\n",
        "answer": "a pitch up input of the stabilizer.\n",
        "choiceone": "much more thrust from the engine.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a stability augmentation system to improve dynamic stability.\n",
        "choicethree": "a higher IAS to compensate the nose down effect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane is flying through the transonic range whilst maintaining straight and level flight. As the Mach number increases\nthe centre of pressure of the wing will move aft. This movement requires ;\n",
        "answer": "a pitch up input of the stabiliser.\n",
        "choiceone": "much more thrust from the engines.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a higher IAS to compensate the nose down effect.\n",
        "choicethree": "a stability augmentation system to improve dynamic stability.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane is in a level turn , at a constant TAS of 300 kt , and a bank angle of 45\u00b0. Its turning radius is ; ( given : g = 10\nm/s\u00b2 )\n",
        "answer": "2381 metres.\n",
        "choiceone": "4743 metres.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3354 metres.\n",
        "choicethree": "9000 metres.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane is in a steady horizontal turn at a TAS of 194.4 kt. The turn radius is 1000 m. The bank angle is ; ( assume g =\n10 m/sec2 )\n",
        "answer": "45\u00b0\n",
        "choiceone": "60\u00b0\n",
        "choicetwo": "30\u00b0\n",
        "choicethree": "50\u00b0\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane is provided with spoilers and in- and outboard ailerons. Roll control during cruise is provided by ;\n",
        "answer": "inboard ailerons and roll-spoilers.\n",
        "choiceone": "outboard ailerons and roll-spoilers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "inboard and outboard ailerons.\n",
        "choicethree": "outboard ailerons only.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane is sensitive to Dutch roll when ;\n",
        "answer": "static lateral stability is much more pronounced than static directional stability.\n",
        "choiceone": "static lateral stability is much less pronounced than static directional stability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an aeroplane has anhedral.\n",
        "choicethree": "static stability is less pronounced than dynamic stability.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane maintains straight and level flight at a speed of 2 * VS. If a vertical gust causes a load factor of 2 , the load\nfactor n caused by the same gust at a speed of 1.3 VS would be ;\n",
        "answer": "n = 1.65\n",
        "choiceone": "n = 1.69\n",
        "choicetwo": "n = 1.3\n",
        "choicethree": "n=4\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane maintains straight and level flight while the IAS is doubled. The change in lift coefficient will be ;\n",
        "answer": "x 0.25\n",
        "choiceone": "x 2.0\n",
        "choicetwo": "x 0.5\n",
        "choicethree": "x 4.0\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane performs a continuous descent with 160 kts IAS and 1000 feet/min vertical speed. In this condition ;\n",
        "answer": "weight is greater than lift.\n",
        "choiceone": "lift is equal to weight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lift is less than drag.\n",
        "choicethree": "drag is less than the combined forces that move the aeroplane forward.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane performs a right turn , the slip indicator is left of neutral. One way to coordinate the turn is to apply ;\n",
        "answer": "more left rudder.\n",
        "choiceone": "less right bank.\n",
        "choicetwo": "more right rudder.\n",
        "choicethree": "a higher turn-rate.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane performs a steady co-ordinated horizontal turn with 20 degrees of bank and at 150 kt TAS. The same aeroplane\nwith the same bank angle and speed , but at a lower mass will turn with ;\n",
        "answer": "the same turn radius.\n",
        "choiceone": "a smaller turn radius.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a higher turn rate.\n",
        "choicethree": "a larger turn radius.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane performs a steady horizontal , co-ordinated turn with 45 degrees of bank at 230 kt TAS. The same aeroplane\nwith the same bank angle and speed , but at a higher mass ;\n",
        "answer": "will turn with the same radius , but might stall.\n",
        "choiceone": "will have a higher rate of turn.\n",
        "choicetwo": "will turn with a smaller turn radius.\n",
        "choicethree": "will turn with a larger turn radius.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane performs a steady horizontal , co-ordinated turn with 45 degrees of bank at 230 kt TAS. The same aeroplane\nwith the same bank angle and speed , but at a lower mass will turn with ;\n",
        "answer": "the same turn radius.\n",
        "choiceone": "a larger turn radius.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a higher rate of turn.\n",
        "choicethree": "a smaller turn radius.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane performs a steady horizontal , co-ordinated turn with 45 degrees of bank at 230 kt TAS. The same aeroplane\nwith the same bank angle and speed , but at a lower mass will turn with ;\n",
        "answer": "the same rate of turn.\n",
        "choiceone": "a lower rate of turn.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a smaller turn radius.\n",
        "choicethree": "a larger turn radius.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane performs a steady horizontal turn with a TAS of 200 kt. The turn radius is 2000 m. The load factor (n) is\napproximately ;\n",
        "answer": "1.1.\n",
        "choiceone": "1.4.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.0.\n",
        "choicethree": "1.8.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane performs a straight and level horizontal flight at the same angle of attack at two different altitudes ; ( all other\nfactors of importance being constant , assume ISA conditions and no compressibility effects )\n",
        "answer": "the TAS at the higher altitude is higher.\n",
        "choiceone": "the TAS at the higher altitude is lower.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the TAS at both altitudes is the same.\n",
        "choicethree": "the TAS at the higher altitude cannot be determined.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane should be equipped with a Mach trimmer , if ;\n",
        "answer": "at transonic Mach numbers the aeroplane demonstrates unconventional elevator stick force characteristics.\n",
        "choiceone": "stick force per g strongly decreases at low Mach numbers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "stick force stability is independent of the airspeed and -altitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "at high airspeed and low altitude the aeroplane demonstrates unconventional elevator stick force\n characteristics.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane that has positive static stability ;\n",
        "answer": "can be dynamically stable , neutral or unstable.\n",
        "choiceone": "is always dynamically unstable.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is never dynamically stable.\n",
        "choicethree": "is always dynamically stable.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane that tends to return to its pre-disturbed equilibrium position after the disturbance has been removed is said to\nhave ;\n",
        "answer": "positive static stability.\n",
        "choiceone": "neutral static stability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "neutral dynamic stability.\n",
        "choicethree": "positive dynamic stability.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane transitions from steady straight and level flight into a horizontal coordinated turn with a load factor of 2 , the\nspeed remains constant and the ;\n",
        "answer": "induced drag increases by a factor of 4.\n",
        "choiceone": "angle of attack increases by a factor of 1/4.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lift increases by a factor of 4.\n",
        "choicethree": "total drag increases by a factor of 4.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane , with a CG location behind the centre of pressure of the wing can only maintain a straight and level flight\nwhen the horizontal tail loading is ;\n",
        "answer": "upwards.\n",
        "choiceone": "zero.\n",
        "choicetwo": "upwards or downwards depending on elevator deflection.\n",
        "choicethree": "downwards.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane with a mass of 2000 kg , is performing a co-ordinated level turn at a constant TAS of 160 kt and the bank angle\nis 60\u00b0. The lift is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "40.000 N.\n",
        "choiceone": "60.000 N.\n",
        "choicetwo": "20.000 N.\n",
        "choicethree": "80.000 N.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane with a mass of 4000 kg is performing a co-ordinated level turn at a constant TAS of 160 kt and a bank angle of\n45\u00b0. The lift is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "56.000 N\n",
        "choiceone": "28.000 N\n",
        "choicetwo": "14.000 N\n",
        "choicethree": "98.000 N\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane\u2019s angle of attack can be defined as the angle between its ;\n",
        "answer": "speed vector and longitudinal axis.\n",
        "choiceone": "speed vector and the horizontal plane.\n",
        "choicetwo": "longitudinal axis and the horizontal plane.\n",
        "choicethree": "lateral axis and the horizontal plane.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane\u2019s angle of incidence is defined as the angle between the ;\n",
        "answer": "longitudinal axis and the wing root chord line.\n",
        "choiceone": "speed vector and the horizontal plane.\n",
        "choicetwo": "speed vector and longitudinal axis.\n",
        "choicethree": "longitudinal axis and the horizontal plane.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane\u2019s bank angle is defined as the angle between its ;\n",
        "answer": "lateral axis and the horizontal plane.\n",
        "choiceone": "speed vector and the horizontal plane.\n",
        "choicetwo": "longitudinal axis and the horizontal plane.\n",
        "choicethree": "speed vector and longitudinal axis.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane\u2019s flight path angle is defined as the angle between its ;\n",
        "answer": "speed vector and the horizontal plane.\n",
        "choiceone": "lateral axis and the horizontal plane.\n",
        "choicetwo": "longitudinal axis and the horizontal plane.\n",
        "choicethree": "speed vector and its longitudinal axis.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane\u2019s pitch angle is defined as the angle between its ;\n",
        "answer": "longitudinal axis and the horizontal plane.\n",
        "choiceone": "speed vector and the horizontal plane.\n",
        "choicetwo": "speed vector and its longitudinal axis.\n",
        "choicethree": "lateral axis and the horizontal plane.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aeroplane\u2019s sideslip angle is defined as the angle between the ;\n",
        "answer": "speed vector and the plane of symmetry.\n",
        "choiceone": "lateral axis and the horizontal plane.\n",
        "choicetwo": "speed vector and normal axis.\n",
        "choicethree": "speed vector and the horizontal plane.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An aft CG shift ;\n",
        "answer": "increases longitudinal manoeuvrability.\n",
        "choiceone": "has no influence on static longitudinal stability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increases static longitudinal stability.\n",
        "choicethree": "decreases longitudinal manoeuvrability.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An engine failure can result in a windmilling (1) propeller and a feathered (2) propeller. Which statement about propeller\ndrag is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "(1) is larger than (2).\n",
        "choiceone": "(2) is larger than (1).\n",
        "choicetwo": "impossible to say which one is largest.\n",
        "choicethree": "(1) is equal to (2).\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An example of a combined lateral and directional aperiodic motion is a ;\n",
        "answer": "spiral dive.\n",
        "choiceone": "phugoid.\n",
        "choicetwo": "short period oscillation.\n",
        "choicethree": "Dutch roll.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An example of a combined lateral and directional periodic motion is a ;\n",
        "answer": "Dutch roll.\n",
        "choiceone": "short period oscillation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "phugoid.\n",
        "choicethree": "spiral dive.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An example of differential aileron deflection during initiation of left turn is ;\n",
        "answer": "Left aileron : 5\u00b0 up\n Right aileron : 2\u00b0 down\n",
        "choiceone": "Left aileron : 5\u00b0 down\n Right aileron : 2\u00b0 up\n",
        "choicetwo": "Left aileron : 2\u00b0 up\n Right aileron : 5\u00b0 down\n",
        "choicethree": "Left aileron : 2\u00b0 down\n Right aileron : 5\u00b0 up\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An increase in geometric dihedral in a steady sideslip condition at constant speed would ;\n",
        "answer": "increase the required lateral control force.\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease the stick force per g.\n",
        "choicetwo": "not affect the required lateral control force.\n",
        "choicethree": "decrease the required lateral control force.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "An increase in wing loading will ;\n",
        "answer": "increase the stall speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease the minimum glide angle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase CLmax.\n",
        "choicethree": "increase sensitivity to turbulence.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Approximately how long does it take to fly a complete circle during a horizontal steady co-ordinated turn with a bank angle\nof 45\u00b0 and a TAS of 200 kt ?\n",
        "answer": "65 s.\n",
        "choiceone": "650 s.\n",
        "choicetwo": "95 s.\n",
        "choicethree": "125 s.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Artificial feel is required ;\n",
        "answer": "with fully powered flight controls.\n",
        "choiceone": "when the flight control surfaces are fitted with control tabs or trim tabs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "when there is a trimmable stabiliser.\n",
        "choicethree": "with power assisted flight controls.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "As altitude increases , the stall speed ( IAS ) ;\n",
        "answer": "initially remains constant and at higher altitudes increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "remains constant regardless of altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "remains constant until the tropopause and at higher altitudes increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "initially remains constant and at higher altitudes decreases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "As angle of attack is increased on a conventional low speed aerofoil at low subsonic speeds , flow separation normally starts\non the ;\n",
        "answer": "upper surface near the trailing edge.\n",
        "choiceone": "lower surface near the leading edge.\n",
        "choicetwo": "upper surface near the leading edge.\n",
        "choicethree": "lower surface near the trailing edge.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "As the Mach number increases from subsonic to supersonic , the centre of pressure moves ;\n",
        "answer": "to the mid chord position.\n",
        "choiceone": "forward.\n",
        "choicetwo": "to a position near the trailing edge.\n",
        "choicethree": "to a position near the leading edge.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "As the Mach number increases in straight and level flight , a shock wave on the upper surface of the wing will ;\n",
        "answer": "move towards the trailing edge.\n",
        "choiceone": "disappear.\n",
        "choicetwo": "not move.\n",
        "choicethree": "move towards the leading edge.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "As the stability of an aeroplane decreases ;\n",
        "answer": "its manoeuvrability increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "its manoeuvrability decreases also.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there is no effect on its stability.\n",
        "choicethree": "its tendency to tuck under decreases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "As the stability of an aeroplane increases:\n",
        "answer": "its manoeuvrability decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "there is no effect on its stability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "its manoeuvrability increases also.\n",
        "choicethree": "its tendency to tuck under increases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Aspect ratio of a wing is the ratio between ;\n",
        "answer": "wing span squared and wing area.\n",
        "choiceone": "wing root chord line and wing tip chord line.\n",
        "choicetwo": "wing span and wing root chord.\n",
        "choicethree": "wing span and dihedral angle.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 27 )\n Image 27\n Assuming all bodies have the same cross-sectional area and are in motion , which body will have the highest pressure drag ?\n",
        "answer": "Body 2.\n",
        "choiceone": "Body 1.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Body 3.\n",
        "choicethree": "Body 4.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming an initial condition in straight and level flight with CL=1. What will be the new value of CL after the value of the\nspeed has doubled ?\n",
        "answer": "0.25.\n",
        "choiceone": "2.00.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1.00.\n",
        "choicethree": "0.50.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming constant IAS , when an aeroplane enters ground effect ;\n",
        "answer": "the induced angle of attack reduces.\n",
        "choiceone": "induced drag increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the effective angle of attack decreases.\n",
        "choicethree": "the effective angle of attack does not change.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming constant IAS , when an aeroplane enters ground effect ;\n",
        "answer": "induced drag reduces.\n",
        "choiceone": "the effective angle of attack decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "downwash does not change.\n",
        "choicethree": "the induced angle of attack increases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming constant IAS , when an aeroplane enters ground effect ;\n",
        "answer": "the effective angle of attack increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "the effective angle of attack decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "induced drag increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "the induced angle of attack increases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming constant IAS , when an aeroplane enters ground effect ;\n",
        "answer": "downwash reduces.\n",
        "choiceone": "downwash does not change.\n",
        "choicetwo": "induced drag increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "the effective angle of attack decreases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming constant IAS , when an aeroplane leaves ground effect ;\n",
        "answer": "the induced angle of attack increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "the effective angle of attack does not change.\n",
        "choicetwo": "induced drag decreases.\n",
        "choicethree": "the effective angle of attack increases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming constant IAS , when an aeroplane leaves ground effect ;\n",
        "answer": "induced drag increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "the effective angle of attack increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "downwash does not change.\n",
        "choicethree": "the induced angle of attack decreases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming constant IAS , when an aeroplane leaves ground effect ;\n",
        "answer": "downwash increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "the effective angle of attack increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "induced drag decreases.\n",
        "choicethree": "downwash does not change.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming constant IAS , when an aeroplane leaves ground effect ;\n",
        "answer": "the effective angle of attack decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "the induced angle of attack decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "induced drag decreases.\n",
        "choicethree": "the effective angle of attack increases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming ISA conditions and a descent below the tropopause at constant Mach number and aeroplane mass , the ;\n",
        "answer": "lift coefficient decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "lift coefficient increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "TAS remain constant.\n",
        "choicethree": "IAS decreases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming ISA conditions and no compressibility effects , if an aeroplane maintains straight and level flight at the same angle\nof attack at two different altitudes , the ;\n",
        "answer": "IAS at both altitudes is the same.\n",
        "choiceone": "IAS is higher at the higher altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "TAS at both altitudes is the same.\n",
        "choicethree": "TAS is lower at the higher altitude.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming ISA conditions and no compressibility effects , if an aeroplane maintains straight and level flight at the same angle\nof attack at two different altitudes , the ;\n",
        "answer": "TAS is higher at the higher altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "TAS at both altitudes is the same.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IAS is higher at the lower altitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "TAS is higher at the lower altitude.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming ISA conditions and no compressibility effects , if an aeroplane maintains straight and level flight at the same angle\nof attack at two different altitudes , the ;\n",
        "answer": "TAS is lower at the lower altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "TAS is higher at the lower altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IAS is lower at the lower altitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "IAS is higher at the lower altitude.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming ISA conditions , climbing at a constant Mach Number up to FL 350 the TAS will ;\n",
        "answer": "decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "remain constant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "first increase , then decrease.\n",
        "choicethree": "increase.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming ISA conditions , climbing at a constant Mach Number up the tropopause the TAS will ;\n",
        "answer": "decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "remain constant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase.\n",
        "choicethree": "first increase , then decrease.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming ISA conditions , which statement with respect to the climb is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "At constant IAS the Mach number increases\n",
        "choiceone": "At constant IAS the TAS decreases\n",
        "choicetwo": "At constant TAS the Mach number decreases\n",
        "choicethree": "At constant Mach number the IAS increases\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming no compressibility effects , induced drag at constant IAS is affected by ;\n",
        "answer": "aeroplane mass.\n",
        "choiceone": "altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "engine thrust.\n",
        "choicethree": "outside air temperature.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming no compressibility effects , the correct relationship between stall speed , limit load factor ( n ) and VA is ;\n",
        "answer": "VA >= VS * SQRT (n)\n",
        "choiceone": "VA <= VS * 1/n\n",
        "choicetwo": "VA >= VS * 1/n\n",
        "choicethree": "VA <= VS * SQRT (n)\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming no flow separation and no compressibility effects the location of the aerodynamic centre of an aerofoil section ;\n",
        "answer": "is independent of angle of attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "is at approximately 50% chord irrespective of angle of attack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "moves forward when the angle of attack increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "moves backward when the angle of attack increases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming no flow separation and no compressibility effects the location of the aerodynamic centre of an aerofoil section ;\n",
        "answer": "is at approximately 25% chord irrespective of angle of attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "moves backward when the angle of attack decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "moves backward when the angle of attack increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "is at approximately 50% chord irrespective of angle of attack.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming no flow separation and no compressibility effects the location of the centre of pressure of a positively cambered\naerofoil section ;\n",
        "answer": "moves backward when the angle of attack decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "moves forward when the angle of attack decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is independent of angle of attack.\n",
        "choicethree": "is at approximately 25% chord irrespective of angle of attack.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming no flow separation and no compressibility effects the location of the centre of pressure of a symmetrical aerofoil\nsection ;\n",
        "answer": "is at approximately 25% chord irrespective of angle of attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "moves forward when the angle of attack decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is at approximately 50% chord irrespective of angle of attack.\n",
        "choicethree": "moves backward when the angle of attack decreases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming no flow separation and no compressibility effects the location of the centre of pressure of a symmetrical aerofoil\nsection ;\n",
        "answer": "is independent of angle of attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "moves backward when the angle of attack decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is at approximately 50% of the chord irrespective of angle of attack.\n",
        "choicethree": "moves forward when the angle of attack decreases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming no flow separation , when speed is decreased in straight and level flight on a positively cambered aerofoil , what\nhappens to the ;\n 1. centre of pressure and\n 2. the magnitude of the total lift force ?\n",
        "answer": "1 moves forward and 2 remains constant.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 moves aft and 2 remains constant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 moves aft and 2 increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "1 moves forward and 2 decreases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming no flow separation , which of these statements about the flow around an aerofoil as the angle of attack decreases\nare correct or incorrect ?\n I. The stagnation point moves down.\n II. The point of lowest static pressure moves aft.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming no flow separation , which of these statements about the flow around an aerofoil as the angle of attack decreases\nare correct or incorrect ?\n I. The stagnation point moves down.\n II. The point of lowest static pressure moves forward.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming no flow separation , which of these statements about the flow around an aerofoil as the angle of attack decreases\nare correct or incorrect ?\n I. The stagnation point moves up.\n II. The point of lowest static pressure moves aft.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming no flow separation , which of these statements about the flow around an aerofoil as the angle of attack decreases\nare correct or incorrect ?\n I. The stagnation point moves up.\n II. The point of lowest static pressure moves forward.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming no flow separation , which of these statements about the flow around an aerofoil as the angle of attack increases\nare correct or incorrect ?\n I. The stagnation point moves down.\n II. The point of lowest static pressure moves aft.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming no flow separation , which of these statements about the flow around an aerofoil as the angle of attack increases\nare correct or incorrect ?\n I. The stagnation point moves up.\n II. The point of lowest static pressure moves aft.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming no flow separation , which of these statements about the flow around an aerofoil as the angle of attack increases\nare correct or incorrect ?\n I. The stagnation point moves up.\n II. The point of lowest static pressure moves forward.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 11 )\n Image 11\n Assuming no pilot input the motion of the aeroplane in the diagram shows ;\n",
        "answer": "dynamic longitudinal stability.\n",
        "choiceone": "dynamic longitudinal instability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "neutral dynamic longitudinal stability.\n",
        "choicethree": "static longitudinal instability.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 21 )\n Image 21\n Assuming no pilot input the motion of the aeroplane in the diagram shows ;\n",
        "answer": "static longitudinal stability and dynamic longitudinal instability.\n",
        "choiceone": "neutral dynamic longitudinal stability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "static longitudinal instability.\n",
        "choicethree": "static and dynamic longitudinal stability.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image12 )\n Image 12\n Assuming no pilot input the motion of the aeroplane in the diagram shows ;\n",
        "answer": "neutral dynamic longitudinal stability.\n",
        "choiceone": "dynamic longitudinal stability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dynamic longitudinal instability.\n",
        "choicethree": "static longitudinal instability.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming standard atmospheric conditions , in order to generate the same amount of lift as altitude is increased , an\naeroplane must be flown at ;\n",
        "answer": "a higher TAS for any given angle of attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "the same TAS regardless of angle of attack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a lower TAS and a lower angle of attack.\n",
        "choicethree": "a lower TAS for any given angle of attack.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming subsonic incompressible flow , how will air density change as air flows through a tube of increasing cross-\nsectional area ? The air density ;\n",
        "answer": "does not vary.\n",
        "choiceone": "decreases with increasing cross-sectional area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increases with increasing cross-sectional area.\n",
        "choicethree": "depends upon the shape of the tube alone and not its cross-sectional area.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming that the RPM remains constant throughout , the angle of attack of a fixed pitch propeller will ;\n",
        "answer": "decrease with increasing airspeed.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase with increasing airspeed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "remain constant at a fixed value irrespective of any airspeed changes.\n",
        "choicethree": "remain constant at a fixed value only if the airspeed decreases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 2 )\n Image 2\n Assuming zero thrust , the point on the diagram corresponding to the minimum glide angle is ;\n",
        "answer": "Point b\n",
        "choiceone": "Point c\n",
        "choicetwo": "Point d\n",
        "choicethree": "Point a\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 2 )\n Image 2\n Assuming zero thrust , the point on the diagram corresponding to the value for minimum sink rate is ;\n",
        "answer": "Point c\n",
        "choiceone": "Point d\n",
        "choicetwo": "Point b\n",
        "choicethree": "Point a\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Assuming zero wing twist , the wing planform that gives the highest local lift coefficient at the wing root is ;\n",
        "answer": "rectangular.\n",
        "choiceone": "tapered.\n",
        "choicetwo": "swept back.\n",
        "choicethree": "elliptical.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Asymmetric propeller blade effect is mainly induced by ;\n",
        "answer": "the inclination of the propeller axis to the relative airflow.\n",
        "choiceone": "large angles of yaw.\n",
        "choicetwo": "large angles of climb.\n",
        "choicethree": "high speed.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At a constant angle of attack , which of the following factors will lead to an increase of ground distance during a glide and\nwith zero thrust ?\n",
        "answer": "Tailwind\n",
        "choiceone": "Headwind\n",
        "choicetwo": "Increase of aeroplane mass\n",
        "choicethree": "Decrease of aeroplane mass\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At a load factor of 1 and the aeroplane\u2019s minimum drag speed , what is the ratio between induced drag Di and parasite drag\nDp ?\n",
        "answer": "Di/Dp = 1.\n",
        "choiceone": "It varies between aeroplane types.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Di/Dp = 1/2.\n",
        "choicethree": "Di/Dp = 2.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At an aeroplane\u2019s minimum drag speed , what is the ratio between induced drag Di and parasite drag Dp ? Di /Dp =\n",
        "answer": "1/1\n",
        "choiceone": "2/1\n",
        "choicetwo": "It varies between aeroplane types.\n",
        "choicethree": "1/2\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At higher altitudes , the stall speed ( IAS ) ;\n",
        "answer": "increases\n",
        "choiceone": "remains the same\n",
        "choicetwo": "decreases until the tropopause\n",
        "choicethree": "decreases\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "At what speed does the front of a shock wave move across the earth\u2019s surface ?\n",
        "answer": "The ground speed of the aeroplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "The true air speed of the aeroplane.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The speed of sound at flight level.\n",
        "choicethree": "The speed of sound at ground level.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Behind a normal shock wave on an aerofoil section the local Mach number is ;\n",
        "answer": "less than 1.\n",
        "choiceone": "equal to 1.\n",
        "choicetwo": "higher than before.\n",
        "choicethree": "lower than before but still greater than 1.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Behind the transition point in a boundary layer ;\n",
        "answer": "the mean speed and friction drag increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "the mean speed increases and the friction drag decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the boundary layer gets thinner and the speed increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "the boundary layer gets thicker and the speed decreases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Bernoulli\u2019s equation can be written as ; ( pt = total pressure , ps = static pressure , q = dynamic pressure )\n",
        "answer": "pt \u2013 q = ps\n",
        "choiceone": "pt = q \u2013 ps\n",
        "choicetwo": "pt = ps \u2013 q\n",
        "choicethree": "pt + ps = q\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Bernoulli\u2019s equation can be written as ; ( pt= total pressure , ps = static pressure and q=dynamic pressure )\n",
        "answer": "pt = ps + q\n",
        "choiceone": "pt = ps / q\n",
        "choicetwo": "pt = ps \u2013 q\n",
        "choicethree": "pt = q \u2013 ps\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Bernoulli\u2019s law states ; ( note : rho is the mean sea level density under ISA conditions , pstat is static pressure , pdyn is\ndynamic pressure , ptot is total pressure )\n",
        "answer": "pstat + \u00bd rhoV\u00b2 = constant.\n",
        "choiceone": "pstat + \u00bd rhoTAS\u00b2 = constant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ptot + \u00bd rhoV\u00b2 = pstat.\n",
        "choicethree": "pdyn + \u00bd rhoV\u00b2 = constant.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "By what approximate percentage will the stall speed increase in a horizontal coordinated turn with a bank angle of 45\u00b0 ?\n",
        "answer": "19%\n",
        "choiceone": "41%\n",
        "choicetwo": "52%\n",
        "choicethree": "31%\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "By what percentage does the lift increase in a level turn at 45\u00b0 angle of bank , compared to straight and level flight ?\n",
        "answer": "41%.\n",
        "choiceone": "52%.\n",
        "choicetwo": "19%.\n",
        "choicethree": "31%.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "By what percentage does VA ( EAS ) alter when the aeroplane\u2019s weight decreases by 19% ?\n",
        "answer": "10% lower.\n",
        "choiceone": "no change\n",
        "choicetwo": "4.36% lower.\n",
        "choicethree": "19% lower.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Compared with an oblique shock wave at the same Mach number a normal shock wave has a ;\n",
        "answer": "higher compression.\n",
        "choiceone": "smaller expansion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "smaller compression.\n",
        "choicethree": "higher expansion.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Compared with an oblique shock wave at the same Mach number a normal shock wave has a ;\n",
        "answer": "higher loss in total pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "higher total temperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "higher total pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "lower static temperature.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Compared with level flight prior to the stall , the lift (1) and drag (2) in the stall change as follows ;\n",
        "answer": "(1) decreases , (2) increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "(1) increases , (2) increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "(1) decreases , (2) decreases.\n",
        "choicethree": "(1) increases , (2) decreases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Compared with level flight , the angle of attack must be increased in a steady , co-ordinated , horizontal turn ;\n",
        "answer": "to compensate for the reduction in the vertical component of lift.\n",
        "choiceone": "because stall speed increases in a turn.\n",
        "choicetwo": "to increase the horizontal component of lift to a value equal to the vertical component.\n",
        "choicethree": "to compensate for the increase in drag.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Compared with stalling airspeed ( VS ) in a given configuration , the airspeed at which stick shaker will be triggered is ;\n",
        "answer": "greater than VS.\n",
        "choiceone": "1.12 VS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1.20 VS.\n",
        "choicethree": "1.30 VS.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Compared with the clean configuration , the angle of attack at CLmax with trailing edge flaps extended is ;\n",
        "answer": "smaller.\n",
        "choiceone": "larger.\n",
        "choicetwo": "smaller or larger depending on the degree of flap extension.\n",
        "choicethree": "unchanged.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Comparing the differences between a horizontal trimmable stabiliser and an elevator trim tab , which of these statements are\ncorrect or incorrect ?\n I. A stabiliser trim is more suitable to cope with the large trim changes generated by the high lift devices\n on most jet transport aeroplanes.\n II. A trim tab runaway causes less control difficulty.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Comparing the differences between a horizontal trimmable stabiliser and an elevator trim tab , which of these statements are\ncorrect or incorrect ?\n I. An elevator trim tab is more suitable to cope with the large trim changes generated by the high lift\n devices on most jet transport aeroplanes.\n II. A stabiliser trim runaway causes less control difficulty.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Comparing the differences between a horizontal trimmable stabiliser and an elevator trim tab , which of these statements are\ncorrect or incorrect ?\n I. An elevator trim tab is more suitable to cope with the large trim changes generated by the high lift\n devices on most jet transport aeroplanes.\n II. A trim tab runaway causes less control difficulty.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Comparing the differences between a horizontal trimmable stabiliser and an elevator trim tab , which of these statements are\ncorrect or incorrect ?\n I. The effects of a stabiliser trim runaway are more serious.\n II. A jammed stabiliser trim causes less control difficulty.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Comparing the differences between a horizontal trimmable stabiliser and an elevator trim tab , which of these statements are\ncorrect or incorrect ?\n I. The effects of a stabiliser trim runaway are more serious.\n II. A jammed trim tab causes less control difficulty.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Comparing the differences between a horizontal trimmable stabiliser and an elevator trim tab , which of these statements are\ncorrect or incorrect ?\n I. The effects of a trim tab runaway are more serious.\n II. A jammed stabiliser trim causes less control difficulty.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Comparing the differences between a horizontal trimmable stabiliser and an elevator trim tab , which of these statements are\ncorrect or incorrect ?\n I. The effects of a trim tab runaway are more serious.\n II. A jammed trim tab causes less control difficulty.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Comparing the differences between a horizontal trimmable stabiliser and an elevator trim tab , which of these statements are\ncorrect or incorrect ?\n I. When trimmed for zero elevator stick force a horizontal trimmable stabiliser causes more drag.\n II. A horizontal trimmable stabiliser enables a larger CG range.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Comparing the differences between a horizontal trimmable stabiliser and an elevator trim tab which of these statements are\ncorrect or incorrect ?\n I. When trimmed for zero elevator stick force a horizontal trimmable stabiliser causes more drag.\n II. An elevator trim tab enables a larger CG range.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Comparing the differences between a horizontal trimmable stabiliser and an elevator trim tab , which of these statements are\ncorrect or incorrect ?\n I. When trimmed for zero elevator stick force an elevator trim tab causes more drag.\n II. A horizontal trimmable stabiliser enables a larger CG range.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Comparing the differences between a horizontal trimmable stabiliser and an elevator trim tab , which of these statements are\ncorrect or incorrect ?\n I. When trimmed for zero elevator stick force an elevator trim tab causes more drag.\n II. An elevator trim tab enables a larger CG range.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Comparing the differences between a horizontal trimmable stabiliser and an elevator trim tab , which statement is correct ?\n I. A stabiliser trim is less suitable for jet transport aeroplanes because of their large speed range.\n II. A stabiliser trim is a more powerful means of trimming.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Comparing the differences between a horizontal trimmable stabiliser and an elevator trim tab , which statement is correct ?\n I. A stabiliser trim is less suitable for jet transport aeroplanes because of their large speed range.\n II. A trim tab is a more powerful means of trimming.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Comparing the differences between a horizontal trimmable stabiliser and an elevator trim tab , which statement is correct ?\n I. A trim tab is less suitable for jet transport aeroplanes because of their large speed range.\n II. A stabiliser trim is a more powerful means of trimming.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Comparing the differences between a horizontal trimmable stabiliser and an elevator trim tab , which statement is correct ?\n I. A trim tab is less suitable for jet transport aeroplanes because of their large speed range.\n II. A trim tab is a more powerful means of trimming.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Comparing the lift coefficient and drag coefficient at normal angle of attack ;\n",
        "answer": "CL is much greater than CD.\n",
        "choiceone": "CL is lower than CD.\n",
        "choicetwo": "CL is much lower than CD.\n",
        "choicethree": "CL has approximately the same value as CD.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Compressibility effects depend on ;\n",
        "answer": "Mach Number.\n",
        "choiceone": "IAS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "TAS.\n",
        "choicethree": "EAS.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider an aerofoil with a certain camber and a positive angle of attack. At which location will the highest flow velocities\noccur ?\n",
        "answer": "Upper side.\n",
        "choiceone": "In the stagnation point.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In front of the stagnation point.\n",
        "choicethree": "Lower side.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider an aeroplane with ;\n 1. a trim tab.\n 2. fully powered hydraulic controls and an adjustable horizontal stabiliser.\n For both cases and starting from a trimmed condition , how will the neutral position of the control column change , after\ntrimming for a speed increase ?\n",
        "answer": "1 moves forward , 2 does not change.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 moves forward , 2 moves forward.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 does not change , 2 does not change.\n",
        "choicethree": "1 does not change , 2 moves forward.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider subsonic incompressible airflow through a venturi ;\n I. The dynamic pressure in the undisturbed airflow is higher than in the throat.\n II. The total pressure in the undisturbed airflow is higher than in the throat.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements about VMCG ;\n 1. VMCG is determined with the gear down.\n 2. VMCG is determined with the flaps in the landing position.\n 3. VMCG is determined by using rudder and nosewheel steering.\n 4. During VMCG determination the aeroplane may not deviate from the straight-line path by more than\n 30 ft.\n The combination that regroups all of the correct statements is ;\n",
        "answer": "1 , 4.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 , 2 , 3 , 4.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3.\n",
        "choicethree": "2 , 3.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the steady flow through a stream tube where the velocity of the stream is V. An increase in temperature of the flow\nat a constant value of V will ;\n",
        "answer": "decrease the mass flow.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase the mass flow.\n",
        "choicetwo": "not affect the mass flow.\n",
        "choicethree": "increase the mass flow when the tube is divergent in the direction of the flow.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider two elevator control systems ;\n 1 is fitted with a trim tab.\n 2 is fitted with fully powered hydraulic controls and an adjustable horizontal stabiliser.\n For both cases and starting from a trimmed condition , how will the neutral position of the control column change , after\ntrimming for a speed decrease ?\n",
        "answer": "1 moves aft , 2 does not change.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 does not change , 2 moves aft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 moves forward , 2 moves forward.\n",
        "choicethree": "1 does not change , 2 does not change.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering a positive cambered aerofoil , the pitching moment when Cl = 0 is ;\n",
        "answer": "negative ( pitch-down ).\n",
        "choiceone": "equal to zero.\n",
        "choicetwo": "infinite\n",
        "choicethree": "positive ( pitch-up ).\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering a positively cambered aerofoil section , the pitching moment when the lift coefficient Cl = 0 is ;\n",
        "answer": "negative ( nose down ).\n",
        "choiceone": "equal to zero.\n",
        "choicetwo": "positive ( nose up ).\n",
        "choicethree": "maximum.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The dynamic pressure in the throat is higher than in the undisturbed airflow.\n II. The total pressure in the throat is higher than in the undisturbed airflow.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The dynamic pressure in the throat is higher than in the undisturbed airflow.\n II. The total pressure in the throat is lower than in the undisturbed airflow.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The dynamic pressure in the throat is higher than in the undisturbed airflow.\n II. The total pressure in the throat is the same as in the undisturbed airflow.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The dynamic pressure in the throat is lower than in the undisturbed airflow.\n II. The total pressure in the throat is higher than in the undisturbed airflow.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The dynamic pressure in the throat is lower than in the undisturbed airflow.\n II. The total pressure in the throat is lower than in the undisturbed airflow.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The dynamic pressure in the throat is lower than in the undisturbed airflow.\n II. The total pressure in the throat is the same as in the undisturbed airflow.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The dynamic pressure in the throat is the same as in the undisturbed airflow.\n II. The total pressure in the throat is higher than in the undisturbed airflow.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The dynamic pressure in the throat is the same as in the undisturbed airflow.\n II. The total pressure in the throat is lower than in the undisturbed airflow.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The dynamic pressure in the undisturbed airflow is higher than in the throat.\n II. The total pressure in the undisturbed airflow is lower than in the throat.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The dynamic pressure in the undisturbed airflow is higher than in the throat.\n II. The total pressure in the undisturbed airflow is the same as in the throat.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The dynamic pressure in the undisturbed airflow is lower than in the throat.\n II. The total pressure in the undisturbed airflow and in the throat is the same.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The dynamic pressure in the undisturbed airflow is lower than in the throat.\n II. The total pressure in the undisturbed airflow is higher than in the throat.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The dynamic pressure in the undisturbed airflow is lower than in the throat.\n II. The total pressure in the undisturbed airflow is lower than in the throat.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The dynamic pressure in the undisturbed airflow is the same as in the throat.\n II. The total pressure in the undisturbed airflow is higher than in the throat.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The dynamic pressure in the undisturbed airflow is the same as in the throat.\n II. The total pressure in the undisturbed airflow is lower than in the throat.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The static pressure in the throat is higher than in the undisturbed airflow.\n II. The speed of the airflow in the throat is higher than in the undisturbed airflow.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The static pressure in the throat is higher than in the undisturbed airflow.\n II. The speed of the airflow in the throat is lower than in the undisturbed airflow.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The static pressure in the throat is higher than in the undisturbed airflow.\n II. The speed of the airflow in the throat is the same as in the undisturbed airflow.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The static pressure in the throat is lower than in the undisturbed airflow.\n II. The speed of the airflow in the throat is higher than in the undisturbed airflow.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The static pressure in the throat is lower than in the undisturbed airflow.\n II. The speed of the airflow in the throat is lower than in the undisturbed airflow.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The static pressure in the throat is lower than in the undisturbed airflow.\n II. The speed of the airflow in the throat is the same as in the undisturbed airflow.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The static pressure in the throat is the same as in the undisturbed airflow.\n II. The speed of the airflow in the throat is higher than in the undisturbed airflow\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The static pressure in the throat is the same as in the undisturbed airflow.\n II. The speed of the airflow in the throat is lower than in the undisturbed airflow.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The static pressure in the undisturbed airflow is higher than in the throat.\n II. The speed in the undisturbed airflow is higher than in the throat.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The static pressure in the undisturbed airflow is higher than in the throat.\n II. The speed in the undisturbed airflow is lower than in the throat.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The static pressure in the undisturbed airflow is higher than in the throat.\n II. The speed in the undisturbed airflow is the same as in the throat.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The static pressure in the undisturbed airflow is lower than in the throat.\n II. The speed in the undisturbed airflow is higher than in the throat.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The static pressure in the undisturbed airflow is lower than in the throat.\n II. The speed in the undisturbed airflow is lower than in the throat.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The static pressure in the undisturbed airflow is lower than in the throat.\n II. The speed in the undisturbed airflow is the same as in the throat.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The static pressure in the undisturbed airflow is the same as in the throat.\n II. The speed in the undisturbed airflow is higher than in the throat.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The static pressure in the undisturbed airflow is the same as in the throat.\n II. The speed in the undisturbed airflow is lower than in the throat.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Considering subsonic incompressible airflow through a Venturi , which statement is correct ?\n I. The static pressure in the undisturbed airflow is the same as in the throat.\n II. The speed in the undisturbed airflow is the same as in the throat.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Constant-speed propellers provide a better performance than fixed-pitch propellers because they ;\n",
        "answer": "produce an almost maximum efficiency over a wider speed range.\n",
        "choiceone": "produce a greater maximum thrust than a fixed-pitch propeller.\n",
        "choicetwo": "have a higher maximum efficiency than a fixed-pitch propeller.\n",
        "choicethree": "have more blade surface area than a fixed-pitch propeller.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Control surface flutter can be eliminated by ;\n",
        "answer": "mass balancing of the control surface.\n",
        "choiceone": "increasing speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "reducing structural stiffness of the control surface attachment structure.\n",
        "choicethree": "aerodynamic balancing of the control surface.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Critical Mach number is the free stream Mach number at which ;\n",
        "answer": "local supersonic flow first exists on any part of the aeroplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "there is supersonic flow over all parts of the aeroplane.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the aeroplane has zero buffet margin.\n",
        "choicethree": "there is subsonic flow over all parts of the aeroplane.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Dangerous stall characteristics , in large transport aeroplanes that require stick pushers to be installed , include ;\n",
        "answer": "excessive wing drop and deep stall.\n",
        "choiceone": "pitch down and yaw.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pitch down and increase in speed.\n",
        "choicethree": "distinct aerodynamic buffet.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Decreasing the aspect ratio of a wing ;\n",
        "answer": "increases induced drag.\n",
        "choiceone": "decreases induced drag.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decreases stall speed.\n",
        "choicethree": "increases gust load.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Deflection of leading edge flaps will ;\n",
        "answer": "increase critical angle of attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease CLmax.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decrease drag.\n",
        "choicethree": "not affect critical angle of attack.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Deploying a Fowler flap , the flap will ;\n",
        "answer": "move aft , then turn down.\n",
        "choiceone": "just turn down.\n",
        "choicetwo": "turn down , then move aft.\n",
        "choicethree": "just move aft.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Differential aileron deflection ;\n",
        "answer": "equals the drag of the right and left aileron.\n",
        "choiceone": "increases the CLmax.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is required to keep the total lift constant when ailerons are deflected.\n",
        "choicethree": "is required to achieve the required roll-rate.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Dihedral of the wing ;\n",
        "answer": "increases the static lateral stability.\n",
        "choiceone": "is only positive for aeroplanes with high mounted wings.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decreases the static lateral stability.\n",
        "choicethree": "is the only way to increase the static lateral stability.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Dihedral of the wing is ;\n",
        "answer": "the angle between the 0.25 chord line of the wing and the lateral axis.\n",
        "choiceone": "the angle between the 0.25 chord line of the wing and the horizon.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the angle between the 0.25 chord line of the wing and the vertical axis.\n",
        "choicethree": "the angle between the leading edge of the wing and the lateral axis.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Dividing lift by weight gives ;\n",
        "answer": "load factor.\n",
        "choiceone": "wing loading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lift-drag ratio.\n",
        "choicethree": "aspect ratio.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Does the pitch-angle of a constant-speed propeller alter in medium horizontal turbulence ?\n",
        "answer": "Yes slightly.\n",
        "choiceone": "Yes , but only if the pitch is full-fine.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No.\n",
        "choicethree": "Yes strongly.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Drag is in the direction of - and lift is perpendicular to the ;\n",
        "answer": "relative wind/airflow.\n",
        "choiceone": "chord line.\n",
        "choicetwo": "horizon.\n",
        "choicethree": "longitudinal axis.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a climb at a constant IAS , the Mach Number will ;\n",
        "answer": "increase.\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease initially and increase subsequently.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase initially and remain constant subsequently.\n",
        "choicethree": "remain constant.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a climbing turn to the right the ;\n",
        "answer": "angle of attack of the left wing is larger than the angle of attack of the right wing.\n",
        "choiceone": "angle of attack of both wings is the same.\n",
        "choicetwo": "stall angle of attack of the left wing will be larger than the corresponding angle for the right wing.\n",
        "choicethree": "angle of attack of the left wing is smaller than the angle of attack of the right wing.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a glide with idle power and constant IAS , if the RPM lever of a constant speed propeller is pulled back from its\nnormal cruise position , the propeller pitch will ;\n",
        "answer": "increase and the rate of descent will decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease and the rate of descent will decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase and the rate of descent will increase.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a glide with idle power and constant IAS , if the RPM lever of a constant speed propeller is pushed full forward from\nits normal cruise position , the propeller pitch will ;\n",
        "answer": "decrease and the rate of descent will increase.\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease and the rate of descent will decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase and the rate of descent will decrease.\n",
        "choicethree": "increase and the rate of descent will increase.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a normal spin recovery ;\n",
        "answer": "the ailerons are held in the neutral position.\n",
        "choiceone": "the control stick is pulled to the most aft position.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the control stick is moved side ways , against the angle of bank.\n",
        "choicethree": "the control stick is moved side ways , in the direction of the angle of bank.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a phugoid the speed ;\n",
        "answer": "varies significantly , whereas during a short period oscillation it does not.\n",
        "choiceone": "remains approximatey constant , as during a short period oscillation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "remains approximately constant , whereas during a short period oscillation it varies significantly.\n",
        "choicethree": "varies significantly , as during a short period oscillation.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a short period oscillation , the altitude ;\n",
        "answer": "remains approximately constant , whereas during a phugoid it varies significantly.\n",
        "choiceone": "varies significantly , whereas during a phugoid it remains approximately constant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "remains approximately constant , as it does during a phugoid.\n",
        "choicethree": "varies significantly , as it does during a phugoid.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a steady horizontal turn , the stall speed ;\n",
        "answer": "increases with the square root of the load factor.\n",
        "choiceone": "increases inversely with the load factor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increases linearly wih the load factor.\n",
        "choicethree": "increases with the square of the load factor.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a straight steady climb ;\n 1. lift is less than weight.\n 2. lift is greater than weight.\n 3. load factor is less than 1.\n 4. load factor is greater than 1.\n 5. lift is equal to weight.\n 6. load factor is equal to 1.\n Which of the following lists the correct statements ?\n",
        "answer": "1 and 3.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 and 6.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2 and 4.\n",
        "choicethree": "5 and 6.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a straight , steady climb and with the thrust force parallel to the flight path ;\n",
        "answer": "lift is the same as during a descent at the same angle and mass.\n",
        "choiceone": "lift is greater than weight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "drag is equal to thrust.\n",
        "choicethree": "lift is equal to weight.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a straight steady descent , lift is ;\n",
        "answer": "less than weight , because lift only needs to balance the weight component perpendicular to the flight path.\n",
        "choiceone": "greater than weight because it must additionally balance a component of drag.\n",
        "choicetwo": "equal to weight to maintain a constant speed.\n",
        "choicethree": "less than weight , because there is less drag compared with horizontal flight.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a take-off roll with a strong crosswind from the left , a four-engine jet aeroplane with wing-mounted engines\nexperiences an engine failure. The failure of which engine will cause the greatest control problem ?\n",
        "answer": "The left outboard engine.\n",
        "choiceone": "The right inboard engine.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The left inboard engine.\n",
        "choicethree": "The right outboard engine.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During a take-off roll with a strong crosswind from the right , a four-engine jet aeroplane with wing-mounted engines\nexperiences an engine failure. The failure of which engine will cause the greatest control problem ?\n",
        "answer": "The right outboard engine.\n",
        "choiceone": "The left outboard engine.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The right inboard engine.\n",
        "choicethree": "The left inboard engine.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During an erect spin recovery ;\n",
        "answer": "the ailerons are held in the neutral position.\n",
        "choiceone": "the control stick is moved side ways , against the angle of bank.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the control stick is moved side ways , in the direction of the angle of bank.\n",
        "choicethree": "the control stick is pulled to the most aft position.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During initiation of a turn with speedbrakes extended , the roll spoiler function induces a spoiler deflection ;\n",
        "answer": "downward on the upgoing wing and upward on the downgoing wing.\n",
        "choiceone": "on the upgoing wing only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on the downgoing wing only.\n",
        "choicethree": "upward on the upgoing wing and downward on the downgoing wing.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During landing of a low-winged jet aeroplane , the greatest elevator up deflection is normally required when the flaps are ;\n",
        "answer": "fully down and the cg is fully forward.\n",
        "choiceone": "up and the cg is fully aft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "fully down and the cg is fully aft.\n",
        "choicethree": "up and the cg is fully forward.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the extension of the flaps at a constant angle of attack the aeroplane starts to ; ( all other factors of importance being\nconstant )\n",
        "answer": "climb.\n",
        "choiceone": "sink suddenly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "bank.\n",
        "choicethree": "yaw.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the retraction of the flaps at a constant angle of attack the aeroplane starts to ; ( all other factors of importance being\nconstant )\n",
        "answer": "sink suddenly.\n",
        "choiceone": "bank.\n",
        "choicetwo": "climb.\n",
        "choicethree": "yaw.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the take-off roll , when the pilot raises the tail in a tail wheeled propeller driven aeroplane , the additional aeroplane\nyawing tendency is due to the effect of ;\n",
        "answer": "gyroscopic precession.\n",
        "choiceone": "asymmetric blade effect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "slipstream.\n",
        "choicethree": "torque reaction.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the take-off roll with a strong crosswind from the left , a four engine jet aeroplane with wing mounted engines\nexperiences an engine failure above V1. Which engine causes the greatest control problem ?\n",
        "answer": "The left outboard engine.\n",
        "choiceone": "The left inboard engine.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The right outboard engine.\n",
        "choicethree": "The right inboard engine.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During which of the following phases of flight is a fixed pitch propeller\u2019s angle of attack highest ?\n",
        "answer": "Take-off run.\n",
        "choiceone": "High-speed glide.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Climb.\n",
        "choicethree": "Low-speed glide.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During which of the following phases of flight is a fixed pitch propeller\u2019s angle of attack lowest ?\n",
        "answer": "High-speed glide.\n",
        "choiceone": "Take-off run.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Climb.\n",
        "choicethree": "Low-speed glide.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "During which type of stall does the angle of attack have the smallest value ?\n",
        "answer": "Shock stall.\n",
        "choiceone": "Deep stall.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Accelerated stall.\n",
        "choicethree": "Low speed stall.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Entering the stall the centre of pressure of a straight (1) wing and of a strongly swept back wing (2) will ;\n",
        "answer": "(1) move aft , (2) move forward.\n",
        "choiceone": "(1) move aft , (2) not move.\n",
        "choicetwo": "(1) move aft , (2) move aft.\n",
        "choicethree": "(1) not move , (2) move forward.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Examples of aerodynamic balancing of control surfaces are ;\n",
        "answer": "servo tab , spring tab , seal between the wing trailing edge and the leading edge of control surface.\n",
        "choiceone": "spring tab , servo tab , and power assisted control.\n",
        "choicetwo": "mass in the nose of the control surface , horn balance and mass balance.\n",
        "choicethree": "balance tab , horn balance , and mass balance.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Examples of aerodynamic balancing of control surfaces are ;\n",
        "answer": "seal between wing\u2019s trailing edge and leading edge of a control surface , horn balance.\n",
        "choiceone": "Fowler flaps , upper and lower rudder.\n",
        "choicetwo": "weight in the nose of the control surface , horn balance.\n",
        "choicethree": "upper and lower rudder , seal between wing\u2019s trailing edge and leading edge of a control surface.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Excessive static lateral stability is an undesirable characteristic for a transport aeroplane because ;\n",
        "answer": "it would impose excessive demands on roll control during a sideslip.\n",
        "choiceone": "it would result in a proportional decline in static directional stability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "it would result in excessive wing loading during a co-ordinated turn.\n",
        "choicethree": "performing co-ordinated turns would be very difficult.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Excluding constants , the coefficient of induced drag ( CDi ) is the ratio of ;\n",
        "answer": "CL\u00b2 and AR ( aspect ratio ).\n",
        "choiceone": "CL\u00b2and S ( wing surface ).\n",
        "choicetwo": "CL and b ( wing span ).\n",
        "choicethree": "CL and CD.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Extension of FOWLER type trailing edge lift augmentation devices , will produce ;\n",
        "answer": "a nose-down pitching moment.\n",
        "choiceone": "no pitching moment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a force which reduces drag.\n",
        "choicethree": "a nose-up pitching moment.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Extension of leading edge flaps will ;\n",
        "answer": "increase critical angle of attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease drag.\n",
        "choicetwo": "not affect critical angle of attack.\n",
        "choicethree": "decrease CLmax.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Flap extension at constant IAS whilst maintaining straight and level flight will increase the ;\n",
        "answer": "maximum lift coefficient ( CLmax ) and the drag.\n",
        "choiceone": "stall speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lift coefficient and the drag.\n",
        "choicethree": "lift and the drag.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Flap selection at constant IAS whilst maintaining straight and level flight will increase the ;\n",
        "answer": "maximum lift coefficient ( CLmax ) and the drag.\n",
        "choiceone": "lift coefficient and the drag.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lift and the drag.\n",
        "choicethree": "stall speed.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Flaperons are controls which combine the function of ;\n",
        "answer": "ailerons and flaps.\n",
        "choiceone": "flaps and speed brakes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flaps and elevator.\n",
        "choicethree": "ailerons and elevator.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Floating due to ground effect during an approach to land will occur ;\n",
        "answer": "when the height is less than halve of the length of the wing span above the surface\n",
        "choiceone": "when the height is less than twice the length of the wing span above the surface\n",
        "choicetwo": "at a speed approaching the stall\n",
        "choicethree": "when a higher than normal angle of attack is used\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cFlutter\u201d may be caused by a ;\n",
        "answer": "distortion by bending and torsion of the structure causing increasing vibration in the resonance frequency.\n",
        "choiceone": "roll control reversal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "high airspeed aerodynamic wing stall.\n",
        "choicethree": "low airspeed aerodynamic wing stall.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cFlutter\u201d may be caused by a ;\n",
        "answer": "combination of bending and torsion of the structure.\n",
        "choiceone": "high airspeed aerodynamic wing stall.\n",
        "choicetwo": "combination of fuselage bending and wing torsion.\n",
        "choicethree": "combination roll control reversal and low speed stall.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Flutter of control surfaces is ;\n",
        "answer": "a divergent oscillatory motion of a control surface caused by the interaction of aerodynamic forces , inertia\n forces and the stiffness of the structure.\n",
        "choiceone": "aileron reversal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the accelerated stall of a wing.\n",
        "choicethree": "divergent oscillatory motion of a control surface caused by the interaction of aerodynamic , inertia and\n friction forces.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Flutter sensitivity of an aeroplane wing is reduced by ;\n",
        "answer": "locating the engine ahead of the torsional axis of the wing.\n",
        "choiceone": "empty tanks near the wing tip.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a low torsion stiffness in relation to the bending stiffness.\n",
        "choicethree": "a high speed ( IAS ).\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Following a disturbance , an aeroplane oscillates about the lateral axis at a constant amplitude. The aeroplane is ;\n",
        "answer": "statically stable - dynamically neutral.\n",
        "choiceone": "statically unstable - dynamically neutral.\n",
        "choicetwo": "statically stable - dynamically unstable.\n",
        "choicethree": "statically unstable - dynamically stable.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a fixed-pitch cruise propeller , the blade angle of attack ;\n",
        "answer": "can become negative during high-speed idle descent.\n",
        "choiceone": "decreases when the aircraft speed decreases ( with constant engine RPM ).\n",
        "choicetwo": "is always positive during idle descent.\n",
        "choicethree": "is lower in ground run than in flight ( with constant engine RPM ).\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a fixed-pitch propeller designed for cruise , the angle of attack of each blade , measured at the reference section ;\n",
        "answer": "is optimum when the aircraft is in a stabilized cruising flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "decreases when the aircraft speed decreases ( with identical engine RPM ).\n",
        "choicetwo": "is lower in ground run than in flight ( with identical engine RPM ).\n",
        "choicethree": "is always positive during idling descent.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a fixed-pitch propeller in flight at a given TAS , the blade angle of attack will ;\n",
        "answer": "decrease if RPM decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase if RPM decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "remain constant if RPM increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "remain constant if RPM decreases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a fixed-pitch propeller in flight at a given TAS , the blade angle of attack will ;\n",
        "answer": "increase if RPM increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "remain constant if RPM increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decrease if RPM increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "remain constant if RPM decreases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a given aeroplane which two main variables determine the value of VMCG ?\n",
        "answer": "Airport elevation and temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "Air density and runway length.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Engine thrust and rudder deflection.\n",
        "choicethree": "Engine thrust and gear position.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a given elevator deflection , aeroplane longitudinal manoeuvrability decreases when ;\n",
        "answer": "the CG moves forward.\n",
        "choiceone": "flaps are retracted at constant IAS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IAS increases\n",
        "choicethree": "the CG moves aft.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a given elevator deflection , aeroplane longitudinal manoeuvrability increases when ;\n",
        "answer": "the CG moves aft.\n",
        "choiceone": "flaps are retracted at constant IAS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IAS decreases.\n",
        "choicethree": "the CG moves forward.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a given RPM of a fixed pitch propeller , the blade angle of attack will ;\n",
        "answer": "decrease when the TAS increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "remain constant when the TAS decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "remain constant when the TAS increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "increase when the TAS increases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a given RPM of a fixed pitch propeller , the blade angle of attack will ;\n",
        "answer": "increase when the TAS decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "remain constant when the TAS increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decrease when the TAS decreases.\n",
        "choicethree": "remain constant when the TAS decreases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a normal stable aeroplane , the centre of gravity is located ;\n",
        "answer": "with a sufficient minimum margin ahead of the neutral point of the aeroplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "aft of the neutral point of the aeroplane.\n",
        "choicetwo": "at the neutral point of the aeroplane.\n",
        "choicethree": "between the aft limit and the neutral point of the aeroplane.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a statically stable aeroplane , the relationship between the neutral point and centre of gravity ( CG ) is such that the\nneutral point is located ;\n",
        "answer": "aft of the CG.\n",
        "choiceone": "anywhere , provided it is between the CG\u2019s forward and aft limits.\n",
        "choicetwo": "at the CG.\n",
        "choicethree": "ahead of the CG.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a subsonic flow the continuity equation states that if the cross-sectional area of a tube decreases , the speed of the flow ;\n",
        "answer": "increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "does not change.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decreases.\n",
        "choicethree": "first decreases then increases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For a subsonic flow the continuity equation states that if the cross-sectional area of a tube increases , the speed of the flow ;\n",
        "answer": "decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "first increases then decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "does not change.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For an aeroplane equipped with a two-position variable pitch propeller it is advisable to select a ;\n",
        "answer": "fine pitch for take-off and climb.\n",
        "choiceone": "fine pitch for cruise and coarse pitch for landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "fine pitch for cruise.\n",
        "choicethree": "coarse pitch for take-off and climb.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For an aeroplane to possess dynamic stability , it needs ;\n",
        "answer": "static stability and sufficient damping.\n",
        "choiceone": "sufficient damping only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a large CG range.\n",
        "choicethree": "static stability only.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For an aeroplane with one fixed value of VA the following applies. VA is ;\n",
        "answer": "the speed at which the aeroplane stalls at the manoeuvring limit load factor at MTOW.\n",
        "choiceone": "the maximum speed in smooth air\n",
        "choicetwo": "the speed at which unrestricted application of elevator control can be used , without exceeding the maximum\n manoeuvring limit load factor\n",
        "choicethree": "just another symbol for the rough air speed\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For any propeller ;\n",
        "answer": "thrust is the component of the total aerodynamic force on the propeller parallel to the rotational axis.\n",
        "choiceone": "thrust is the component of the total aerodynamic force on the propeller in the plane of rotation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the force contributing to propeller torque perpendicular to the propeller plane of rotation.\n",
        "choicethree": "the total aerodynamic force on a blade element may be resolved into two components , torque and lift.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For most jet transport aeroplanes , slat extension has ;\n",
        "answer": "a greater effect on stall speed than flap extension.\n",
        "choiceone": "a minor effect on stall speed whereas flap extension has a significant effect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same significant effect on stall speed as flap extension.\n",
        "choicethree": "the same minor effect on stall speed as flap extension.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For most jet transport aeroplanes , the maximum operating limit speed , VMO ;\n",
        "answer": "is replaced by MMO at higher altitudes.\n",
        "choiceone": "is lower than VNE.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is equal to VD.\n",
        "choicethree": "is expressed as a true air speed.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For shallow climb angles the following formula can be used ; ( gamma = climb angle )\n",
        "answer": "sin gamma = T/W - CD/CL.\n",
        "choiceone": "sin gamma = T/W - CL/CD.\n",
        "choicetwo": "sin gamma = W/T - CL/CD.\n",
        "choicethree": "sin gamma = W/T - CD/CL.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "For shallow flight path angles in straight and steady flight , the following formula can be used ;\n",
        "answer": "sin gamma = T/W - CD/CL.\n",
        "choiceone": "sin gamma = T/W - CL/CD.\n",
        "choicetwo": "sin gamma = W/T - CD/CL.\n",
        "choicethree": "sin gamma = W/T - CL/CD.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "From a polar curve of the entire aeroplane one can read ;\n",
        "answer": "the maximum CL/CD ratio and maximum lift coefficient.\n",
        "choiceone": "the minimum drag and the maximum lift.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the minimum CL/CD ratio and the minimum drag.\n",
        "choicethree": "the minimum drag coefficient and the maximum lift.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "From a polar diagram of the entire aeroplane in the clean configuration one can read ;\n",
        "answer": "the maximum CL/CD ratio and maximum lift coefficient.\n",
        "choiceone": "the minimum drag coefficient and the maximum lift.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the minimum drag and the maximum lift.\n",
        "choicethree": "the minimum CL/CD ratio and the minimum drag.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "From an initial condition of level flight the flaps are extended at a constant pitch attitude. The aeroplane will subsequently ;\n",
        "answer": "start to climb.\n",
        "choiceone": "start to sink.\n",
        "choicetwo": "maintain level flight.\n",
        "choicethree": "start to bank.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "From an initial condition of level flight the flaps are retracted at a constant pitch attitude. The aeroplane will subsequently ;\n",
        "answer": "start to sink.\n",
        "choiceone": "start to climb.\n",
        "choicetwo": "start to bank.\n",
        "choicethree": "maintain level flight.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "From the buffet onset graph of a given jet transport aeroplane it is determined that at FL 310 at a given mass buffet free flight\nis possible between M = 0.74 and M = 0.88. In what way would these numbers change if the aeroplane is suddenly pulled up e.g. in a\ntraffic avoidance manoeuvre ?\n",
        "answer": "The lower Mach number increases and the higher Mach number decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "Both Mach numbers increase.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Both Mach numbers decrease.\n",
        "choicethree": "The lower Mach number decreases and the higher Mach number increases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Aeroplane mass : 50 000 kg\n Lift/Drag ratio : 10\n Thrust per engine : 20 000 N\n Assumed g : 10 m/s\u00b2\n For a straight , steady , wings level climb of a four-engine aeroplane , the all engines climb gradient is ;\n",
        "answer": "6.0 %\n",
        "choiceone": "4.3 %\n",
        "choicetwo": "8.5 %\n",
        "choicethree": "7.7 %\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Aeroplane mass : 50 000 kg\n Lift/Drag ratio : 12\n Thrust per engine : 20 000 N\n Assumed g : 10 m/s\u00b2\n For a straight , steady , wings level climb of a four-engine aeroplane , the all engines climb gradient is ;\n",
        "answer": "7.7 %\n",
        "choiceone": "4.3 %\n",
        "choicetwo": "6.0 %\n",
        "choicethree": "8.5 %\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Aeroplane mass : 50 000 kg\n Lift/Drag ratio : 12\n Thrust per engine : 21 000 N\n Assumed g : 10 m/s\u00b2\n For a straight , steady , wings level climb of a four-engine aeroplane , the all engines climb gradient is ;\n",
        "answer": "8.5 %\n",
        "choiceone": "7.7 %\n",
        "choicetwo": "4.3 %\n",
        "choicethree": "6.0 %\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Aeroplane mass : 50 000 kg\n Lift/Drag ratio : 12\n Thrust per engine : 21 000 N\n Assumed g : 10 m/s\u00b2\n For a straight , steady , wings level climb of a four-engine aeroplane , the one engine inoperative climb gradient is ;\n",
        "answer": "4.3 %\n",
        "choiceone": "6.0 %\n",
        "choicetwo": "7.7 %\n",
        "choicethree": "8.5 %\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Aeroplane mass : 50 000 kg\n Lift/Drag ratio : 12\n Thrust per engine : 28 000 N\n Assumed g : 10 m/s\u00b2\n For a straight , steady , wings level climb of a four-engine aeroplane , the one engine inoperative climb gradient is ;\n",
        "answer": "8.5 %\n",
        "choiceone": "8.0 %\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.9 %\n",
        "choicethree": "9.7 %\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Aeroplane mass : 50 000 kg\n Lift/Drag ratio : 10\n Thrust per engine : 30 000 N\n Assumed g : 10 m/s\u00b2\n For a straight , steady , wings level climb of a three-engine aeroplane , the all engines climb gradient is ;\n",
        "answer": "8.0 %\n",
        "choiceone": "2.9 %\n",
        "choicetwo": "9.7 %\n",
        "choicethree": "8.5 %\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Aeroplane mass : 50 000 kg\n Lift/Drag ratio: 12\n Thrust per engine : 28 000 N\n Assumed g : 10 m/s\u00b2.\n For a straight , steady , wings level climb of a three-engine aeroplane , the all-engines climb gradient is ;\n",
        "answer": "8.5 %\n",
        "choiceone": "9.7 %\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.9 %\n",
        "choicethree": "8.0 %\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Aeroplane mass : 50 000 kg\n Lift/Drag ratio : 12\n Thrust per engine : 30 000 N\n Assumed g : 10 m/s\u00b2\n For a straight , steady , wings level climb of a three-engine aeroplane , the all engines climb gradient is ;\n",
        "answer": "9.7 %\n",
        "choiceone": "8.0 %\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.9 %\n",
        "choicethree": "8.5 %\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Aeroplane mass : 50 000 kg\n Lift/Drag ratio : 12\n Thrust per engine : 28 000 N\n Assumed g : 10 m/s\u00b2\n For a straight , steady , wings level climb of a three-engine aeroplane , the one engine inoperative climb gradient is ;\n",
        "answer": "2.9 %\n",
        "choiceone": "8.0 %\n",
        "choicetwo": "8.5 %\n",
        "choicethree": "9.7 %\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Aeroplane mass : 50 000 kg\n Lift/Drag ratio : 10\n Thrust per engine : 60 000 N\n Assumed g : 10 m/s\u00b2\n For a straight , steady , wings level climb of a twin engine aeroplane , the all engines climb gradient is ;\n",
        "answer": "14 %\n",
        "choiceone": "11.7 %\n",
        "choicetwo": "3.7 %\n",
        "choicethree": "15.7 %\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given:\n Aeroplane mass : 50 000 kg\n Lift/Drag ratio: 12\n Thrust per engine : 50 000 N\n Assumed g : 10 m/s\u00b2\n For a straight , steady, wings level climb of a twin engine aeroplane , the all engines climb gradient is ;\n",
        "answer": "11.7 %\n",
        "choiceone": "14 %\n",
        "choicetwo": "15.7 %\n",
        "choicethree": "3.7 %\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Aeroplane mass : 50 000 kg\n Lift/Drag ratio : 12\n Thrust per engine : 60 000 N\n Assumed g : 10 m/s\u00b2\n For a straight , steady , wings level climb of a twin engine aeroplane , the all engines climb gradient is ;\n",
        "answer": "15.7 %\n",
        "choiceone": "3.7 %\n",
        "choicetwo": "11.7 %\n",
        "choicethree": "14 %\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n Aeroplane mass : 50 000 kg\n Lift/Drag ratio : 12\n Thrust per engine : 60 000 N\n Assumed g : 10 m/s\u00b2\n For a straight , steady , wings level climb of a twin engine aeroplane , the one engine inoperative climb gradient is ;\n",
        "answer": "3.7 %\n",
        "choiceone": "15.7 %\n",
        "choicetwo": "11.7 %\n",
        "choicethree": "14 %\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n p = pressure.\n rho = density.\n T = absolute temperature.\n The relationship between pressure , density and absolute temperature of a given mass of air can be expressed as follows ;\n",
        "answer": "p / ( rho * T ) = constant.\n",
        "choiceone": "rho / ( T * p ) = constant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "p * rho / T = constant.\n",
        "choicethree": "p * T / rho = constant.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given ;\n theta = pitch angle.\n gamma = flight path angle.\n alpha = angle of attack.\n no wind , bank or sideslip.\n The relationship between these three parameters is ;\n",
        "answer": "theta = gamma + alpha.\n",
        "choiceone": "theta = gamma - alpha.\n",
        "choicetwo": "gamma = alpha - theta\n",
        "choicethree": "alpha = gamma - theta.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given an aeroplane in steady , straight and level flight at low speed and considering the effects of CG location and thrust ,\nthe highest value of wing lift occurs at ;\n",
        "answer": "forward CG and idle thrust.\n",
        "choiceone": "forward CG and take-off thrust.\n",
        "choicetwo": "aft CG and take-off thrust.\n",
        "choicethree": "aft CG and idle thrust.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given an aeroplane in steady , straight and level flight at low speed and considering the effects of CG location and thrust ,\nthe lowest value of wing lift occurs at ;\n",
        "answer": "aft CG and take-off thrust.\n",
        "choiceone": "forward CG and take-off thrust.\n",
        "choicetwo": "aft CG and idle thrust.\n",
        "choicethree": "forward CG and idle thrust.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given an aeroplane with a propeller turning clockwise as seen from behind , the torque effect during the take off run will\ntend to ;\n",
        "answer": "roll the aeroplane to the left.\n",
        "choiceone": "pitch the aeroplane nose up.\n",
        "choicetwo": "roll the aeroplane to the right.\n",
        "choicethree": "pitch the aeroplane nose down.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given an initial condition in straight and level flight with a speed of 1.4 VS. The maximum bank angle attainable without\nstalling in a steady co-ordinated turn , whilst maintaining speed and altitude , is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "60\u00b0.\n",
        "choiceone": "30\u00b0.\n",
        "choicetwo": "44\u00b0.\n",
        "choicethree": "32\u00b0.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given that ;\n pstat = static pressure.\n rho = density.\n pdyn = dynamic pressure.\n ptot = total pressure.\n Bernoulli\u2019s equation reads as follows ;\n",
        "answer": "pstat + \u00bdrho * TAS2 = constant.\n",
        "choiceone": "pstat + \u00bdrho * TAS2 = pdyn.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ptot = \u00bdrho * IAS2 + pstat.\n",
        "choicethree": "pdyn + pstat = \u00bdrho * TAS2\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given the following aeroplane configurations ;\n 1 Clean wing.\n 2 Slats only extended.\n 3 Flaps only extended.\n Place these configurations in order of stall angle of attack ;\n",
        "answer": "3 , 1 , 2.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 , 1 , 3.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2 , 3 , 1.\n",
        "choicethree": "1 , 3 , 2.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given the following characteristic points on a jet engine aeroplane\u2019s polar curve ;\n 1. CLMAX.\n 2. long range cruise ( zero wind ).\n 3. maximum lift to drag ratio.\n 4. minimum rate of descent ( assume zero thrust ).\n 5. maximum range cruise ( zero wind ).\n Arrange these points in order of increasing angle of attack ;\n",
        "answer": "2 , 5 , 3 , 4 , 1.\n",
        "choiceone": "4 , 5 , 2 , 3 , 1.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 , 2 , 5 , 1 , 4.\n",
        "choicethree": "1 , 2 , 4 , 3 , 5.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Given two identical aeroplanes with wing mounted engines , one fitted with jet engines and the other with counter rotating\npropellers , what happens following an engine failure ?\n",
        "answer": "More roll tendency for the propeller aeroplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "The same yaw tendency for both aeroplanes regardless of left or right engine failure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Less roll tendency for the propeller aeroplane.\n",
        "choicethree": "The same roll tendency for both aeroplanes.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ground effect has the following influence on the landing distance ;\n",
        "answer": "increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "increases , only if the landing flaps are fully extended.\n",
        "choicetwo": "does not change.\n",
        "choicethree": "decreases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Gyroscopic precession of a propeller is induced by ;\n",
        "answer": "pitching and yawing.\n",
        "choiceone": "increasing RPM and yawing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pitching and rolling.\n",
        "choicethree": "increasing RPM and rolling.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "High aspect ratio , as compared with low aspect ratio , has the effect of ;\n",
        "answer": "decreasing induced drag and critical angle of attack\n",
        "choiceone": "increasing lift and drag\n",
        "choicetwo": "increasing lift and critical angle of attack\n",
        "choicethree": "increasing induced drag and decreasing critical angle of attack\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "High speed buffet is induced by ;\n",
        "answer": "boundary layer separation due to shock wave formation.\n",
        "choiceone": "expansion waves on the wing upper surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a shift of the centre of gravity.\n",
        "choicethree": "boundary layer control.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 081-6253A )\n Annex 081-6253A\n How are the speeds ( shown in the figure ) at point 1 and point 2 related to the relative wind/airflow V ?\n",
        "answer": "V1 = 0 and V2 > V\n",
        "choiceone": "V1 < V2 and V2 < V\n",
        "choicetwo": "V1 = 0 and V2 = V\n",
        "choicethree": "V1 > V2 and V2 < V\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can a pilot recognise static stick force stability in an aeroplane during flight ?\n",
        "answer": "To maintain a speed above the trim speed requires a push force.\n",
        "choiceone": "When speed decreases the push-force increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The elevator stick force remains constant with speed changes.\n",
        "choicethree": "To maintain a speed above the trim speed requires a pull force.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can a pilot recognise static stick force stability in an aeroplane during flight ?\n",
        "answer": "To maintain a speed below the trim speed requires a pull force.\n",
        "choiceone": "To maintain a speed below the trim speed requires a push force.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When speed increases the pull force increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "The elevator stick force remains constant with speed changes.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can the designer of an aeroplane with straight wings increase the static lateral stability ?\n",
        "answer": "By increasing the aspect ratio of the vertical stabiliser , whilst maintaining a constant area.\n",
        "choiceone": "By increasing anhedral.\n",
        "choicetwo": "By applying wing twist.\n",
        "choicethree": "By fitting a ventral fin ( a fin at the under side of the aeroplane ).\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How can wing flutter be prevented ?\n",
        "answer": "By locating mass in front of the torsion axis of the wing.\n",
        "choiceone": "By installing the fuel tanks in the fuselage.\n",
        "choicetwo": "By increasing the aspect ratio of the wing.\n",
        "choicethree": "By mounting the engines on the fuselage.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does positive camber of an aerofoil affect static longitudinal stability ? It has ;\n",
        "answer": "no effect , because camber of the aerofoil produces a constant pitch down moment coefficient , independent\n of angle of attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "positive effect , because the centre of pressure shifts rearward at increasing angle of attack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "negative effect , because the lift vector rotates forward at increasing angle of attack.\n",
        "choicethree": "positive effect , because the lift vector rotates backward at increasing angle of attack.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does stall speed ( IAS ) vary with altitude ?\n",
        "answer": "It remains constant at lower altitudes but increases at higher altitudes due to compressibility effects.\n",
        "choiceone": "It remains constant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It remains constant at lower altitudes but decreases at higher altitudes due to compressibility effects.\n",
        "choicethree": "It increases with increasing altitude , because the density decreases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does the Mach number change during a climb at constant IAS from sea level to 40.000 ft ?\n",
        "answer": "Increases with increasing altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "Initially remains constant until approximately 25.000 ft and then decreases with increasing altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Decreases with increasing altitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "Initially remains constant until approximately 25.000 ft and then increases with increasing altitude.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does the total drag change , in straight and level flight at constant mass , as speed is increased from the stall speed ( VS )\nto maximum IAS ( VNE or VMO ) ?\n",
        "answer": "Initially decreases , then increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "Initially increases , then decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Decreases.\n",
        "choicethree": "Increases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does the total drag vary as speed is increased from stalling speed ( VS ) to maximum IAS ( VNE ) in a straight and level\nflight at constant weight ?\n",
        "answer": "Decreasing , then increasing.\n",
        "choiceone": "Increasing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Increasing , then decreasing.\n",
        "choicethree": "Decreasing.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does VA ( EAS ) alter when the aeroplane\u2019s mass decreases by 19% ?\n",
        "answer": "10% lower.\n",
        "choiceone": "19% lower.\n",
        "choicetwo": "4.36% lower.\n",
        "choicethree": "no change.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does VA ( EAS ) alter when the aeroplane\u2019s mass decreases by 19% ?\n",
        "answer": "10% reduction.\n",
        "choiceone": "19% reduction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "4.36% reduction.\n",
        "choicethree": "No change.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How does VMCG change with increasing field elevation and temperature ?\n",
        "answer": "decreases , because the engine thrust decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "increases , because at a lower density a larger IAS is necessary to generate the required rudder force\n",
        "choicetwo": "decreases , because VMCG is expressed in IAS which decreases with constant TAS and decreasing density\n",
        "choicethree": "increases , because VMCG is related to V1 and VR and those speeds increase if the density decreases\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How is adverse yaw compensated for during entry into and roll out from a turn ?\n",
        "answer": "Differential aileron deflection\n",
        "choiceone": "Servo tabs\n",
        "choicetwo": "Anti-balanced rudder control\n",
        "choicethree": "Horn-balanced controls\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How is stall warning presented to the pilots of a large transport aeroplane ?\n",
        "answer": "Stick shaker and/or aerodynamic buffet.\n",
        "choiceone": "Stick pusher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stall warning light only.\n",
        "choicethree": "Aural warning only.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How will the density and static temperature change in a supersonic flow from a position in front of a shock wave to\nbehind it ?\n",
        "answer": "Density will increase , static temperature will increase.\n",
        "choiceone": "Density will increase , static temperature will decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Density will decrease , static temperature will increase.\n",
        "choicethree": "Density will decrease , static temperature will decrease.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a symmetrical aerofoil is accelerated from subsonic to supersonic speed , the aerodynamic centre will move ;\n",
        "answer": "aft to the mid of the chord.\n",
        "choiceone": "aft to the trailing edge.\n",
        "choicetwo": "forward to the mid of the chord.\n",
        "choicethree": "forward to the leading edge.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an aeroplane carries out a descent at 160 kt IAS and 1000 ft/min vertical speed ;\n",
        "answer": "weight is greater than lift.\n",
        "choiceone": "lift is less than drag.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lift is equal to weight.\n",
        "choicethree": "drag is less than the combined forces that move the aeroplane forward.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an aeroplane exhibits insufficient stick force per g , this problem can be resolved by installing ;\n",
        "answer": "a bobweight in the control system which pulls the stick forwards.\n",
        "choiceone": "a spring which pushes the stick forwards.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a spring which pulls the stick backwards.\n",
        "choicethree": "a bobweight in the control system which pulls the stick backwards.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an aeroplane flies in the ground effect ;\n",
        "answer": "the lift is increased and the drag is decreased.\n",
        "choiceone": "drag and lift are reduced.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the effective angle of attack is decreased.\n",
        "choicethree": "the induced angle of attack is increased.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an aeroplane is accelerated from subsonic to supersonic speeds , the centre of pressure will move ;\n",
        "answer": "to the mid chord position.\n",
        "choiceone": "forward.\n",
        "choicetwo": "to a position near the leading edge.\n",
        "choicethree": "to a position near the trailing edge.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If an aeroplane performs a steady co-ordinated horizontal turn at a TAS of 200 kt and a turn radius of 2000 m , the load\nfactor (n) will be approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "1.1\n",
        "choiceone": "1.8\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.0\n",
        "choicethree": "1.4\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If flaps are deployed at constant IAS in straight and level flight , the magnitude of tip vortices will eventually ; ( flap span\nless than wing span )\n",
        "answer": "decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase or decrease , depending on the initial angle of attack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase.\n",
        "choicethree": "remain the same.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If IAS remains constant , the effect of decreasing aeroplane mass is that Mcrit ;\n",
        "answer": "increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "remains unchanged.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decreases , assuming the temperature remains constant.\n",
        "choicethree": "decreases as altitude increases and increases as altitude decreases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If in a two-dimensional incompressible and subsonic flow , the streamlines converge the static pressure in the flow will ;\n",
        "answer": "decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "not change.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase.\n",
        "choicethree": "increase initially , then decrease.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If S is the frontal area of the propeller disc , propeller solidity is the ratio of ;\n",
        "answer": "the total frontal area of all blades to S.\n",
        "choiceone": "the mean chord of one blade to S.\n",
        "choicetwo": "S to the frontal area of one blade.\n",
        "choicethree": "the frontal area of one blade to S.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the airspeed is doubled , whilst maintaining the same control surface deflection the aerodynamic force on this control\nsurface will ;\n",
        "answer": "become four times greater.\n",
        "choiceone": "double.\n",
        "choicetwo": "become four times smaller.\n",
        "choicethree": "increase by the square root of the airspeed.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the airspeed reduces in level flight below the speed for maximum L/D , the total drag of an aeroplane will ;\n",
        "answer": "increase because of increased induced drag.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase because of increased parasite drag.\n",
        "choicetwo": "reduce because of reduced induced drag.\n",
        "choicethree": "reduce because of reduced friction drag.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the altitude is increased and the TAS remains constant in the troposphere under standard atmospheric conditions , the\nMach number will ;\n",
        "answer": "increase.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase or decrease , depending on the type of aeroplane.\n",
        "choicetwo": "not change.\n",
        "choicethree": "decrease.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the aspect ratio of a wing increases whilst all other relevant factors remain constant , the critical angle of attack will ;\n",
        "answer": "decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "remain constant only for a wing consisting of symmetrical aerofoils.\n",
        "choicetwo": "remain constant.\n",
        "choicethree": "increase.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the continuity equation is applicable , what will happen to the air density ( rho ) if the cross sectional area of a tube\nchanges ? ( low speed , subsonic and incompressible flow )\n",
        "answer": "rho1 = rho2\n",
        "choiceone": "rho1 < rho2\n",
        "choicetwo": "rho1 > rho2\n",
        "choicethree": "The density depends on the change of the tube area.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the elevator trim tab is deflected up , the cockpit trim indicator presents ;\n",
        "answer": "nose-down.\n",
        "choiceone": "neutral.\n",
        "choicetwo": "nose-up.\n",
        "choicethree": "nose-left.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the lift generated by a given wing is 1000 kN , what will be the lift if the wing area is doubled ?\n",
        "answer": "2000 kN.\n",
        "choiceone": "4000 kN.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1000 kN.\n",
        "choicethree": "500 kN.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Mach number is 0.8 and the TAS is 400 kt , what is the speed of sound ?\n",
        "answer": "500 kt.\n",
        "choiceone": "480 kt.\n",
        "choicetwo": "600 kt.\n",
        "choicethree": "320 kt.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Mach number is 0.8 and the TAS is 480 kt , what is the speed of sound ?\n",
        "answer": "600 kt.\n",
        "choiceone": "560 kt.\n",
        "choicetwo": "384 kt.\n",
        "choicethree": "750 kt.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the Mach number of an aeroplane in supersonic flight is increased , the Mach cone angle will ;\n",
        "answer": "decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease and beyond a certain Mach number start increasing again.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase.\n",
        "choicethree": "stay constant.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the nose of an aeroplane yaws left , this causes ;\n",
        "answer": "a roll to the left.\n",
        "choiceone": "a roll to the right.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a decrease in relative airspeed on the right wing.\n",
        "choicethree": "an increase in lift on the left wing.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the propeller pitch of a windmilling propeller is decreased during a glide at constant IAS the propeller drag in the direction\nof flight will ;\n",
        "answer": "increase and the rate of descent will increase.\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease and the rate of descent will increase.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decrease and the rate of descent will decrease.\n",
        "choicethree": "increase and the rate of descent will decrease.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the propeller pitch of a windmilling propeller is increased during a glide at constant IAS the propeller drag in the direction\nof flight will ;\n",
        "answer": "decrease and the rate of descent will decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase and the rate of descent will decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decrease and the rate of descent will increase.\n",
        "choicethree": "increase and the rate of descent will increase.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the RPM lever of a constant speed propeller is moved forward during a glide with idle power and whilst maintaining\nconstant airspeed , the propeller pitch will ;\n",
        "answer": "decrease and the rate of descent will increase.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase and the rate of descent will decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase and the rate of descent will increase.\n",
        "choicethree": "decrease and the rate of descent will decrease.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the stall speed of an aeroplane is 60 kt , at what speed will the aeroplane stall if the load factor is 2 ?\n",
        "answer": "85 kt.\n",
        "choiceone": "120 kt.\n",
        "choicetwo": "66 kt.\n",
        "choicethree": "72 kt.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the sum of all the moments in flight is not zero , the aeroplane will rotate about the ;\n",
        "answer": "centre of gravity.\n",
        "choiceone": "aerodynamic centre of the wing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "centre of pressure of the wing.\n",
        "choicethree": "neutral point of the aeroplane.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the static lateral stability of an aeroplane is increased , whilst its static directional stability remains constant ;\n",
        "answer": "its sensitivity to Dutch roll increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "the nose-down pitching moment in a turn increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "turning flight becomes more difficult.\n",
        "choicethree": "its spiral stability decreases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the total sum of moments about one of its axes is not zero , an aeroplane would ;\n",
        "answer": "experience an angular acceleration about that axis.\n",
        "choiceone": "not be affected because the situation is normal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "be difficult to control.\n",
        "choicethree": "fly a path with a constant curvature.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the wing area is increased , lift will ;\n",
        "answer": "increase because it is directly proportional to wing area.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase with the square of the wing area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "remain constant.\n",
        "choicethree": "not change because the lift coefficient is constant.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you decrease the propeller pitch during a glide with idle-power at constant IAS the lift to drag ratio will ;\n",
        "answer": "decrease and the rate of descent will increase.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase and the rate of descent will decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decrease and the rate of descent will decrease.\n",
        "choicethree": "increase and the rate of descent will increase.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you increase the propeller pitch during a glide with idle-power at constant IAS the lift to drag ratio will ;\n",
        "answer": "increase and the rate of descent will decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease and the rate of descent will decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase and the rate of descent will increase.\n",
        "choicethree": "decrease and the rate of descent will increase.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you pull back the RPM lever of a constant speed propeller during a glide with idle power and constant speed , the propeller\npitch will ;\n",
        "answer": "increase and the rate of descent will decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase and the rate of descent will increase.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decrease and the rate of descent will increase.\n",
        "choicethree": "decrease and the rate of descent will decrease.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you push forward the RPM lever of a constant speed propeller during a glide with idle power and constant speed , the\npropeller pitch will ;\n",
        "answer": "decrease and the rate of descent will increase.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase and the rate of descent will increase.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase and the rate of descent will decrease.\n",
        "choicethree": "decrease and the rate of descent will decrease.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ignoring downwash effects on the tailplane , extension of Fowler flaps , will produce ;\n",
        "answer": "a nose-down pitching moment.\n",
        "choiceone": "no pitching moment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a nose-up pitching moment.\n",
        "choicethree": "a force which reduces drag.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a convergent tube with an incompressible sub-sonic airflow , the following pressure changes will occur ;\n Ps = static pressure.\n Pdyn = dynamic pressure.\n Ptot = total pressure.\n",
        "answer": "Ps decreases , Pdyn increases , Ptot remains constant.\n",
        "choiceone": "Ps decreases , Pdyn increases , static temperature increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Ps decreases , Ptot increases , static temperature decreases.\n",
        "choicethree": "Ps increases , Pdyn decreases , Ptot remains constant.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a co-ordinated horizontal turn , the magnitude of the centripetal force at 45 degrees of bank ;\n",
        "answer": "is equal to the weight of the aeroplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "is equal to the lift of the aeroplane.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is greater than the lift of the aeroplane.\n",
        "choicethree": "has a vertical component.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a skidding turn ( the nose pointing inwards ) , compared with a co-ordinated turn , the bank angle (i) and the \u201cball\u201d or slip\nindicator (ii) are respectively ;\n",
        "answer": "(i) too small , (ii) displaced towards the high wing.\n",
        "choiceone": "(i) too large , (ii) displaced towards the high wing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "(i) too small , (ii) displaced towards the low wing.\n",
        "choicethree": "(i) too large , (ii) displaced towards the low wing.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a slipping turn ( nose pointing outwards ) , compared to a co-ordinated turn , the bank angle (i) and the \u201cball\u201d or slip\nindicator (ii) are respectively ;\n",
        "answer": "(i) too large , (ii) displaced towards the low wing.\n",
        "choiceone": "(i) too large , (ii) displaced towards the high wing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "(i) too small , (ii) displaced towards the low wing.\n",
        "choicethree": "(i) too small , (ii) displaced towards the high wing.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a stationary subsonic streamline flow pattern , if the streamlines converge , in this part of the pattern , the static pressure\n(I) will .......... and the velocity (II) will ............ ;\n",
        "answer": "(I) decrease , (II) increase.\n",
        "choiceone": "(I) increase , (II) decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "(I) decrease , (II) decrease.\n",
        "choicethree": "(I) increase , (II) increase.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a steady co-ordinated horizontal turn , lift is ;\n",
        "answer": "greater than in straight and level flight , because it must balance the weight and generate the centripetal force.\n",
        "choiceone": "greater than in straight and level flight , because it must generate the centrifugal force.\n",
        "choicetwo": "greater than in straight and level flight because it must balance the centripetal force.\n",
        "choicethree": "equal to the aeplane weight.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a steady , horizontal , co-ordinated turn ;\n",
        "answer": "thrust equals drag , because there is equilibrium of forces along the direction of flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "thrust equals drag , because drag is the same as in straight and level flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "thrust is greater than drag , because the centrifugal force reduces the aeroplane speed.\n",
        "choicethree": "thrust is greater than drag , because the excess thrust also supplies the centripetal force.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a steady level , co-ordinated turn , the load factor n and the stalling speed VS will be ;\n",
        "answer": "n greater than 1 , VS higher than in straight and level flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "n greater than 1 , VS lower than in straight and level flight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "n smaller than 1 , VS lower than in straight and level flight.\n",
        "choicethree": "n smaller than 1 , VS higher than in straight and level flight.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a steady straight climb at climb angle \u201cgamma\u201d , the lift of an aeroplane with weight W is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "W * cos ( gamma )\n",
        "choiceone": "W * ( 1-sin ( gamma ) )\n",
        "choicetwo": "W * ( 1-tan ( gamma ) )\n",
        "choicethree": "W / cos ( gamma )\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a straight , steady climb the thrust must be ;\n",
        "answer": "greater than the drag because it must also balance a component of weight.\n",
        "choiceone": "greater than drag because more lift has to be produced.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lower than the drag because it is assisted by a component of weight.\n",
        "choicethree": "equal to the drag.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a straight steady descent , which of the following statements is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Lift is less than weight , load factor is less than 1.\n",
        "choiceone": "Lift is equal to weight , load factor is equal to 1.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Lift is equal to weight , load factor is less than 1.\n",
        "choicethree": "Lift is less than weight , load factor is equal to 1.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a twin engine jet aeroplane ( engines mounted below the low wings ) the thrust is suddenly increased. Which elevator\ndeflection will be required to maintain the pitching moment zero ?\n",
        "answer": "Down.\n",
        "choiceone": "Up.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No elevator movement will required because the thrust line of the engines remains unchanged.\n",
        "choicethree": "It depends on the position of the centre of gravity.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In case of supersonic flow retarded by a normal shock wave a high efficiency ( low loss in total pressure ) can be obtained if\nthe Mach number in front of the shock is ;\n",
        "answer": "small but still supersonic.\n",
        "choiceone": "lower than 1.\n",
        "choicetwo": "exactly 1.\n",
        "choicethree": "high ( supersonic ).\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In case the Mach trimmer fails ;\n",
        "answer": "the Mach number must be limited.\n",
        "choiceone": "try to relocate the centre-of-gravity aft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the speed must be kept constant.\n",
        "choicethree": "the aeroplane weight must be limited.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In comparison to a conventional aerofoil section , typical shape characteristics of a supercritical aerofoil section are ;\n",
        "answer": "a larger nose radius , flatter upper surface and negative as well as positive camber.\n",
        "choiceone": "a larger nose radius , flatter lower surface and negative as well as positive camber.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a sharper pointed nose , negative camber and a flatter upper surface.\n",
        "choicethree": "a sharper pointed nose , flatter lower surface and positive camber at the rear of the aerofoil section.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In general , control forces are reduced by ;\n",
        "answer": "a horn balance , servo tab and spring tab.\n",
        "choiceone": "mass balancing , a trim tab and spring tab.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a balance tab , forward shift of the CG and a servo tab.\n",
        "choicethree": "a servo tab , spring tab and mass balancing.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In general , directional controllability with one engine inoperative on a multi-engine aeroplane is adversely affected by: ;\n 1. high temperature.\n 2. low temperature.\n 3. aft CG location.\n 4. forward CG location.\n 5. high altitude.\n 6. low altitude\n The combination that regroups all of the correct statements is ;\n",
        "answer": "2 , 3 , 6.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 , 4 , 5.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 , 4 , 6.\n",
        "choicethree": "2 , 3 , 5.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In general , directional controllability with one engine inoperative on a multi-engine aeroplane is favourably affected by ;\n 1. high temperature.\n 2. low temperature.\n 3. aft CG location.\n 4. forward CG location.\n 5. high altitude.\n 6. low altitude.\n The combination that regroups all of the correct statements is ;\n",
        "answer": "1 , 4 , 5.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 , 4 , 6.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2 , 3 , 5.\n",
        "choicethree": "1 , 4 , 6.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In general transport aeroplanes with power assisted flight controls are fitted with an adjustable stabilizer instead of trim tabs\non the elevator. This is because ;\n",
        "answer": "effectiveness of trim tabs is insufficient for those aeroplanes\n",
        "choiceone": "trim tab deflection increases Mcrit\n",
        "choicetwo": "mechanical adjustment of trim tabs creates too many problems\n",
        "choicethree": "the pilot does not feel the stick forces at all\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to fly a rate one turn at a higher airspeed , the bank angle must be ;\n",
        "answer": "increased and the turn radius will increase.\n",
        "choiceone": "decreased and the turn radius will decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decreased and the turn radius will increase\n",
        "choicethree": "increased and the turn radius will decrease.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to maintain constant speed during a level , co-ordinated turn , compared with straight and level flight , the pilot\nmust ;\n",
        "answer": "increase thrust/power and angle of attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase thrust/power and decrease angle of attack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase thrust/power and keep angle of attack unchanged.\n",
        "choicethree": "increase angle of attack and keep thrust/power unchanged.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to maintain straight and level flight at a constant airspeed , whilst the flaps are being retracted , the angle of attack\nmust be ;\n",
        "answer": "increased\n",
        "choiceone": "increased or decreased depending upon the type of flap\n",
        "choicetwo": "held constant\n",
        "choicethree": "decreased\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to perform a steady level turn at constant speed in an aeroplane , the pilot must ;\n",
        "answer": "increase thrust/power and angle of attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase thrust/power and decrease angle of attack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase angle of attack and keep thrust/power unchanged.\n",
        "choicethree": "increase thrust/power and keep angle of attack unchanged.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to provide an adequate \u201cbuffet boundary\u201d at the commencement of the cruise a speed of 1.3 VS is used. At a mass of\n120.000 kg this is a CAS of 180 knots. If the mass of the aeroplane is increased to 135.000 kg the value of 1.3 VS will be ;\n",
        "answer": "increased to 191 knots , drag will increase and air distance per kg of fuel will decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "increased to 202 knots but , since the same angle of attack is used , drag and range will remain the same.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increased to 191 knots , drag will decrease and air distance per kg of fuel will increase.\n",
        "choicethree": "unaffected as VS always occurs at the same angle of attack.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In straight and level flight , as speed is increased ;\n",
        "answer": "the elevator is deflected further downwards and the trim tab further upwards.\n",
        "choiceone": "the elevator and trim tab do not move.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the elevator is deflected further upwards and the trim tab further downwards.\n",
        "choicethree": "both elevator and trim tab are deflected further downwards.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In straight and level flight , as speed is reduced ;\n",
        "answer": "the elevator is deflected further upwards and the trim tab further downwards.\n",
        "choiceone": "the elevator and trim tab do not move.\n",
        "choicetwo": "both elevator and trim tab are deflected further upwards.\n",
        "choicethree": "the elevator is deflected further downwards and the trim tab further upwards.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In straight and level flight at a speed of 1.3 VS , the lift coefficient , expressed as a percentage of its maximum ( CLmax ) ,\nwould be ;\n",
        "answer": "59%.\n",
        "choiceone": "77%.\n",
        "choicetwo": "130%.\n",
        "choicethree": "169%.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In straight flight , as speed is increased , whilst trimming to keep the stick force zero ;\n",
        "answer": "the elevator is deflected further downwards and the trim tab further upwards.\n",
        "choiceone": "both elevator and trim tab are deflected further downwards.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the elevator and trim tab do not move.\n",
        "choicethree": "the elevator is deflected further upwards and the trim tab further downwards.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In straight flight , as speed is reduced , whilst trimming to keep the stick force zero ;\n",
        "answer": "the elevator is deflected further upwards and the trim tab further downwards.\n",
        "choiceone": "the elevator and trim tab do not move.\n",
        "choicetwo": "both elevator and trim tab are deflected further upwards.\n",
        "choicethree": "the elevator is deflected further downwards and the trim tab further upwards.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In supersonic flight aerofoil pressure distribution is ;\n",
        "answer": "rectangular.\n",
        "choiceone": "triangular.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same as in subsonic flight.\n",
        "choicethree": "irregular.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In supersonic flight , all disturbances produced by an aeroplane are ;\n",
        "answer": "in between a conical area , depending on the Mach Number.\n",
        "choiceone": "very weak and negligible.\n",
        "choicetwo": "outside the conical area depending on the Mach Number.\n",
        "choicethree": "in front of the aeroplane.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In supersonic flight , all disturbances produced by an aeroplane are ;\n",
        "answer": "within a conical zone , dependent on the Mach Number.\n",
        "choiceone": "outside the conical area depending on the Mach Number.\n",
        "choicetwo": "in front of the aeroplane.\n",
        "choicethree": "very weak and negligible.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the event of failure of the Mach trimmer ;\n",
        "answer": "the Mach number must be limited.\n",
        "choiceone": "the speed must be kept constant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the centre of gravity must be moved aft.\n",
        "choicethree": "the aeroplane mass must be limited.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the transonic range lift will decrease at the shock stall due to the ;\n",
        "answer": "separation of the boundary layer at the shock waves.\n",
        "choiceone": "attachment of the shock wave on the trailing edge of the wing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "appearance of the bow wave.\n",
        "choicethree": "first appearance of a shock wave at the upper side of the wing.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the transonic range the aeroplane characteristics are strongly determined by the ;\n",
        "answer": "Mach Number.\n",
        "choiceone": "TAS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IAS.\n",
        "choicethree": "CAS.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In transonic flight the ailerons will be less effective than in subsonic flight because ;\n",
        "answer": "aileron deflection only partly affects the pressure distribution around the wing.\n",
        "choiceone": "behind the shock wave pressure is lower.\n",
        "choicetwo": "aileron down deflection moves the shock wave forward.\n",
        "choicethree": "aileron deflection only affects the air in front of the shock wave.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In twin engine aeroplanes with propellers turning clockwise as seen from behind ;\n",
        "answer": "the left engine is the critical engine.\n",
        "choiceone": "the \u201cminimum control speed\u201d is determined by the failure of the right engine.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the right engine is the critical engine.\n",
        "choicethree": "the left engine produces a higher yaw moment if the right engine fails than vice versa.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In twin-engine aeroplanes with right turning propellers ;\n",
        "answer": "the left engine is the critical motor.\n",
        "choiceone": "the left engine produces a higher yaw moment if the right engine fails than vice versa.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the \u201cminimum control speed\u201d is determined by the failure of the right engine.\n",
        "choicethree": "the right engine is the critical motor.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what flight phase are the outboard ailerons ( if present ) not operated ?\n",
        "answer": "During cruise flight.\n",
        "choiceone": "During take-off , until lift-off.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In the approach phase , before landing.\n",
        "choicethree": "During a landing with strong and gusty crosswind to avoid overcontrolling the aeroplane.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what phase of flight are the outboard ailerons ( if fitted ) not active ?\n",
        "answer": "Cruise.\n",
        "choiceone": "Take-off , until lift-off.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Approach.\n",
        "choicethree": "Landing with a strong and gusty crosswind , to avoid over-controlling the aeroplane.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what way do (1) induced drag and (2) parasite drag alter with increasing speed in straight and level flight ?\n",
        "answer": "(1) decreases and (2) increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "(1) increases and (2) decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "(1) decreases and (2) decreases.\n",
        "choicethree": "(1) increases and (2) increases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what way is the longitudinal stability affected by the degree of positive camber of the aerofoil ?\n",
        "answer": "No effect , because camber of the aerofoil produces a constant pitch down moment coefficient , independent\n of angle of attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "Positive , because the centre of pressure shifts rearward at increasing angle of attack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Negative , because the lift vector rotates forward at increasing angle of attack.\n",
        "choicethree": "Positive , because the lift vector rotates backward at increasing angle of attack.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which phase of the take-off is the aerodynamic effect of ice located on the wing leading edge most critical ?\n",
        "answer": "The last part of the rotation.\n",
        "choiceone": "The take-off run.\n",
        "choicetwo": "All phases of the take-off are equally critical.\n",
        "choicethree": "During climb with all engines operating.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which situation would the wing lift of an aeroplane in straight and level flight have the highest value ?\n",
        "answer": "Forward centre of gravity and idle thrust.\n",
        "choiceone": "Aft centre of gravity and take-off thrust.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aft centre of gravity and idle thrust.\n",
        "choicethree": "Forward centre of gravity and take-off thrust.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Increase of the delta load factor due to a given vertical upgust at a given EAS occurs when ;\n",
        "answer": "the slope of the CL-alpha graph becomes steeper.\n",
        "choiceone": "the wing loading increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the weight increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "the altitude increases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Increase of wing loading will ;\n",
        "answer": "increase the stall speeds.\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease take off speeds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decrease the minimum gliding angle.\n",
        "choicethree": "increase CLmax.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Increasing air density will have the following effect on the drag of a body in an airstream ; ( angle of attack and TAS are\nconstant )\n",
        "answer": "the drag increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "this has no effect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the drag is only affected by the ground speed.\n",
        "choicethree": "the drag decreases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Increasing dynamic pressure will have the following effect on the drag of an aeroplane ; ( all other factors of importance\nremaining constant )\n",
        "answer": "at speeds greater than the minimum drag speed , drag increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "drag increases across the whole speed range.\n",
        "choicetwo": "none.\n",
        "choicethree": "drag decreases across the whole speed range.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Increasing dynamic pressure will have the following effect on the total drag of an aeroplane ;\n",
        "answer": "at speeds above the minimum drag speed , total drag increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "total drag decreases across the whole speed range.\n",
        "choicetwo": "at speeds below the minimum drag speed , total drag decreases.\n",
        "choicethree": "total drag increases across the whole speed range.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Increasing the aspect ratio of a wing ;\n",
        "answer": "decreases induced drag.\n",
        "choiceone": "increases induced drag.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decreases gust load.\n",
        "choicethree": "increases stall speed.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Increasing the number of propeller blades will ;\n",
        "answer": "increase the maximum absorption of power.\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease the torque in the propeller shaft at maximum power.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase the noise level at maximum power.\n",
        "choicethree": "increase the propeller efficiency.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Induced drag at constant IAS is affected by ;\n",
        "answer": "aeroplane weight.\n",
        "choiceone": "aeroplane wing location.\n",
        "choicetwo": "engine thrust.\n",
        "choicethree": "angle between wing chord and fuselage centre line.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Induced drag is created by the ;\n",
        "answer": "spanwise flow pattern resulting in the tip vortices.\n",
        "choiceone": "interference of the air stream between wing and fuselage.\n",
        "choicetwo": "separation of the boundary layer over the wing.\n",
        "choicethree": "propeller wash blowing across the wing.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Induced drag is the result of ;\n",
        "answer": "downwash generated by tip vortices.\n",
        "choiceone": "propeller slipstream over the wing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "aerodynamic interaction between aeroplane parts.\n",
        "choicethree": "boundary layer separation on the aft portion of the wing.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Induced drag may be reduced by ;\n",
        "answer": "an increase in aspect ratio.\n",
        "choiceone": "an increase in the taper ratio of the wing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the use of a wing tip with a much thinner aerofoil.\n",
        "choicethree": "a decrease of the aspect ratio.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Interference drag is the result of ;\n",
        "answer": "aerodynamic interaction between aeroplane parts ( e.g. wing/fuselage ).\n",
        "choiceone": "separation of the induced vortex.\n",
        "choicetwo": "downwash behind the wing.\n",
        "choicethree": "the addition of induced and parasite drag\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Is a transport aeroplane allowed to fly at a higher Mach number than the \u201cbuffet-onset\u201d Mach number in 1 g flight ?\n",
        "answer": "No , this is not acceptable.\n",
        "choiceone": "Yes , if you want to fly fast at very high altitudes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Yes , but only during approach.\n",
        "choicethree": "Yes , this causes no problems.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Just above the critical Mach number the first evidence of a shock wave will appear at the ;\n",
        "answer": "upper side of the wing.\n",
        "choiceone": "trailing edge of the wing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lower side of the wing.\n",
        "choicethree": "leading edge of the wing.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lift is generated when ;\n",
        "answer": "the flow direction of a certain mass of air is changed.\n",
        "choiceone": "a certain mass of air is retarded.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a symmetrical aerofoil is placed in a high velocity air stream at zero angle of attack.\n",
        "choicethree": "a certain mass of air is accelerated in its flow direction.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lift is the ;\n",
        "answer": "component of the total aerodynamic force , perpendicular to the local flow.\n",
        "choiceone": "component of the total aerodynamic force , perpendicular to the undisturbed airflow.\n",
        "choicetwo": "component of the total aerodynamic force , perpendicular to the mean aerodynamic chord.\n",
        "choicethree": "vertical component of the total aerodynamic force , perpendicular to the undisturbed airflow.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Load factor is ;\n",
        "answer": "Lift / Weight\n",
        "choiceone": "1 / Bank angle\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wing loading\n",
        "choicethree": "Weight / Lift\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Load factor is increased by ;\n",
        "answer": "upward gusts.\n",
        "choiceone": "an increase in aeroplane mass.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a decrease in air density.\n",
        "choicethree": "forward CG movement.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Longitudinal stability is directly influenced by ;\n",
        "answer": "centre of gravity position.\n",
        "choiceone": "the vertical stabiliser.\n",
        "choicetwo": "wing dihedral.\n",
        "choicethree": "elevator deflection only.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Longitudinal static stability is created by the fact that the ;\n",
        "answer": "centre of gravity is located in front of the neutral point of the aeroplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "centre of gravity is located in front of the leading edge of the wing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "aeroplane possesses a large trim speed range.\n",
        "choicethree": "wing surface is greater than the horizontal tail surface.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Low speed pitch-up can be caused by a significant thrust ;\n",
        "answer": "increase with podded engines located beneath a low-mounted wing.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase with engines located on the rear fuselage.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decrease with podded engines located beneath a low-mounted wing.\n",
        "choicethree": "decrease with engines located on the rear fuselage.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Low speed pitch up is caused by the ;\n",
        "answer": "spanwise flow on a swept back wing.\n",
        "choiceone": "Mach trim system.\n",
        "choicetwo": "wing tip vortex.\n",
        "choicethree": "spanwise flow on a swept forward wing.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Low speed pitch up is caused by the ;\n",
        "answer": "outward drift of the boundary layer on a swept-back wing.\n",
        "choiceone": "wing tip vortices on high aspect ratio wings.\n",
        "choicetwo": "dihedral effect.\n",
        "choicethree": "boundary layer separation at the wing tip of a forward swept wing.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mach buffet occurs ;\n",
        "answer": "at the Mach Number at which shockwave induced boundary layer separation occurs.\n",
        "choiceone": "when the stalling angle of attack is exceeded.\n",
        "choicetwo": "directly after exceeding Mcrit.\n",
        "choicethree": "when the Mach Number has increased to Mcrit.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mass-balancing of control surfaces is used to ;\n",
        "answer": "prevent flutter of control surfaces.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase the stick force stability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "limit the stick forces.\n",
        "choicethree": "ensure that the control surfaces are in the mid-position during taxiing .\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mcrit is increased by ;\n",
        "answer": "sweepback , thin aerofoils and area ruling.\n",
        "choiceone": "sweepback , dihedral and thin aerofoils.\n",
        "choicetwo": "sweepback , area ruling and high aspect ratio.\n",
        "choicethree": "dihedral , thin aerofoils and supercritical aerofoil sections.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mcrit is the free stream Mach Number at which ;\n",
        "answer": "somewhere about the airframe Mach 1 is reached locally.\n",
        "choiceone": "shockstall occurs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the critical angle of attack is reached.\n",
        "choicethree": "Mach buffet occurs.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Minimum drag of an aeroplane in straight and level flight occurs at the ;\n",
        "answer": "maximum CL-CD ratio.\n",
        "choiceone": "minimum speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "minimum angle of attack.\n",
        "choicethree": "minimum CD value.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Negative tail stall is ;\n",
        "answer": "a sudden reduction in the downward aerodynamic force on the tailplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "flow separation at the rear of the lower surface of the wing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a typical aerodynamic problem for canards.\n",
        "choicethree": "flow reversal on the fin leading to flow re-attachment.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a jet aeroplane ( engines mounted below the low wing ) the thrust is suddenly increased. Which of these statements is\ncorrect about the elevator deflection required to maintain zero pitching moment ?\n",
        "answer": "The elevator must be deflected downward.\n",
        "choiceone": "The amount of elevator deflection is independent of CG location.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No elevator deflection be will required because the thrust line of the engines remains unchanged.\n",
        "choicethree": "The elevator must be deflected upwards.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a large transport aeroplane , the auto-slat system ;\n",
        "answer": "extends the slats automatically when a certain value of angle of attack is exceeded.\n",
        "choiceone": "assist the ailerons.\n",
        "choicetwo": "provides for automatic slat retraction after take-off.\n",
        "choicethree": "ensures that the slats are always extended when the ground/flight system is in the \u201cground\u201d position.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a swept wing aeroplane at low airspeed , the \u201cpitch up\u201d phenomenon ;\n",
        "answer": "is caused by wingtip stall.\n",
        "choiceone": "never occurs , since a swept wing is a \u201cremedy\u201d to pitch up.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is caused by extension of trailing edge lift augmentation devices.\n",
        "choicethree": "is caused by boundary layer fences mounted on the wings.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a symmetrical aerofoil , the pitching moment for which Cl = 0 is ;\n",
        "answer": "zero.\n",
        "choiceone": "negative ( pitch-down ).\n",
        "choicetwo": "positive ( pitch-up ).\n",
        "choicethree": "equal to the moment coefficient for stabilized angle of attack.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a un-swept wing , when the aerofoil is accelerated from subsonic to supersonic speeds , the aerodynamic centre ;\n",
        "answer": "shifts from 25% to about 50% of the aerofoil chord.\n",
        "choiceone": "slightly shifts forward.\n",
        "choicetwo": "remains unchanged.\n",
        "choicethree": "shifts aft by about 10%.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On a wing fitted with a \u201cfowler\u201d type trailing edge flap , the \u201cFull extended\u201d position will produce ;\n",
        "answer": "an increase in wing area and camber.\n",
        "choiceone": "an increase in wing area only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an unaffected CD , at a given angle of attack.\n",
        "choicethree": "an unaffected wing area and increase in camber.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "On an asymmetrical , single curve aerofoil , in subsonic airflow , at low angle of attack , when the angle of attack is\nincreased , the centre of pressure will ( assume a conventional transport aeroplane ) ;\n",
        "answer": "move forward.\n",
        "choiceone": "move aft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "remain unaffected.\n",
        "choicethree": "remain matching the airfoil aerodynamic centre.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "One advantage of a movable-stabilizer system compared with an elevator trim system is that ;\n",
        "answer": "it is a more effective means of trimming.\n",
        "choiceone": "the system\u2019s complexity is reduced.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the complete system ( structure and control mechanism ) weighs less.\n",
        "choicethree": "it leads to greater stability in flight.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "One advantage of a supercritical wing aerofoil over a conventional one is ;\n",
        "answer": "it allows a wing of increased relative thickness to be used for approximately the same cruise Mach number.\n",
        "choiceone": "a lower value of Mcrit at the same relative thickness.\n",
        "choicetwo": "that there is no need for spoilers.\n",
        "choicethree": "improved Dutch roll damping at cruise altitude.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "One advantage of mounting the horizontal tailplane on top of the vertical fin is ;\n",
        "answer": "to improve the aerodynamic efficiency of the vertical fin.\n",
        "choiceone": "that it does not require a de-icing system.\n",
        "choicetwo": "to decrease the susceptibility to deep stall.\n",
        "choicethree": "to decrease fuel consumption by creating a tail-heavy situation.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "One disadvantage of wing sweep is the stalling characteristics. At the stall ;\n",
        "answer": "tip stall will occur first , which produces a pitch-up moment.\n",
        "choiceone": "wing root stall will occur first , which produces a rolling moment\n",
        "choicetwo": "leading edge stall will occur first , which produces a nose-down moment\n",
        "choicethree": "tip stall will occur first , which produces a nose-down moment\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "One disadvantage of wing sweepback is ;\n",
        "answer": "the tendency of the wingtip section to stall prior to the wing root section.\n",
        "choiceone": "the tendency of the wing root section to stall prior to the wingtip section.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a severe pitch down moment when the centre of presure shifts forward.\n",
        "choicethree": "that the critical Mach number is significantly lower.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "One important advantage the turbulent boundary layer has over the laminar layer is that ;\n",
        "answer": "it has less tendency to separate from the surface.\n",
        "choiceone": "skin friction drag is less.\n",
        "choicetwo": "energy is less.\n",
        "choicethree": "it is thinner.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "One method to compensate adverse yaw is ;\n",
        "answer": "a differential aileron.\n",
        "choiceone": "a balance tab.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an anti-balance tab.\n",
        "choicethree": "a balance panel.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the requirements for positive dynamic stability is:\n",
        "answer": "positive static stability.\n",
        "choiceone": "a large deflection range of the stabilizer trim.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a small cg range.\n",
        "choicethree": "an effective elevator.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Outboard ailerons ( if present ) are normally used ;\n",
        "answer": "in low speed flight only.\n",
        "choiceone": "at transonic and supersonic speeds only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "when the landing gear is up.\n",
        "choicethree": "in high speed flight only.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Positive static lateral stability is the tendency of an aeroplane to ;\n",
        "answer": "roll to the left in the case of a sideslip ( with the aeroplane nose pointing to the left of the incoming flow ).\n",
        "choiceone": "roll to the left in the case of a sideslip angle ( with the aeroplane nose pointing to the right of the incoming\n flow ).\n",
        "choicetwo": "roll to the left in a right turn.\n",
        "choicethree": "roll to the right in a right turn.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Positive static lateral stability is the tendency of an aeroplane to ;\n",
        "answer": "roll to the left in the case of a positive sideslip angle ( aeroplane nose to the left ).\n",
        "choiceone": "roll to the right in a right turn.\n",
        "choicetwo": "roll to the right in the case of a positive sideslip angle ( aeroplane nose to the right ).\n",
        "choicethree": "roll to the left in a right turn.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Positive static longitudinal stability means that a ;\n",
        "answer": "nose-down moment occurs after encountering an up-gust.\n",
        "choiceone": "nose-up moment occurs with a speed change at constant angle of attack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "nose-up moment occurs after encountering an up-gust.\n",
        "choicethree": "nose-down moment occurs with a speed change at constant angle of attack.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Positive static stability of an aeroplane means that following a disturbance from the equilibrium condition ;\n",
        "answer": "the initial tendency is to return towards its equilibrium condition.\n",
        "choiceone": "the tendency is to move with an oscillatory motion of decreasing amplitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the tendency is to move with an oscillatory motion of increasing amplitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "the initial tendency is to diverge further from its equilibrium condition.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Propeller blade twist is the ;\n",
        "answer": "varying of the blade angle from the root to the tip of a propeller blade.\n",
        "choiceone": "varying of the helix angle from the root to the tip of a propeller blade.\n",
        "choicetwo": "angle between the blade angle and the direction of the flight of the aeroplane.\n",
        "choicethree": "angle between the relative airflow and the propeller blade\u2019s angle of attack.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Propeller efficiency is ;\n",
        "answer": "the ratio of power available ( Thrust * TAS ) to shaft power ( Torque * RPM ).\n",
        "choiceone": "a number greater than one.\n",
        "choicetwo": "maximum when TAS is zero.\n",
        "choicethree": "greater with a larger number of blades.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Propeller efficiency may be defined as the ratio between:\n",
        "answer": "usable ( power available ) power of the propeller and shaft power.\n",
        "choiceone": "the usable ( power available ) power and the maximum power.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the thermal power of fuel-flow and shaft power.\n",
        "choicethree": "the thrust and the maximum thrust.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regarding a positively cambered aerofoil section , which statement is correct ?\n I. The angle of attack has a negative value when the lift coefficient equals zero.\n II. A nose down pitching moment exists when the lift coefficient equals zero.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct and II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect and II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct and II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect and II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regarding a positively cambered aerofoil section , which statement is correct ?\n I. The angle of attack has a negative value when the lift coefficient equals zero.\n II. A nose up pitching moment exists when the lift coefficient equals zero.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct and II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct and II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect and II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect and II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regarding a positively cambered aerofoil section , which statement is correct ?\n I. The angle of attack has a positive value when the lift coefficient equals zero.\n II. A nose down pitching moment exists when the lift coefficient equals zero.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect and II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect and II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct and II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct and II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regarding a positively cambered aerofoil section , which statement is correct ?\n I. The angle of attack has a positive value when the lift coefficient equals zero.\n II. A nose up pitching moment exists when the lift coefficient equals zero.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect and II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct and II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect and II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct and II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regarding a symmetric aerofoil section , which statement is correct ?\n I. The angle of attack has a negative value when the lift coefficient equals zero.\n II. A nose up pitching moment exists when the lift coefficient equals zero.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect and II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect and II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct and II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct and II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regarding a symmetric aerofoil section , which statement is correct ?\n I. The angle of attack has a positive value when the lift coefficient equals zero.\n II. A nose down pitching moment exists when the lift coefficient equals zero.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect and II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct and II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect and II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct and II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regarding a symmetric aerofoil section , which statement is correct ?\n I. The angle of attack has a positive value when the lift coefficient equals zero.\n II. The pitching moment is zero when the lift coefficient equals zero.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect and II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct and II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct and II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect and II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regarding a symmetric aerofoil section , which statement is correct ?\n I. The angle of attack is zero when the lift coefficient equals zero.\n II. A nose up pitching moment exists when the lift coefficient equals zero.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct and II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct and II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect and II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect and II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regarding a symmetric aerofoil section , which statement is correct ?\n I. The angle of attack is zero when the lift coefficient equals zero.\n II. The pitching moment is zero when the lift coefficient equals zero.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct and II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct and II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect and II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect and II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regarding deep stall characteristics , identify whether the following statements are correct or incorrect ;\n I. A wing with forward sweep and a low horizontal tail makes an aeroplane prone to deep stall.\n II. A stick pusher system can be fitted to an aeroplane that exhibits abnormal stall characteristics.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regarding deep stall characteristics , identify whether the following statements are correct or incorrect ;\n I. A wing with forward sweep and a low horizontal tail makes an aeroplane prone to deep stall.\n II. A stick shaker system is fitted to an aeroplane that exhibits abnormal stall characteristics.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regarding deep stall characteristics , identify whether the following statements are correct or incorrect ;\n I. An aeroplane with a low horizontal tail and wings with sweepback is normally prone to deep stall.\n II. An aeroplane with a canard is normally prone to deep stall.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regarding deep stall characteristics , identify whether the following statements are correct or incorrect ;\n I. The combination of a wing with sweepback and a T-tail make an aeroplane prone to deep stall.\n II. A stick shaker system is fitted to an aeroplane that exhibits abnormal stall characteristics.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regarding the lift formula , if airspeed doubles , lift will ;\n",
        "answer": "be 4 times greater.\n",
        "choiceone": "also double.\n",
        "choicetwo": "halve.\n",
        "choicethree": "not change.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regarding the lift formula , if density doubles , lift will ;\n",
        "answer": "also double.\n",
        "choiceone": "remain the same.\n",
        "choicetwo": "halve.\n",
        "choicethree": "be 4 times greater.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Regarding the transonic speed range ;\n",
        "answer": "both subsonic and supersonic speeds exist in the flow around the aeroplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "it starts at Mcrit and extends to Mach number equal to 1.\n",
        "choicetwo": "it starts at a Mach number equal to1.\n",
        "choicethree": "it starts at a Mach number just above 1.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Rolling is the rotation of the aeroplane about the ;\n",
        "answer": "longitudinal axis.\n",
        "choiceone": "vertical axis.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lateral axis.\n",
        "choicethree": "wing axis.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Rotation about the lateral axis is called ;\n",
        "answer": "pitching.\n",
        "choiceone": "slipping.\n",
        "choicetwo": "yawing.\n",
        "choicethree": "rolling.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Rotation about the longitudinal axis of an aeroplane can be achieved by ;\n",
        "answer": "aileron deflection and/or rudder deflection.\n",
        "choiceone": "speed brake extension or wing flap deflection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "symmetrical spoiler deflection and/or elevator deflection.\n",
        "choicethree": "elevator deflection and/or slat extension.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Rotation around the longitudinal axis is called ;\n",
        "answer": "rolling.\n",
        "choiceone": "pitching.\n",
        "choicetwo": "yawing.\n",
        "choicethree": "slipping.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Rotation around the normal axis is called ;\n",
        "answer": "yawing.\n",
        "choiceone": "rolling.\n",
        "choicetwo": "slipping.\n",
        "choicethree": "pitching.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Select if the following statements are correct or incorrect ;\n i. When the propeller tip speed is supersonic the prop noise doesn\u2019t increase.\n ii. When the propeller tip speed is supersonic it is less efficient.\n",
        "answer": "i. incorrect , ii. correct\n",
        "choiceone": "i. incorrect , ii. incorrect\n",
        "choicetwo": "i. correct , ii. correct\n",
        "choicethree": "i. correct , ii. incorrect\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sensitivity for spiral dive will occur when ;\n",
        "answer": "the static directional stability is positive and the static lateral stability is relatively weak.\n",
        "choiceone": "the dutch roll tendency is too strongly suppressed by the yaw damper.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the static directional stability is negative and the static lateral stability is positive.\n",
        "choicethree": "the static lateral and directional stability are both negative.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Shock induced separation can occur ;\n",
        "answer": "behind a strong normal shock wave , independent of angle of attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "at high Mach numbers , only at low angles of attack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "in supersonic flow only.\n",
        "choicethree": "at high Mach numbers , only at high angles of attack.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Shock induced separation results in ;\n",
        "answer": "decreasing lift.\n",
        "choiceone": "increasing lift.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decreasing drag.\n",
        "choicethree": "constant lift.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Shock stall ;\n",
        "answer": "occurs when the lift coefficient , as a function of Mach number , reaches its maximum value.\n",
        "choiceone": "results from flow separation behind the bow wave.\n",
        "choicetwo": "occurs as soon as Mcrit is exceeded.\n",
        "choicethree": "results from flow separation at the underside of the aerofoil.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Shock stall is ;\n",
        "answer": "separation of the boundary layer behind the shock wave.\n",
        "choiceone": "separation of the flow at high angles of attack and at high Mach Numbers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "separation of the flow behind the bow wave.\n",
        "choicethree": "separation of the flow at the trailing edge of the wing at high Mach Numbers.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Slat extension ;\n",
        "answer": "delays the stall to a higher angle of attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "increases the lift by increasing the wing area and the camber of the aft portion of the wing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "provides a boundary layer suction on the upper surface of the wing.\n",
        "choicethree": "decreases the camber of the aerofoil and diverts the flow around the sharp leading edge.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Slat extension will ;\n",
        "answer": "increase the critical angle of attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "reduce tip vortices.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decrease the energy in the boundary layer on the upperside of the wing.\n",
        "choicethree": "create gaps between leading edge and engine nacelles.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Slat or flap asymmetry occurring after either extension or retraction , may have an effect on controllability since ;\n",
        "answer": "slat asymmetry causes a yawing moment , whereas flap asymmetry causes a large rolling moment.\n",
        "choiceone": "slat and flap asymmetry both cause a large yawing moment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "slat asymmetry causes a large rolling moment , whereas flap asymmetry causes a large yawing moment.\n",
        "choicethree": "slat and flap asymmetry both cause a large rolling moment.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Some aeroplanes have a \u201cwaist\u201d or \u201ccoke bottle\u201d contoured fuselage. This is done to ;\n",
        "answer": "apply area rule.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase the strength of the wing root junction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "fit the engine intakes better to the fuselage.\n",
        "choicethree": "improve the low speed characteristics.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Spoiler deflection causes ;\n",
        "answer": "an increase in drag and decrease in lift.\n",
        "choiceone": "an increase in lift only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an increase in lift and drag.\n",
        "choicethree": "decrease in lift and drag.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Spoiler extension causes ;\n",
        "answer": "an increase in drag and decrease in lift.\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease in lift and drag.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an increase in lift only.\n",
        "choicethree": "an increase in lift and drag.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Spoilers mounted on the wing upper surface can be used to ;\n",
        "answer": "assist the ailerons.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase lift and drag.\n",
        "choicetwo": "assist the elevators.\n",
        "choicethree": "prevent aeroplane yaw following engine failure.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Stall speed ( IAS ) varies with ;\n",
        "answer": "weight.\n",
        "choiceone": "altitude ( below approximately 10.000 ft ).\n",
        "choicetwo": "temperature.\n",
        "choicethree": "density.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Static directional stability is mainly provided by ;\n",
        "answer": "the fin.\n",
        "choiceone": "wing dihedral.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the elevator.\n",
        "choicethree": "wing anhedral.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Static directional stability is the ;\n",
        "answer": "tendency of an aeroplane to recover from a skid with the rudder free.\n",
        "choiceone": "tendency of an aeroplane to recover from a disturbance about the lateral axis.\n",
        "choicetwo": "tendency of an aeroplane to raise the low wing in a sideslip.\n",
        "choicethree": "natural ability of an aeroplane to recover from a disturbance about the longitudinal axis.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Static lateral stability should not be too large , because ;\n",
        "answer": "too much aileron deflection would be required in a crosswind landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "the roll trim sensitivity would increase sharply.\n",
        "choicetwo": "too much rudder deflection would be required in a crosswind landing.\n",
        "choicethree": "constant aileron deflection would be required during cruise in case of crosswind.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Static lateral stability should not be too small , because ;\n",
        "answer": "the aeroplane would show too strong a tendency to spiral dive.\n",
        "choiceone": "the stick force per g would become unacceptably small.\n",
        "choicetwo": "after a disturbance around the longitudinal axis the aeroplane would show too strong a tendency to return to\n the original attitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "the aeroplane would show too strong a tendency for Dutch Roll.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Static lateral stability will be decreased by ;\n",
        "answer": "increasing wing anhedral.\n",
        "choiceone": "increasing the size of the vertical tail.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increasing wing sweepback.\n",
        "choicethree": "the use of a high , rather than low , wing mounting.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Static lateral stability will be decreased by ;\n",
        "answer": "the use of a low , rather than high , wing mounting.\n",
        "choiceone": "reducing wing anhedral.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increasing the size of the vertical tail.\n",
        "choicethree": "increasing wing sweepback.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Static lateral stability will be decreased by ;\n",
        "answer": "reducing wing sweepback.\n",
        "choiceone": "increasing the size of the vertical tail.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the use of a high , rather than low , wing mounting.\n",
        "choicethree": "reducing wing anhedral.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Static lateral stability will be increased by ;\n",
        "answer": "reducing wing anhedral.\n",
        "choiceone": "reducing wing sweepback.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the use of a low , rather than high , wing mounting.\n",
        "choicethree": "reducing the size of the vertical tail.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Static lateral stability will be increased by ;\n",
        "answer": "increasing wing sweepback.\n",
        "choiceone": "increasing wing anhedral.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the use of a low , rather than high , wing mounting.\n",
        "choicethree": "reducing the size of the vertical tail.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Static lateral stability will be increased by ;\n",
        "answer": "the use of a high , rather than low , wing mounting.\n",
        "choiceone": "increasing wing anhedral.\n",
        "choicetwo": "reducing wing sweepback.\n",
        "choicethree": "reducing the size of the vertical tail.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Static pressure is acts ;\n",
        "answer": "in all directions.\n",
        "choiceone": "only in the direction of the total pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only perpendicular to the direction of the flow.\n",
        "choicethree": "only in direction of the flow.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Static stability means that ;\n",
        "answer": "following a disturbance from the equilibrium condition , a force and/or moment is generated that tends to\n counter the effects of that disturbance.\n",
        "choiceone": "the amplitude of the oscillatory motion of an aeroplane tends to decrease over time.\n",
        "choicetwo": "following a disturbance from the equilibrium condition , a force and/or moment is generated that tends to\n increase the effects of that disturbance.\n",
        "choicethree": "the amplitude of the oscillatory motion of an aeroplane tends to increase over time.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Stick force per g ;\n",
        "answer": "is dependent on cg location.\n",
        "choiceone": "does not change with increasing altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "has a maximum value related to acceptable controllability , the minimum value is of no concern.\n",
        "choicethree": "is selected by he pilot by electronic means before each flight.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Stick forces , provided by an elevator feel system , depend on ;\n",
        "answer": "elevator deflection , dynamic pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "stabilizer position , static pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "elevator deflection , static pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "stabilizer position , total pressure.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sweepback of a wing positively influences ;\n 1. static longitudinal stability.\n 2. static lateral stability.\n 3. dynamic longitudinal stability.\n The combination that regroups all of the correct statements is ;\n",
        "answer": "2.\n",
        "choiceone": "3.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 , 2 , 3.\n",
        "choicethree": "1.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Taper ratio of a wing is the ratio between ;\n",
        "answer": "tip chord and root chord.\n",
        "choiceone": "root chord and tip chord.\n",
        "choicetwo": "mean geometric chord and wing span.\n",
        "choicethree": "wing span squared and wing area.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The (1) stick force stability and the (2) manoeuvre stability are positively affected by ;\n",
        "answer": "(1) forward CG movement (2) forward CG movement.\n",
        "choiceone": "(1) trimming the aeroplane nose up (2) trimming the aeroplane nose up.\n",
        "choicetwo": "(1) aft CG movement (2) aft CG movement.\n",
        "choicethree": "(1) forward CG movement (2) trimming the aeroplane nose up.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The additional increase of drag at Mach Numbers above the critical Mach Number is due to ;\n",
        "answer": "wave drag.\n",
        "choiceone": "increased skin friction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increased interference drag.\n",
        "choicethree": "increased angle of attack.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The aerodynamic centre of a wing is the point relative to which ;\n",
        "answer": "assuming no flow separation , the pitching moment coefficient does not change with varying angle of attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "the aeroplane becomes longitudinally unstable when the CG is moved beyond it in an aft direction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the velocity of the relative airflow is reduced to zero.\n",
        "choicethree": "the boundary layer changes from laminar to turbulent.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The aerodynamic centre of the wing is the point , where ;\n",
        "answer": "the pitching moment coefficient does not vary with angle of attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "changes of lift due to variations in angle of attack are constant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "aerodynamic forces are constant.\n",
        "choicethree": "the aeroplane\u2019s lateral axis intersects with the centre of gravity.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The aerodynamic contribution to the static longitudinal stability of the nacelles of aft fuselage mounted engines is ;\n",
        "answer": "positive.\n",
        "choiceone": "negative.\n",
        "choicetwo": "maximum during cruise.\n",
        "choicethree": "zero.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The aerodynamic drag of a body , placed in a certain airstream depends amongst others on ;\n",
        "answer": "The airstream velocity.\n",
        "choiceone": "The weight of the body.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The specific mass of the body.\n",
        "choicethree": "The c.g. location of the body.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The aerofoil polar is ;\n",
        "answer": "a graph of the relation between the lift coefficient and the drag coefficient.\n",
        "choiceone": "a graph of the relation between the lift coefficient and the angle of attack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the relation between the horizontal and the vertical speed.\n",
        "choicethree": "a graph , in which the thickness of the wing aerofoil is given as a function of the chord.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The aeroplane drag in straight and level flight is lowest when the ;\n",
        "answer": "parasite drag is equal to the induced drag.\n",
        "choiceone": "induced drag is lowest.\n",
        "choicetwo": "induced drag is equal to zero.\n",
        "choicethree": "parasite drag equals twice the induced drag.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 4 )\n Image 4\n The aeroplane motion , schematically illustrated in the annex , is an example of a dynamically ;\n",
        "answer": "unstable periodic motion.\n",
        "choiceone": "stable periodic motion.\n",
        "choicetwo": "indifferent periodic motion.\n",
        "choicethree": "indifferent aperiodic motion.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The aft CG limit can be determined by the ;\n",
        "answer": "minimum acceptable static longitudinal stability.\n",
        "choiceone": "maximum elevator deflection available.\n",
        "choicetwo": "minimum acceptable elevator deflection.\n",
        "choicethree": "maximum static longitudinal stability required.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The aft movement of the centre of pressure during the acceleration through the transonic flight regime will ;\n",
        "answer": "increase the static longitudinal stability.\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease the longitudinal stability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase the static lateral stability.\n",
        "choicethree": "decrease the static lateral stability.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The airload on the horizontal tailplane ( tailload ) of an aeroplane in straight and level cruise flight ;\n",
        "answer": "is in general directed downwards and will become less negative when the c.g. moves aft.\n",
        "choiceone": "will in principle be zero on transport aeroplanes without an electronic flight control system ( Fly-by-Wire )\n due to the trim system.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is in general directed upwards and will increase when c.g. is moved forward.\n",
        "choicethree": "is in general directed downwards and will always become less negative in a linear fashion with increasing\n airspeed.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The angle between the aeroplane longitudinal axis and the chord line is the ;\n",
        "answer": "angle of incidence.\n",
        "choiceone": "climb path angle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "angle of attack.\n",
        "choicethree": "glide path angle.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The angle between the airflow ( relative wind ) and the chord line of an aerofoil is ;\n",
        "answer": "angle of attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "glide path angle.\n",
        "choicetwo": "same as the angle between chord line and fuselage axis.\n",
        "choicethree": "climb path angle.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The angle of attack ( aerodynamic angle of incidence ) of an aerofoil is the angle between the ;\n",
        "answer": "chord line and the relative undisturbed airflow.\n",
        "choiceone": "bottom surface and the relative airflow.\n",
        "choicetwo": "bottom surface and the horizontal\n",
        "choicethree": "bottom surface and the chord line.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The angle of attack for a propeller blade is the angle between the blade chord line and the ;\n",
        "answer": "local air speed vector.\n",
        "choiceone": "aeroplane heading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "principal direction of the propeller blade.\n",
        "choicethree": "direction of propeller axis.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The angle of attack of a fixed pitch propeller blade increases when ;\n",
        "answer": "RPM increases and forward velocity decreases\n",
        "choiceone": "forward velocity increases and RPM decreasing\n",
        "choicetwo": "velocity and RPM increase\n",
        "choicethree": "velocity and RPM decrease\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The angle of attack of a propeller blade element is the angle between the blade element chord line and the ;\n",
        "answer": "resultant air speed vector.\n",
        "choiceone": "propeller plane.\n",
        "choicetwo": "propeller axis.\n",
        "choicethree": "TAS vector.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 26 )\n Image 26\n The angle of attack of a rotating propeller blade element shown in the annex is ;\n",
        "answer": "angle 1.\n",
        "choiceone": "angle 2.\n",
        "choicetwo": "not correctly indicated in the diagram.\n",
        "choicethree": "angle 3.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The angle of attack of a two dimensional wing section is the angle between ;\n",
        "answer": "the chord line of the aerofoil and the free stream direction.\n",
        "choiceone": "the chord line of the aerofoil and the fuselage centreline.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the chord line and the camber line of the aerofoil.\n",
        "choicethree": "the fuselage centreline and the free stream direction.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The angle of attack of a wing profile is defined as the angle between ;\n",
        "answer": "the undisturbed airflow and the chordline.\n",
        "choiceone": "the local airflow and the chordline.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the local airflow and the mean camberline.\n",
        "choicethree": "the undisturbed airflow and the mean camberline.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The angle of attack of an aerofoil section is defined as the angle between the ;\n",
        "answer": "undisturbed airflow and the chord line.\n",
        "choiceone": "undisturbed airflow and the mean camberline.\n",
        "choicetwo": "local airflow and the mean camberline.\n",
        "choicethree": "local airflow and the chord line.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The angle of attack of an aerofoil section is the angle between the ;\n",
        "answer": "chord line and the relative undisturbed airflow.\n",
        "choiceone": "bottom surface and the horizontal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "bottom surface and the relative airflow.\n",
        "choicethree": "bottom surface and the chord line.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The application of the area rule on aeroplane design will decrease the ;\n",
        "answer": "wave drag.\n",
        "choiceone": "skin friction drag.\n",
        "choicetwo": "induced drag.\n",
        "choicethree": "form drag.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The aspect ratio of the wing ;\n",
        "answer": "is the ratio between the wing span and the mean geometric chord.\n",
        "choiceone": "is the ratio between the tip chord and the wing span.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is the ratio between chord and root chord.\n",
        "choicethree": "is the ratio between the wing span and the root chord.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The asymmetric blade effect on an single engine aeroplane with a clockwise rotating propeller ;\n",
        "answer": "produces left yaw.\n",
        "choiceone": "does not produce any yaw.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is also called the gyroscopic effect.\n",
        "choicethree": "produces right yaw.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The bank angle in a rate-one turn depends on ;\n",
        "answer": "TAS.\n",
        "choiceone": "load factor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "weight.\n",
        "choicethree": "wind.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The blade angle of a propeller is usually referenced at ;\n",
        "answer": "75 % of blade radius.\n",
        "choiceone": "25 % of blade radius.\n",
        "choicetwo": "99 % of blade radius.\n",
        "choicethree": "50 % of blade radius.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 26 )\n Image 26\n The blade angle of a rotating propeller blade element shown in the annex is ;\n",
        "answer": "angle 2.\n",
        "choiceone": "angle 3.\n",
        "choicetwo": "angle 1.\n",
        "choicethree": "not correctly indicated in the diagram.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The boundary layer of a wing is ;\n",
        "answer": "a layer on the wing in which the stream velocity is lower than the free stream velocity.\n",
        "choiceone": "a turbulent flow around the wing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "caused by suction on the upper wing surface.\n",
        "choicethree": "created by the normal shock wave at transonic speeds.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The bow wave will first appear at ;\n",
        "answer": "a Mach number just above M = 1.\n",
        "choiceone": "Mach 1.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a Mach number just below M = 1.\n",
        "choicethree": "the critical Mach number.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The centre of gravity moving aft will ;\n",
        "answer": "increase the elevator up effectiveness.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase or decrease the elevator up effectiveness , depending on wing location.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decrease the elevator up effectiveness.\n",
        "choicethree": "not affect the elevator up or down effectiveness.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The CG of an aeroplane is in a fixed position forward of the neutral point. Speed changes cause a departure from the trimmed\nposition. Which of the following statements about the stick force stability is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "An increase of 10 kt from the trimmed position at low speed has more effect on the stick force than an\n increase of 10 kt from the trimmed position at high speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Increase of speed generates pull forces.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Stick force stability is not affected by trim.\n",
        "choicethree": "Aeroplane nose up trim decreases the stick force stability.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The CG of an aeroplane is in a fixed position forward of the neutral point. Which of these statements about the stick force\nstability is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "An increase of 10 kt from the trimmed position at high speed has less effect on the stick force than an\n increase of 10 kt from the trimmed position at low speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Maintaining a steady speed below the trim speed requires a push force.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aeroplane nose down trim increases the stick force stability.\n",
        "choicethree": "Stick force stability is not affected by trim.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Cl - alpha curve of a positive cambered aerofoil intersects with the vertical axis of the Cl - alpha graph ;\n",
        "answer": "above the origin.\n",
        "choiceone": "nowhere.\n",
        "choicetwo": "below the origin.\n",
        "choicethree": "in the origin.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The consequences of exceeding Mcrit in a swept-wing aeroplane may be ; ( assume no corrective devices, straight and level\nflight )\n",
        "answer": "buffeting of the aeroplane and a tendency to pitch down.\n",
        "choiceone": "an increase in speed and a tendency to pitch up.\n",
        "choicetwo": "buffeting of the aeroplane and a tendency to pitch up.\n",
        "choicethree": "engine unbalance and buffeting.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The continuity equation states ; If the area of a tube is increasing , the speed of the subsonic and incompressible flow inside\nis ;\n",
        "answer": "decreasing.\n",
        "choiceone": "increasing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "sonic.\n",
        "choicethree": "not changing.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The contribution of swept back wings to static directional stability ;\n",
        "answer": "is positive.\n",
        "choiceone": "is nil.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decreases as the sweepback increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "is negative.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The contribution of the wing to the static longitudinal stability of an aeroplane ;\n",
        "answer": "depends on CG location relative to the wing aerodynamic centre.\n",
        "choiceone": "is always negative.\n",
        "choicetwo": "depends on the wing location relative to the fuselage.\n",
        "choicethree": "is positive if the wing has a positively cambered aerofoil section and the aerodynamic centre is ahead of the\n CG.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The contribution of wing sweep back to static directional stability is ;\n",
        "answer": "positive.\n",
        "choiceone": "zero.\n",
        "choicetwo": "negative.\n",
        "choicethree": "posiive or negative depending on sweepback angle.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The contribution to the static directional stability of a straight wing with high aspect ratio and without dihedral ;\n",
        "answer": "is always negligible.\n",
        "choiceone": "is always negative.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is always positive.\n",
        "choicethree": "becomes more positive as the aspect ratio increases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The correct drag formula is ;\n",
        "answer": "D = CD \u00bdRHO V\u00b2 S\n",
        "choiceone": "D = CD \u00bd 1/RHO V\u00b2 S\n",
        "choicetwo": "D = CD \u00bdRHO V S\n",
        "choicethree": "D = CD 2 RHO V\u00b2 S\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 32 )\n Image 32\n The correct sequence of cross-sections representing propeller blade twist is ;\n",
        "answer": "sequence 2.\n",
        "choiceone": "sequence 4.\n",
        "choicetwo": "sequence 1.\n",
        "choicethree": "sequence 3.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 33 )\n Image 33\n The correct sequence of cross-sections representing propeller blade twist is ;\n",
        "answer": "sequence 3.\n",
        "choiceone": "sequence 2.\n",
        "choicetwo": "sequence 1.\n",
        "choicethree": "sequence 4.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The critical angle of attack ;\n",
        "answer": "remains unchanged regardless of gross weight.\n",
        "choiceone": "decreases if the CG is moved aft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "changes with an increase in gross weight.\n",
        "choicethree": "increases if the CG is moved forward.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The critical Mach number can be increased by ;\n",
        "answer": "sweepback of the wings.\n",
        "choiceone": "an increase in wing aspect ratio.\n",
        "choicetwo": "positive dihedral of the wings.\n",
        "choicethree": "a T-tail.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The critical Mach number for an aerofoil equals the free stream airfoil Mach number at which ;\n",
        "answer": "sonic speed ( M=1 ) is reached at a certain point on the upper side of the aerofoil.\n",
        "choiceone": "a \u201csupersonic bell\u201d appears on the upper surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a shock-wave appears on the upper surface.\n",
        "choicethree": "the maximum operating temperature is reached.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The critical Mach number of an aerofoil is the free stream Mach number at which ;\n",
        "answer": "sonic speed ( M=1 ) is first reached on the upper surface.\n",
        "choiceone": "a \u201csupersonic bell\u201d appears on the upper surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the maximum operating temperature is reached.\n",
        "choicethree": "a shock-wave appears on the upper surface.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The critical Mach Number of an aeroplane can be increased by ;\n",
        "answer": "sweep back of the wings.\n",
        "choiceone": "control deflection\n",
        "choicetwo": "vortex generators.\n",
        "choicethree": "dihedral of the wings.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The critical Mach number of an aeroplane is the free stream Mach number that produces the first sign of ;\n",
        "answer": "local sonic flow.\n",
        "choiceone": "buffet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "supersonic flow.\n",
        "choicethree": "a shock wave.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The critical Mach Number of an aeroplane is the free stream Mach Number , which produces the first evidence of ;\n",
        "answer": "local sonic flow.\n",
        "choiceone": "shock wave.\n",
        "choicetwo": "supersonic flow.\n",
        "choicethree": "buffet.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The critical Mach number of an aeroplane is the Mach number ;\n",
        "answer": "above which , locally , supersonic flow exists somewhere over the aeroplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "at which there is subsonic flow over all parts of the aeroplane.\n",
        "choicetwo": "at which there is supersonic flow over a part of the aeroplane.\n",
        "choicethree": "at which the aeroplane has zero buffet margin.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The descent angle of a given aeroplane in a steady wings level glide has a fixed value for a certain combination of ; ( ignore\ncompressibility effects and assume zero thrust )\n",
        "answer": "configuration and angle of attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "altitude and configuration.\n",
        "choicetwo": "mass and altitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "configuration and mass.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 7 )\n Image 7\n The diagram representing a feathered propeller is ;\n",
        "answer": "diagram 3\n",
        "choiceone": "diagram 4\n",
        "choicetwo": "diagram 2\n",
        "choicethree": "diagram 1\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 081-6250A )\n Annex 081-6250A\n The diagram shows the parameter X versus TAS. If a horizontal flight is considered the axis X shows ;\n",
        "answer": "the induced drag.\n",
        "choiceone": "the lift force.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the total drag.\n",
        "choicethree": "the parasite drag.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 7 )\n Image 7\n The diagram that correctly represents the aerodynamic forces acting on a propeller in normal flight is ;\n",
        "answer": "Diagram 1\n",
        "choiceone": "Diagram 2\n",
        "choicetwo": "Diagram 4\n",
        "choicethree": "Diagram 3\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 7 )\n Image 7\n The diagram that correctly represents the aerodynamic forces acting on a propeller in reverse thrust is ;\n",
        "answer": "Diagram 2\n",
        "choiceone": "Diagram 1\n",
        "choicetwo": "Diagram 4\n",
        "choicethree": "Diagram 3\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 7 )\n Image 7\n The diagram that correctly represents the aerodynamic forces acting on a windmilling propeller is ;\n",
        "answer": "Diagram 4\n",
        "choiceone": "Diagram 2\n",
        "choicetwo": "Diagram 3\n",
        "choicethree": "Diagram 1\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 7 )\n Image 7\n The diagram that correctly represents the propeller in the feathered position is ;\n",
        "answer": "Diagram 3\n",
        "choiceone": "Diagram 2\n",
        "choicetwo": "Diagram 1\n",
        "choicethree": "Diagram 4\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 8 )\n Image 8\n The diagram the letter which correctly represents the Angle of Advance ( Helix Angle ) is ;\n",
        "answer": "D\n",
        "choiceone": "B\n",
        "choicetwo": "A\n",
        "choicethree": "C\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The difference between a propeller\u2019s blade angle and its angle of attack is called ;\n",
        "answer": "the helix angle.\n",
        "choiceone": "propeller slip.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the effective pitch.\n",
        "choicethree": "the propeller angle.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The difference between IAS and TAS will ;\n",
        "answer": "decrease with decreasing altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase with decreasing temperature.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decrease with increasing speed.\n",
        "choicethree": "increase with increasing air density.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The difference between the effects of slat and flap asymmetry is that ; ( \u201clarge\u201d in the context of this question means not or\nhardly controllable by normal use of controls )\n",
        "answer": "flap asymmetry causes a large rolling moment at any speed whereas slat asymmetry causes a large difference\n in CLmax.\n",
        "choiceone": "flap asymmetry causes a large rolling moment whereas slat asymmetry causes a large yawing moment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "flap asymmetry causes a large yawing moment whereas slat asymmetry causes a large rolling moment at any\n speed.\n",
        "choicethree": "flap asymmetry causes a large difference in CLmax whereas slat asymmetry causes a large rolling moment at\n any speed.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The effect of a positive wing sweep on static directional stability is as follows ;\n",
        "answer": "Stabilizing effect\n",
        "choiceone": "No effect\n",
        "choicetwo": "Negative dihedral effect\n",
        "choicethree": "Destabilizing dihedral effect\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The effect of a ventral fin on the static stability of an aeroplane is as follows ; ( 1 = longitudinal , 2 = lateral , 3 = directional )\n",
        "answer": "1 : no effect , 2 : negative , 3 : positive\n",
        "choiceone": "1 : no effect , 2 : positive , 3 : negative\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 : negative , 2 : positive , 3 : positive\n",
        "choicethree": "1 : positive , 2 : negative , 3 : negative\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The effect of a wing with sweepback on static directional stability is as follows ;\n",
        "answer": "Stabilizing effect.\n",
        "choiceone": "Destabilizing dihedral effect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No effect.\n",
        "choicethree": "Negative dihedral effect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The effect of increasing angle of sweep is ;\n",
        "answer": "an increase in the critical Mach number.\n",
        "choiceone": "a decrease in stall speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a decrease in the critical Mach number.\n",
        "choicethree": "an increase in the longitudinal stability.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The effect of the wing downwash on the static longitudinal stability of an aeroplane is ;\n",
        "answer": "negative.\n",
        "choiceone": "smallest at high values of the lift coefficient.\n",
        "choicetwo": "positive.\n",
        "choicethree": "negligible.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The effect on static stability of an aeroplane with a high wing as compared to a low wing is ;\n",
        "answer": "a positive dihedral effect.\n",
        "choiceone": "zero dihedral effect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "no effect as it is only used to improve aeroplane loading.\n",
        "choicethree": "a negative dihedral effect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The effective pitch of a propeller is the ;\n",
        "answer": "actual distance a propeller advances in one revolution.\n",
        "choiceone": "angle between the chordline of a blade element and the propeller plane of rotation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the distance a propeller advances with slippage.\n",
        "choicethree": "theoretical distance a propeller would advance in one revolution at zero blade angle of attack.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The effects of very heavy rain ( tropical rain ) on the aerodynamic characteristics of an aeroplane are ;\n",
        "answer": "decrease of CLmax and increase of drag.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase of CLmax and decrease of drag.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decrease of CLmax and decrease of drag.\n",
        "choicethree": "increase of CLmax and increase of drag.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The elevator deflection required for a given manoeuvre will be ;\n",
        "answer": "larger at low IAS when compared to high IAS.\n",
        "choiceone": "the same for all CG positions.\n",
        "choicetwo": "larger for an aft CG posion when compared to a forward position.\n",
        "choicethree": "the same at all speeds.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The elevator deflection required for a given manoeuvre will be ;\n",
        "answer": "smaller at high IAS when compared to low IAS.\n",
        "choiceone": "larger for an aft CG posion when compared to a forward position.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the same for all CG positions.\n",
        "choicethree": "the same at all speeds.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The elevator deflection required for a given manoeuvre will be ;\n",
        "answer": "larger for a forward CG posion when compared to an aft position.\n",
        "choiceone": "the same at all speeds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "larger at high IAS when compared to low IAS.\n",
        "choicethree": "larger for an aft CG posion when compared to a forward position.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The elevator deflection required for a given manoeuvre will be ;\n",
        "answer": "smaller for an aft CG posion when compared to a forward position.\n",
        "choiceone": "larger for an aft CG posion when compared to a forward position.\n",
        "choicetwo": "larger at high IAS when compared to low IAS.\n",
        "choicethree": "the same at all speeds.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The extreme right limitation for both gust and manoeuvre diagrams is created by the speed ;\n",
        "answer": "VD\n",
        "choiceone": "VMO\n",
        "choicetwo": "Vflutter\n",
        "choicethree": "VC\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The flight Mach number is 0.8 and the TAS is 400 kts. The speed of sound is ;\n",
        "answer": "500 kts\n",
        "choiceone": "480 kts\n",
        "choicetwo": "320 kts\n",
        "choicethree": "600 kts\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following factors increase stall speed ;\n",
        "answer": "an increase in load factor , a forward cg shift , decrease in thrust.\n",
        "choiceone": "increasing bank angle , increasing thrust , slat extension.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a higher weight , selecting a higher flap setting , a forward cg shift.\n",
        "choicethree": "a lower weight , decreasing bank angle, a smaller flapsetting.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The following unit of measurement : kgm/s\u00b2 is expressed in the SI-system as ;\n",
        "answer": "Newton\n",
        "choiceone": "Joule\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pascal\n",
        "choicethree": "Watt\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The forces of lift and drag on an aerofoil are , respectively , normal and parallel to the ;\n",
        "answer": "relative wind/airflow.\n",
        "choiceone": "chord line.\n",
        "choicetwo": "horizon.\n",
        "choicethree": "longitudinal axis.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The formula for the Mach Number is ; ( a = speed of sound )\n",
        "answer": "M = TAS / a\n",
        "choiceone": "M = a / TAS\n",
        "choicetwo": "M = TAS*a\n",
        "choicethree": "M = IAS / a\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The four forces acting on an aeroplane in level flight are ;\n",
        "answer": "thrust , lift , drag and weight.\n",
        "choiceone": "thrust , lift , drag and mass.\n",
        "choicetwo": "power , lift , gravity and drag.\n",
        "choicethree": "power , velocity , weight and friction.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The frontal area of a body , placed in a certain airstream is increased by a factor 3. The shape will not alter. The aerodynamic\ndrag will increase with a factor ;\n",
        "answer": "3.\n",
        "choiceone": "6.\n",
        "choicetwo": "9.\n",
        "choicethree": "1.5.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The function of ailerons is to rotate the aeroplane about the ;\n",
        "answer": "longitudinal axis.\n",
        "choiceone": "normal axis.\n",
        "choicetwo": "yaw axis.\n",
        "choicethree": "lateral axis.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The function of the slot between an extended slat and the leading edge of the wing is to ;\n",
        "answer": "cause a venturi effect which energizes the boundary layer.\n",
        "choiceone": "reduce the wing loading.\n",
        "choicetwo": "allow space for vibration of the slat.\n",
        "choicethree": "slow the air flow in the slot so that more pressure is created under the wing.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The function of the stick pusher is ;\n",
        "answer": "to activate and push the stick forward at or beyond a certain value of angle of attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "to vibrate the controls.\n",
        "choicetwo": "to activate and push the stick forward prior to stick shaker.\n",
        "choicethree": "to pull the stick , to avoid a high speed stall.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The fundamental difference between the aerodynamic characteristics of two and three-dimensional flow is that , in a three-\ndimensional flow about a wing ;\n",
        "answer": "a spanwise component exists in addition to the chordwise speed component.\n",
        "choiceone": "flow separation occurs at the stall.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an upward component is added to the chordwise speed component.\n",
        "choicethree": "a downward component is added to the chordwise speed component of the flow behind the wing.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The geometric pitch of a propeller is the ;\n",
        "answer": "theoretical distance a propeller would advance in one revolution at zero blade angle of attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "distance a propeller advances with slippage.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the angle between the chordline of a blade element and the propeller plane of rotation.\n",
        "choicethree": "distance a propeller would have to advance in one revolution to give no thrust.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The gust load factor due to a vertical upgust increases when ;\n",
        "answer": "the gradient of the CL-alpha graph increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "altitude increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "wing loading increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "weight increases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 26 )\n Image 26\n The helix or advance angle of a rotating propeller blade element shown in the annex is ;\n",
        "answer": "angle 3.\n",
        "choiceone": "angle 1.\n",
        "choicetwo": "angle 2.\n",
        "choicethree": "not correctly indicated in the diagram.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 081-6272A )\n Annex 081-6272A\n The high lift device shown in the figure is a ;\n",
        "answer": "Krueger flap\n",
        "choiceone": "Slotted flap\n",
        "choicetwo": "Slot or slat\n",
        "choicethree": "Fowler flap\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 081-6271A )\n Annex 081-6271A\n The high lift device shown in the figure is a ;\n",
        "answer": "Slat\n",
        "choiceone": "Fowler flap\n",
        "choicetwo": "Krueger flap\n",
        "choicethree": "Slotted flap\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The increase in stall speed ( IAS ) with increasing altitude is due to ;\n",
        "answer": "compressibility effects.\n",
        "choiceone": "exceedance of Mcrit.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an increase in TAS.\n",
        "choicethree": "the larger angle of attack necessary in lower-density air to obtain the same lift as at sea level.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The induced angle of attack is ;\n",
        "answer": "the angle by which the relative airflow is deflected due to downwash.\n",
        "choiceone": "the angle by which the flow over the wing is deflected when landing flaps are set.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the angle between the local flow at the wing and the horizontal tail.\n",
        "choicethree": "caused by the fuselage and is greatest at the wing root.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The induced angle of attack is the result of ;\n",
        "answer": "downwash due to tip vortices.\n",
        "choiceone": "downwash due to flow separation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "change in direction of flow due to the effective angle of attack.\n",
        "choicethree": "a large local angle of attack in a two dimensional flow.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The induced drag ;\n",
        "answer": "increases as the lift coefficient increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "increases as the magnitude of the tip vortices decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "has no relation to the lift coefficient.\n",
        "choicethree": "increases as the aspect ratio increases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The induced drag coefficient , CDi is proportional with ;\n",
        "answer": "CL\u00b2\n",
        "choiceone": "CLmax\n",
        "choicetwo": "CL\n",
        "choicethree": "square root ( CL )\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The lift and drag forces , acting on a wing cross section ;\n",
        "answer": "depend on the pressure distribution about the wing cross section.\n",
        "choiceone": "vary linearly with the angle of attack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "are proportional to each other , independent of angle of attack.\n",
        "choicethree": "are normal to each other at just one angle of attack.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The lift coefficient ( CL ) of an aeroplane in steady horizontal flight is 0.35. An increase in angle of attack of 1 degree would\nincrease CL by 0.079. If a vertical gust instantly changes the angle of attack by 2 degrees, the load factor will be ;\n",
        "answer": "1.45\n",
        "choiceone": "0.45\n",
        "choicetwo": "0.9\n",
        "choicethree": "1.9\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The lift coefficient ( CL ) of an aeroplane in steady horizontal flight is 0.4. An increase in angle of attack of 1 degree will\nincrease CL by 0.09. A vertical up gust instantly changes the angle of attack by 5 degrees. The load factor will be ;\n",
        "answer": "2.13\n",
        "choiceone": "1.09\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.0\n",
        "choicethree": "3.18\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The lift coefficient ( CL ) of an aeroplane in steady horizontal flight is 0.42. An increase in angle of attack of 1 degree\nincreases CL by 0.1. A vertical up gust instantly changes the angle of attack by 3 degrees. The load factor will be ;\n",
        "answer": "1.71\n",
        "choiceone": "0.74\n",
        "choicetwo": "1.49\n",
        "choicethree": "2.49\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The lift coefficient Cl versus angle of attack curve of a negatively cambered aerofoil section intersects the horizontal axis of\nthe graph ;\n",
        "answer": "to the right of the origin.\n",
        "choiceone": "at the origin.\n",
        "choicetwo": "nowhere.\n",
        "choicethree": "to the left of the origin.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The lift coefficient Cl versus angle of attack curve of a negatively cambered aerofoil section intersects the vertical axis of the\ngraph ;\n",
        "answer": "below the origin.\n",
        "choiceone": "above the origin.\n",
        "choicetwo": "nowhere.\n",
        "choicethree": "at the origin.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The lift coefficient Cl versus angle of attack curve of a positively cambered aerofoil section intersects the horizontal axis of\nthe graph ;\n",
        "answer": "to the left of the origin.\n",
        "choiceone": "to the right of the origin.\n",
        "choicetwo": "nowhere.\n",
        "choicethree": "at the origin.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The lift coefficient Cl versus angle of attack curve of a symmetrical aerofoil section intersects the horizontal axis of the\ngraph ;\n",
        "answer": "at the origin.\n",
        "choiceone": "to the left of the origin.\n",
        "choicetwo": "to the right of the origin.\n",
        "choicethree": "nowhere.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The lift coefficient Cl versus angle of attack curve of a symmetrical aerofoil section intersects the vertical axis of the graph ;\n",
        "answer": "at the origin.\n",
        "choiceone": "below the origin.\n",
        "choicetwo": "above the origin.\n",
        "choicethree": "nowhere.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The lift force , acting on an aerofoil ; ( no flow separation )\n",
        "answer": "is mainly caused by suction on the upperside of the aerofoil.\n",
        "choiceone": "is maximum at an angle of attack of 2 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increases , proportional to the angle of attack until 40 degrees.\n",
        "choicethree": "is mainly caused by overpressure at the underside of the aerofoil.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The lift formula can be written as ; ( rho = density )\n",
        "answer": "L = CL * \u00bdrho * V2 * S.\n",
        "choiceone": "L = W.\n",
        "choicetwo": "L = CL * 2rho * V2 * S.\n",
        "choicethree": "L = n * W.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The lift formula is ;\n",
        "answer": "L = CL \u00bdRHO V\u00b2 S\n",
        "choiceone": "L=nW\n",
        "choicetwo": "L = CL 2RHO V\u00b2 S\n",
        "choicethree": "L=W\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The lift of an aeroplane of weight W in a constant linear climb with a climb angle ( gamma ) is approximately ;\n",
        "answer": "Wcos.gamma.\n",
        "choiceone": "W ( 1-sin.gamma ).\n",
        "choicetwo": "W ( 1-tan.gamma ).\n",
        "choicethree": "W / cos.gamma.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The lift to drag ratio determines the ;\n",
        "answer": "horizontal glide distance from a given altitude at zero wind and zero thrust.\n",
        "choiceone": "endurance speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "maximum rate of climb.\n",
        "choicethree": "horizontal distance in the climb up to a given altitude.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The load factor is greater than 1 ( one ) ;\n",
        "answer": "when lift is greater than weight.\n",
        "choiceone": "during a wings level stall before recovery.\n",
        "choicetwo": "in steady wings level horizontal flight.\n",
        "choicethree": "during a steady co-ordinated horizontal turn.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The location of the centre of pressure of a positive cambered wing at increasing angle of attack will ;\n",
        "answer": "shift forward.\n",
        "choiceone": "shift in spanwise direction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "not shift.\n",
        "choicethree": "shift aft.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The loss of total pressure in a shock wave is due to the fact that ;\n",
        "answer": "kinetic energy in the flow is converted into heat energy.\n",
        "choiceone": "the friction in the boundary layer is higher.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the speed reduction is too high.\n",
        "choicethree": "the static pressure decrease is comparatively high.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Mach number ;\n",
        "answer": "is the ratio between the TAS of the aeroplane and the local speed of sound.\n",
        "choiceone": "increases at a given TAS , when the temperature rises.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is the ratio between the TAS of the aeroplane and the speed of sound at sea level.\n",
        "choicethree": "is the ratio between the IAS of the aeroplane and the local speed of sound.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Mach number is the ratio between the ;\n",
        "answer": "TAS of the aeroplane and the speed of sound of the undisturbed flow.\n",
        "choiceone": "IAS of the aeroplane and the speed of sound of the undisturbed flow.\n",
        "choicetwo": "TAS of the aeroplane and the speed of sound at sea level.\n",
        "choicethree": "IAS of the aeroplane and the speed of sound at sea level.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Mach-trim function is installed on most commercial jets in order to minimize the adverse effects of ;\n",
        "answer": "changes in the position of centre of pressure\n",
        "choiceone": "compressibility effects on the stabilizer\n",
        "choicetwo": "uncontrolled changes in stabilizer setting\n",
        "choicethree": "increased drag due to shock wave formation\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Mach trim system will ;\n",
        "answer": "adjust the stabilizer , depending on the Mach Number.\n",
        "choiceone": "adjust the elevator trim tab , depending on the Mach Number.\n",
        "choicetwo": "keep the Mach Number automatically constant.\n",
        "choicethree": "pump the fuel from tank to tank , depending on the Mach Number.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Mach trim system will prevent ;\n",
        "answer": "tuck under.\n",
        "choiceone": "buffeting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "shock stall.\n",
        "choicethree": "dutch roll.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main function of a trailing edge flap is to ;\n",
        "answer": "increase the maximum lift coefficient of the wing.\n",
        "choiceone": "alter the position of the centre of gravity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "trim the aeroplane longitudinally.\n",
        "choicethree": "increase the angle of attack at which a wing will stall.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The main purpose of a boundary-layer fence on a swept wing is to ;\n",
        "answer": "improve the low speed handling characteristics.\n",
        "choiceone": "improve the lift coefficient of the trailing edge flaps.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase the critical Mach number.\n",
        "choicethree": "improve the high speed handling characteristics.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The manoeuvrability of an aeroplane is best when the ;\n",
        "answer": "CG is on the aft CG limit.\n",
        "choiceone": "flaps are down.\n",
        "choicetwo": "speed is low.\n",
        "choicethree": "CG position is on the forward CG limit.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The manoeuvre stability of a large jet transport aeroplane is 280 N/g. What stick force is required , if the aeroplane is pulled\nto the limit manoeuvring load factor from a trimmed horizontal straight and steady flight ? ( cruise configuration )\n",
        "answer": "420 N\n",
        "choiceone": "1050 N\n",
        "choicetwo": "770 N\n",
        "choicethree": "630 N\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The manoeuvring speed VA , expressed in indicated airspeed , of a transport aeroplane ;\n",
        "answer": "depends on aeroplane mass and pressure altitude.\n",
        "choiceone": "is a constant value.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is independent of aeroplane mass , but dependent on pressure altitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "depends on aeroplane mass and is independent of pressure altitude.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum acceptable cruising altitude is limited by a minimum acceptable load factor because exceeding that altitude ;\n",
        "answer": "turbulence may induce Mach buffet.\n",
        "choiceone": "a sudden necessary bank angle may exceed the limit load factor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "turbulence may exceed the limit load factor.\n",
        "choicethree": "Mach buffet will occur immediately.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum aft position of the centre of gravity is , amongst others , limited by the ;\n",
        "answer": "required minimum value of the stick force per g.\n",
        "choiceone": "inability to achieve maximum rotation rate during take-off.\n",
        "choicetwo": "maximum longitudinal stability of the aeroplane.\n",
        "choicethree": "maximum elevator deflection.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum ground distance during a glide with zero thrust decreases ;\n",
        "answer": "in a headwind at a constant aeroplane mass compared with zero wind.\n",
        "choiceone": "with an increase in aeroplane mass in zero wind.\n",
        "choicetwo": "in a tailwind at a constant aeroplane mass compared with zero wind.\n",
        "choicethree": "with a decrease in aeroplane mass in zero wind.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The maximum ground distance during a glide with zero thrust increases ;\n",
        "answer": "in a tailwind at a constant aeroplane mass compared with zero wind.\n",
        "choiceone": "with an increase in aeroplane mass in zero wind.\n",
        "choicetwo": "in a headwind at a constant aeroplane mass compared with zero wind.\n",
        "choicethree": "with a decrease in aeroplane mass in zero wind.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Mean Aerodynamic Chord ( MAC ) for a given wing of any planform is ;\n",
        "answer": "the chord of a rectangular wing with same moment and lift.\n",
        "choiceone": "the chord of a large rectangular wing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the wing area divided by the wing span.\n",
        "choicethree": "the average chord of the actual aeroplane.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The mean geometric chord of a wing is the ;\n",
        "answer": "wing area divided by the wing span.\n",
        "choiceone": "wing span squared divided by wing area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "aspect ratio multiplied by the taper ratio.\n",
        "choicethree": "wing area divide by mean aerodynamic chord.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most aft CG location may be limited by ;\n 1. insufficient stick force stability.\n 2. insufficient flare capability.\n 3. excessive in-flight manoeuvrability.\n 4. insufficient in-flight manoeuvrability.\n The combination that regroups all of the correct statements is ;\n",
        "answer": "1 , 3.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 , 4.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2 , 3.\n",
        "choicethree": "1 , 2 , 4.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most forward CG location may be limited by ;\n 1. insufficient flare capability.\n 2. excessive in-flight manoeuvrability.\n 3. insufficient in-flight manoeuvrability.\n The combination that regroups all of the correct statements is ;\n",
        "answer": "1 , 3.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 , 2.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.\n",
        "choicethree": "3.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most important factor determining the required position of the Trimmable Horizontal Stabiliser ( THS ) for take off\nis the ;\n",
        "answer": "position of the aeroplane\u2019s centre of gravity.\n",
        "choiceone": "total mass of the aeroplane.\n",
        "choicetwo": "stall speed.\n",
        "choicethree": "centre of gravity position of the fuel.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The most important problem of ice accretion on a transport aeroplane during flight is ;\n",
        "answer": "reduction in CLmax.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase in drag.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase in weight.\n",
        "choicethree": "blocking of control surfaces.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The movement of the aerodynamic centre of the wing when an aeroplane accelerates through the transonic range causes ;\n",
        "answer": "an increase in static longitudinal stability.\n",
        "choiceone": "an increase in static directional stability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a decrease in static directional stability.\n",
        "choicethree": "a decrease in static longitudinal stability.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The neutral point of an aeroplane is the point where ;\n",
        "answer": "the aeroplane becomes longitudinally unstable when the CG is moved beyond it in an aft direction.\n",
        "choiceone": "the boundary layer changes from laminar to turbulent.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the velocity of the relative airflow is reduced to zero.\n",
        "choicethree": "assuming no flow separation , the pitching moment coefficient does not change with varying angle of attack.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The parameters that can be read from the aeroplane parabolic polar curve are the ;\n",
        "answer": "minimum glide angle and the parasite drag coefficient.\n",
        "choiceone": "aspect ratio of the wing and the induced drag coefficient.\n",
        "choicetwo": "induced drag and the parasite drag.\n",
        "choicethree": "minimum rate of descent and the induced drag.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The pitch angle is defined as the angle between the ;\n",
        "answer": "longitudinal axis and the horizontal plane.\n",
        "choiceone": "longitudinal axis and the chord line.\n",
        "choicetwo": "speed vector axis and the longitudinal axis.\n",
        "choicethree": "chord line and the horizontal plane.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The pitch up effect of an aeroplane with swept wing in a stall is due to the ;\n",
        "answer": "wing tip stalling first.\n",
        "choiceone": "wing root stalling first.\n",
        "choicetwo": "aft movement of the centre of gravity.\n",
        "choicethree": "forward movement of the centre of gravity.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The pitch up tendency of an aeroplane with swept back wings during a stall is caused by the ;\n",
        "answer": "forward movement of the centre of pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "aft movement of the centre of gravity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "forward movement of the centre of gravity.\n",
        "choicethree": "aft movement of the centre of pressure.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 15 )\n Image 15\n The pitching moment versus angle of attack line in the diagram , which corresponds to a CG located at the neutral point of a\ngiven aeroplane at low and moderate angles of attack is ;\n",
        "answer": "line 2.\n",
        "choiceone": "line 4.\n",
        "choicetwo": "line 1.\n",
        "choicethree": "line 3.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 31 )\n Image 31\n The point in the annex showing zero lift is ;\n",
        "answer": "point a.\n",
        "choiceone": "point b.\n",
        "choicetwo": "point d.\n",
        "choicethree": "point c.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 19 )\n Image 19\n The point in the diagram corresponding to the minimum value of drag coefficient is ;\n",
        "answer": "point 1.\n",
        "choiceone": "point 3.\n",
        "choicetwo": "point 4.\n",
        "choicethree": "point 2.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 19 )\n Image 19\n The point in the diagram corresponding to the minimum value of drag is ;\n",
        "answer": "point 2.\n",
        "choiceone": "point 1.\n",
        "choicetwo": "point 3.\n",
        "choicethree": "point 4.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 19 )\n Image 19\n The point in the diagram giving the lowest speed in unaccelerated flight is ;\n",
        "answer": "point 4.\n",
        "choiceone": "point 1.\n",
        "choicetwo": "point 2.\n",
        "choicethree": "point 3.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 2 )\n Image 2\n The point in the figure corresponding to CL for minimum horizontal flight speed is ;\n",
        "answer": "Point d\n",
        "choiceone": "Point a\n",
        "choicetwo": "Point b\n",
        "choicethree": "Point c\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The point , where the aerodynamic lift acts on a wing is ;\n",
        "answer": "the centre of pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "the c.g. location.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the point of maximum thickness of the wing.\n",
        "choicethree": "the suction point of the wing.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The point , where the single resultant aerodynamic force acts on an aerofoil , is called ;\n",
        "answer": "centre of pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "aerodynamic centre.\n",
        "choicetwo": "neutral point.\n",
        "choicethree": "centre of gravity.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The polar curve of an aerofoil section is a graphic relationship between ;\n",
        "answer": "CL and CD.\n",
        "choiceone": "CD and angle of attack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "angle of attack and CL.\n",
        "choicethree": "TAS and stall speed.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The polar curve of an aerofoil section is a graphic relationship between ;\n",
        "answer": "lift coefficient Cl and drag coefficient Cd.\n",
        "choiceone": "drag coefficient Cd and angle of attack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "TAS and stall speed.\n",
        "choicethree": "angle of attack and lift coefficient Cl.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The position of the centre of pressure on an aerofoil of an aeroplane cruising at supersonic speed when compared with that at\nsubsonic speed is ;\n",
        "answer": "further aft.\n",
        "choiceone": "further forward.\n",
        "choicetwo": "undetermined since there is no defined centre of pressure location at supersonic speeds.\n",
        "choicethree": "identical.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The positive manoeuvring limit load factor for a large jet transport aeroplane with flaps extended is ;\n",
        "answer": "2.0\n",
        "choiceone": "2.5\n",
        "choicetwo": "1.5\n",
        "choicethree": "3.75\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The positive manoeuvring limit load factor for a light aeroplane in the utility category in the clean configuration is ;\n",
        "answer": "4.4\n",
        "choiceone": "6.0\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.5\n",
        "choicethree": "3.8\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The primary purpose of dihedral is to ;\n",
        "answer": "increase static lateral stability.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase static directional stability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase dynamic stability.\n",
        "choicethree": "decrease sensitivity to Dutch roll.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of a dorsal fin is to ;\n",
        "answer": "maintain static directional stability at large sideslip angles.\n",
        "choiceone": "provide pitch and yaw control.\n",
        "choicetwo": "stabilise forebody vortices.\n",
        "choicethree": "reduce tendency for spiral instability.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The purpose of correctly setting the leading and trailing edge devices on the wing of an aeroplane during take-off , approach\nand landing is to ;\n",
        "answer": "reduce stall speed , increase CLMAX with minimum increase in drag for take-off , but with a relatively high\n drag for approach and landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "reduce stall speed and drag during take-off and landing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase stall speed and CLMAX during take-off , but reduce stall speed with a relatively high drag during\n approach and landing.\n",
        "choicethree": "reduce the take-off roll and increase the landing roll.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The reference section of a propeller blade with radius R is usually taken at a distance from the propeller axis equal to ;\n",
        "answer": "0.75 R\n",
        "choiceone": "0.90 R\n",
        "choicetwo": "0.50 R\n",
        "choicethree": "0.25 R\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The regime of flight from the critical Mach number up to approximately M = 1.3 is called the ;\n",
        "answer": "transonic range.\n",
        "choiceone": "supersonic range.\n",
        "choicetwo": "subsonic range.\n",
        "choicethree": "hypersonic range.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The relationship between induced drag and the aspect ratio is ;\n",
        "answer": "a decrease in the aspect ratio increases the induced drag\n",
        "choiceone": "an increase in the aspect ratio increases the induced drag\n",
        "choicetwo": "induced drag = 1.3 aspect ratio value\n",
        "choicethree": "there is no relationship\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The relationship between the stall speed VS and VA ( EAS ) for a large transport aeroplane can be expressed in the following\nformula ; ( SQRT= square root )\n",
        "answer": "VA >= VS * SQRT (2.5)\n",
        "choiceone": "VA <= VS * SQRT (2.5)\n",
        "choicetwo": "VA > VS * SQRT (2.5)\n",
        "choicethree": "VA <= VS / SQRT (2.5)\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The relative thickness of an aerofoil is expressed in ;\n",
        "answer": "% chord.\n",
        "choiceone": "camber.\n",
        "choicetwo": "degrees cross section tail angle.\n",
        "choicethree": "meters.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The sensor of a stall warning system can be activated by a change in the location of the ;\n",
        "answer": "stagnation point.\n",
        "choiceone": "transition region.\n",
        "choicetwo": "centre of gravity.\n",
        "choicethree": "centre of lift.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 6 )\n Image 6\n The sequence which correctly represents blade twist at the given sections is ;\n",
        "answer": "Sequence 4\n",
        "choiceone": "Sequence 3\n",
        "choicetwo": "Sequence 1\n",
        "choicethree": "Sequence 2\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The shape of the gust load diagram is also determinated by the following three vertical speed in ft/s ( clean configuration ) ;\n",
        "answer": "25 , 50 , 66\n",
        "choiceone": "35 , 55 , 66\n",
        "choicetwo": "15 , 56 , 65\n",
        "choicethree": "22 , 55 , 75\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \u201cshort period mode\u201d is an ;\n",
        "answer": "oscillation about the lateral axis.\n",
        "choiceone": "oscillation about the longitudinal axis.\n",
        "choicetwo": "oscillation about the vertical axis.\n",
        "choicethree": "unstable movement of the aeroplane , induced by the pilot.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The SI unit of measurement for density is ;\n",
        "answer": "kg/m3.\n",
        "choiceone": "psi.\n",
        "choicetwo": "kg/cm2.\n",
        "choicethree": "bar.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The SI unit of measurement for pressure is ;\n",
        "answer": "N/m2.\n",
        "choiceone": "kg/m3.\n",
        "choicetwo": "bar/dm2.\n",
        "choicethree": "lb/gal.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The SI units of air density (I) and force (II) are ;\n",
        "answer": "(I) kg/m3 , (II) N.\n",
        "choiceone": "(I) kg/m\u00b2 , (II) kg.\n",
        "choicetwo": "(I) N/kg , (II) kg.\n",
        "choicethree": "(I) N/m3 , (II) N.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The significance of VA for jet transport aeroplanes is reduced at high cruising altitudes because ;\n",
        "answer": "buffet onset limitations normally become limiting.\n",
        "choiceone": "the engine has insufficient thrust to reach the limit load factor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the elevator deflection is limited to prevent exceeding the limit load factor.\n",
        "choicethree": "at high altitudes the bank angle is normally limited to 15\u00ba to prevent exceeding the limit load factor.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The sonic boom of an aeroplane flying at supersonic speed is created by ;\n",
        "answer": "shock waves around the aeroplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "aerodynamic heating.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the centre of pressure , which is moving aft on the aerofoil.\n",
        "choicethree": "the expansion flow behind the aeroplane.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The span-wise flow is caused by the difference between the air pressure on top and beneath the wing and its direction of\nmovement goes from ;\n",
        "answer": "beneath to the top of the wing via the wing tip\n",
        "choiceone": "the top to beneath the wing via the wing\u2019s trailing edge\n",
        "choicetwo": "beneath to the top of the wing via the trailing edge\n",
        "choicethree": "the top to beneath the wing via the leading edge\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The span-wise flow on an unswept wing is from the ;\n",
        "answer": "lower to the upper surface via the wing tip.\n",
        "choiceone": "upper surface via the trailing edge to the lower wing surface.\n",
        "choicetwo": "upper surface via the leading edge to the lower wing surface.\n",
        "choicethree": "lower surface via the trailing edge to the upper wing surface.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The speed for minimum glide angle occurs at an angle of attack that corresponds to ; ( assume zero thrust , ^ \u2026 denotes\npower of \u2026 )\n",
        "answer": "( CL/CD ) max\n",
        "choiceone": "( CL^3/CD^2 ) max\n",
        "choicetwo": "CLmax\n",
        "choicethree": "( CL/CD^2 ) max\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The speed of sound is affected by the ;\n",
        "answer": "temperature of the air.\n",
        "choiceone": "pressure of the air.\n",
        "choicetwo": "humidity of the air.\n",
        "choicethree": "density of the air.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The speed of sound is determined only by ;\n",
        "answer": "temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "humidity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "density.\n",
        "choicethree": "pressure.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The speed range between high and low speed buffet ;\n",
        "answer": "increases during a descent at a constant IAS.\n",
        "choiceone": "decreases during a descent at a constant Mach number.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is always positive at Mach numbers below MMO.\n",
        "choicethree": "increases during climb.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The speed range from approximately M=1.3 to approximately M=5 is called the ;\n",
        "answer": "supersonic range.\n",
        "choiceone": "transonic range.\n",
        "choicetwo": "hypersonic range.\n",
        "choicethree": "subsonic range.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The stall speed ;\n",
        "answer": "increases with an increased weight\n",
        "choiceone": "does not depend on weight\n",
        "choicetwo": "decreases with an increased weight\n",
        "choicethree": "increases with the length of the wingspan\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The stall speed decreases ; ( all other relevant factors are constant )\n",
        "answer": "when , during a manoeuvre , the aeroplane nose is suddenly pushed firmly downwards ( e.g. as in a push\n over ).\n",
        "choiceone": "when flaps are retracted.\n",
        "choicetwo": "in a horizontal turn.\n",
        "choicethree": "when the CG is moved forward.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The stall speed ( IAS ) will change according to the following factors ;\n",
        "answer": "May increase with altitude , especially high altitude , will increase during icing conditions and will increase\n when the cg moves forward.\n",
        "choiceone": "May increase when the cg moves forward , with higher altitude and due to the slipstream from a propeller on\n an engine located forward of the wing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Will increase with increased load factor , more flaps and increased bank angle in a turn.\n",
        "choicethree": "Will increase in a turn , higher temperature and will increase when the cg moves aft.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The stall speed in a 60\u00b0 banked turn increases by the following factor ;\n",
        "answer": "1.41\n",
        "choiceone": "2.00\n",
        "choicetwo": "1.07\n",
        "choicethree": "1.30\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The stall speed increases , when ; ( all other factors of importance being constant )\n",
        "answer": "pulling out of a dive.\n",
        "choiceone": "weight decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "spoilers are retracted.\n",
        "choicethree": "minor altitude changes occur e.g. 0-10.000 ft.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The stall speed line in the manoeuvring load diagram runs through a point where the ;\n",
        "answer": "speed = VS , load factor = +1.\n",
        "choiceone": "speed = VB , load factor = +1.\n",
        "choicetwo": "speed = 0 , load factor = +1.\n",
        "choicethree": "speed = VA , load factor = +1.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The stall speed line in the manoeuvring load diagram runs through a point where the ;\n",
        "answer": "speed = VA , load factor = limit load factor.\n",
        "choiceone": "speed = VB , load factor = gust load factor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "speed = VS , load factor = 0.\n",
        "choicethree": "speed = 0 , load factor = +1.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The stall speed lines in the manoeuvring load diagram originate from a point where the ;\n",
        "answer": "speed = 0 , load factor = 0.\n",
        "choiceone": "speed = VS , load factor = 0.\n",
        "choicetwo": "speed = 0 , load factor = +1.\n",
        "choicethree": "speed = VA , load factor = +1.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The stalling speed in IAS will change according to the following factors ;\n",
        "answer": "May increase during turbulence and will always increase when banking in a turn.\n",
        "choiceone": "Will increase during turn , increased mass and an aft cg location.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Will decrease with a forward cg location , lower altitude and due to the slip stream from a propeller on an\n engine located forward of the wing.\n",
        "choicethree": "Will increase with increased load factor , icing conditions and more flaps.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The stalling speed in IAS will change according to the following factors ;\n",
        "answer": "Increase during turn , increased mass and forward cg location.\n",
        "choiceone": "Decrease in a forward cg location , higher altitude and due to the slip stream from a propeller on an engine\n located forward of the wing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Increase with increased load factor , more flaps but will not increase due to the bank angle in a turn.\n",
        "choicethree": "Increase with increased load factor , icing conditions and an aft cg location.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The stick force per g of a heavy transport aeroplane is 300 N/g. What stick force is required , if the aeroplane in the clean\nconfiguration is pulled to the limit manoeuvring load factor from a trimmed horizontal straight and steady flight ?\n",
        "answer": "450 N.\n",
        "choiceone": "825 N.\n",
        "choicetwo": "750 N.\n",
        "choicethree": "1125 N.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The stick shaker stalling is taken from ;\n",
        "answer": "IAS.\n",
        "choiceone": "TAS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Ground Speed.\n",
        "choicethree": "Mach Number.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The subsonic speed range ;\n",
        "answer": "ends at Mcrit.\n",
        "choiceone": "ends at a Mach number just above M = 1.\n",
        "choicetwo": "ends at M = 1.\n",
        "choicethree": "implies both subsonic and supersonic speeds exist in the flow around the aeroplane.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ( subsonic ) static pressure ;\n",
        "answer": "decreases in a flow in a tube when the diameter decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "increases in a flow in a tube when the diameter decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is the total pressure plus the dynamic pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "is the pressure in a point at which the velocity has become zero.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 9 )\n Image 9\n The tab in the figure represents ;\n",
        "answer": "a servo tab.\n",
        "choiceone": "a balance tab.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a trim tab.\n",
        "choicethree": "an anti-balance tab.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 10 )\n Image 10\n The tab in the figure represents ;\n",
        "answer": "a balance tab that also functions as a trim.\n",
        "choiceone": "an anti-balance tab.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a control tab.\n",
        "choicethree": "a trim tab.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The tendency to Dutch roll increases when ;\n",
        "answer": "the static lateral stability increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "the centre of gravity moves forward.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the static directional stability increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "the anhedral increases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term angle of attack in a two dimensional flow is defined as ;\n",
        "answer": "the angle between the wing chord line and the direction of the relative wind/airflow.\n",
        "choiceone": "the angle formed by the longitudinal axis of the aeroplane and the chord line of the wing\n",
        "choicetwo": "the angle between the aeroplane climb path and the horizon.\n",
        "choicethree": "the angle for maximum lift/drag ratio\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The terms \u201cq\u201d and \u201cS\u201d in the lift formula are ;\n",
        "answer": "dynamic pressure and the area of the wing.\n",
        "choiceone": "static pressure and wing surface area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "static pressure and dynamic pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "square root of surface and wing loading.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The torque effect during the take off run in respect of a right hand propeller , when viewed from behind , will tend to ;\n",
        "answer": "roll the aeroplane to the left.\n",
        "choiceone": "pitch the aeroplane nose up.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pitch the aeroplane nose down.\n",
        "choicethree": "roll the aeroplane to the right.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The torque reaction of a rotating fixed pitch propeller will be greatest at ;\n",
        "answer": "low aeroplane speed and maximum engine power.\n",
        "choiceone": "low aeroplane speed and low engine power.\n",
        "choicetwo": "high aeroplane speed and maximum engine power.\n",
        "choicethree": "high aeroplane speed and low engine power.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The total drag of a three dimensional wing consists of ;\n",
        "answer": "induced drag and parasite drag.\n",
        "choiceone": "parasite drag and pressure drag.\n",
        "choicetwo": "pressure drag , friction drag and parasite drag.\n",
        "choicethree": "induced drag and interference drag.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The total drag of an aerofoil in two dimensional flow comprises ;\n",
        "answer": "pressure drag and skin friction drag.\n",
        "choiceone": "skin friction drag and induced drag.\n",
        "choicetwo": "interference drag and skin friction drag.\n",
        "choicethree": "induced drag and form drag.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The trailing edge flaps when extended ;\n",
        "answer": "degrade the best angle of glide\n",
        "choiceone": "increase the zero lift angle of attack\n",
        "choicetwo": "significantly increase the angle of attack for maximum lift\n",
        "choicethree": "significantly lower the drag\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The transition point is the point where ;\n",
        "answer": "the boundary layer changes from laminar to turbulent.\n",
        "choiceone": "the aeroplane becomes longitudinally unstable when the cg is moved beyond it in an aft direction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the velocity of the relative airflow is reduced to zero.\n",
        "choicethree": "changes in lift due to variations in angle of attack are constant.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The transition point is where the boundary layer changes from ;\n",
        "answer": "laminar into turbulent.\n",
        "choiceone": "turbulent into laminar.\n",
        "choicetwo": "attached flow into separated flow.\n",
        "choicethree": "separated flow into attached flow.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The true airspeed ( TAS ) is ;\n",
        "answer": "lower than the indicated airspeed ( IAS ) at ISA conditions and altitudes below sea level.\n",
        "choiceone": "equal to the IAS , multiplied by the air density at sea level.\n",
        "choicetwo": "higher than the speed of the undisturbed airstream about the aeroplane.\n",
        "choicethree": "lower than the speed of the undisturbed airstream about the aeroplane.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The type of stall that has the largest associated angle of attack is ;\n",
        "answer": "a deep stall.\n",
        "choiceone": "a shock stall.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a low speed stall.\n",
        "choicethree": "an accelerated stall.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The unit of density is ;\n",
        "answer": "kg/m\u00b3\n",
        "choiceone": "kg/cm\u00b2\n",
        "choicetwo": "bar\n",
        "choicethree": "psi\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The unit of measurement of pressure is ;\n",
        "answer": "psi\n",
        "choiceone": "kg/m\u00b3\n",
        "choicetwo": "lb/gal\n",
        "choicethree": "kg/dm\u00b2\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The units of wing loading (I) W/S and (II) dynamic pressure q are ;\n",
        "answer": "(I) N/m\u00b2 , (II) N/m\u00b2.\n",
        "choiceone": "(I) kg m , (II) N/m\u00b2.\n",
        "choicetwo": "(I) N/m3 , (II) kg/m\u00b2.\n",
        "choicethree": "(I) N/m , (II) kg.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The use of a slot in the leading edge of the wing enables the aeroplane to fly at a slower speed because ;\n",
        "answer": "it delays the stall to a higher angle of attack\n",
        "choiceone": "it changes the camber of the wing\n",
        "choicetwo": "the laminar part of the boundary layer gets thicker\n",
        "choicethree": "it decelerates the upper surface boundary layer air\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The value of the induced drag of an aeroplane in straight and level flight at constant mass varies linearly with ;\n",
        "answer": "1/V\u00b2\n",
        "choiceone": "1/V\n",
        "choicetwo": "V\u00b2\n",
        "choicethree": "V\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The value of the manoeuvre stability of an aeroplane is 150 N/g. The stick force required to achieve a load factor of 2.5 from\nsteady level flight is ;\n",
        "answer": "225 N.\n",
        "choiceone": "450 N.\n",
        "choicetwo": "375 N.\n",
        "choicethree": "150 N.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The value of the parasite drag in straight and level flight at constant weight varies linearly with the ;\n",
        "answer": "square of the speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "square of the angle of attack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "angle of attack.\n",
        "choicethree": "speed.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The vane of a stall warning system with a flapper switch is activated by the change of the ;\n",
        "answer": "stagnation point.\n",
        "choiceone": "centre of pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "point of lowest pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "centre of gravity.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 14 )\n Image 14\n The variation of propeller efficiency of a fixed pitch propeller with TAS at a given RPM is shown in ;\n",
        "answer": "figure 4.\n",
        "choiceone": "figure 3.\n",
        "choicetwo": "figure 2.\n",
        "choicethree": "figure 1.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 30 )\n Image 30\n The variation of propeller efficiency of a fixed pitch propeller with TAS at a given RPM is shown in ;\n",
        "answer": "figure 3.\n",
        "choiceone": "figure 1.\n",
        "choicetwo": "figure 4.\n",
        "choicethree": "figure 2.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The wing of an aeroplane will never stall at low subsonic speeds as long as ....\n",
        "answer": "the angle of attack is smaller than the value at which the stall occurs.\n",
        "choiceone": "the IAS exceeds the power-on stall speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there is a nose-down attitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "the CAS exceeds the power-on stall speed.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "To be able to predict compressibility effects you have to determine the ;\n",
        "answer": "Mach Number.\n",
        "choiceone": "EAS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "IAS.\n",
        "choicethree": "TAS.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "To increase the critical Mach number a conventional aerofoil should ;\n",
        "answer": "have a low thickness to chord ratio.\n",
        "choiceone": "have a large camber.\n",
        "choicetwo": "have a large leading edge radius.\n",
        "choicethree": "be used with a high angle of attack.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Total drag is the sum of ;\n",
        "answer": "parasite drag and induced drag.\n",
        "choiceone": "induced drag and friction drag.\n",
        "choicetwo": "friction drag and pressure drag.\n",
        "choicethree": "parasite drag , interference drag and pressure drag.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Total pressure is ; ( rho = density )\n",
        "answer": "static pressure plus dynamic pressure.\n",
        "choiceone": "static pressure minus dynamic pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "\u00bd rho V\u00b2.\n",
        "choicethree": "measured at a small hole in a surface , parallel to the local stream.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Trailing edge flap extension will ;\n",
        "answer": "decrease the critical angle of attack and increase the value of CLmax.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase the critical angle of attack and increase the value of CLmax.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase the critical angle of attack and decrease the value of CLmax.\n",
        "choicethree": "decrease the critical angle of attack and decrease the value of CLmax.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Trailing edge flaps once extended ;\n",
        "answer": "degrade the best angle of glide.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase the zero lift angle of attack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "significantly increase the angle of attack for maximum lift.\n",
        "choicethree": "signficantly lower the drag.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "True airspeed ( TAS ) is ;\n",
        "answer": "lower than the indicated airspeed ( IAS ) at altitudes below sea level , under ISA conditions.\n",
        "choiceone": "EAS corrected for compressibility.\n",
        "choicetwo": "higher than the indicated airspeed ( IAS ) at altitudes below sea level , under ISA conditions\n",
        "choicethree": "equal to the IAS , multiplied by the air density at sea level.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cTuck under\u201d is ;\n",
        "answer": "the tendency to nose down when speed is increased into the transonic flight regime.\n",
        "choiceone": "the tendency to nose down when the control column is pulled back.\n",
        "choicetwo": "shaking of the control column at high Mach Number.\n",
        "choicethree": "the tendency to nose up when speed is increased into the transonic flight regime.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cTuck under\u201d is caused by (i) which movement of the centre of pressure of the wing and (ii) which change of the downwash\nangle at the location of the stabilizer ;\n",
        "answer": "(i) aft , (ii) decreasing\n",
        "choiceone": "(i) aft , (ii) increasing\n",
        "choicetwo": "(i) forward , (ii) increasing\n",
        "choicethree": "(i) forward , (ii) decreasing\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cTuck under\u201d is the ;\n",
        "answer": "nose down pitching tendency as speed is increased in the transonic range.\n",
        "choiceone": "nose up pitching tendency as speed is increased in the transonic range.\n",
        "choicetwo": "shaking of the control column at high Mach number.\n",
        "choicethree": "nose down pitching tendency when the control column is pulled rearwards.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cTuck under\u201d may happen at ;\n",
        "answer": "high Mach numbers.\n",
        "choiceone": "all Mach numbers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "only at low altitudes.\n",
        "choicethree": "low Mach numbers.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Tuck under will happen ;\n",
        "answer": "only above the critical Mach number.\n",
        "choiceone": "only at the critical Mach number.\n",
        "choicetwo": "above or below the critical Mach number depending on the angle of attack.\n",
        "choicethree": "only below the critical Mach number.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Turning motion in a steady , level co-ordinated turn is created by ;\n",
        "answer": "the centripetal force.\n",
        "choiceone": "the centrifugal force.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the drag.\n",
        "choicethree": "the thrust.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two identical aeroplanes A and B , with the same mass , are flying steady level co-ordinated 20 degree bank turns. If the\nTAS of A is 130 kt and the TAS of B is 200 kt ;\n",
        "answer": "the lift coefficient of A is greater than that of B.\n",
        "choiceone": "the rate of turn of A is less than that of B.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the turn radius of A is greater than that of B.\n",
        "choicethree": "the load factor of A is greater than that of B.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two identical aeroplanes A and B , with the same mass , are flying steady level co-ordinated 20 degree bank turns. If the\nTAS of A is 130 kt and the TAS of B is 200 kt ;\n",
        "answer": "the turn radius of A is less than that of B.\n",
        "choiceone": "the lift coefficient of A is less than that of B.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the rate of turn of A is less than that of B.\n",
        "choicethree": "the load factor of A is greater than that of B.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two identical aeroplanes A and B , with the same mass , are flying steady level co-ordinated 20 degree bank turns. If the\nTAS of A is 130 kt and the TAS of B is 200 kt ;\n",
        "answer": "the load factor of A and B are the same.\n",
        "choiceone": "the lift coefficient of A is less than that of B.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the rate of turn of A is less than that of B.\n",
        "choicethree": "the turn radius of A is greater than that of B.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two identical aircraft A and B , with the same mass , are flying steady level co-ordinated 20 degree bank turns. If the TAS of\nA is 130 kt and that of B is 200 kt ;\n",
        "answer": "the rate of turn of A is greater than that of B.\n",
        "choiceone": "the lift coefficient of A is less than that of B.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the turn radius of A is greater than that of B.\n",
        "choicethree": "the load factor of A is greater than that of B.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two methods to increase the critical Mach Number are ;\n",
        "answer": "thin aerofoils and sweep back of the wing.\n",
        "choiceone": "thin aerofoils and dihedral of the wing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "positive cambering of the aerofoil and sweep back of the wing.\n",
        "choicethree": "thick aerofoils and dihedral of the wing.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Upon extension of a spoiler on a wing ;\n",
        "answer": "CD is increased and CL is decreased.\n",
        "choiceone": "only CL is decreased ( CD remains unaffected ).\n",
        "choicetwo": "both CL and CD are increased.\n",
        "choicethree": "CD is increased , while CL remains unaffected.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Upon extension of Fowler flaps whilst maintaining the same angle of attack ;\n",
        "answer": "CL and CD increase.\n",
        "choiceone": "CD decreases , while the centre of lift shifts aft.\n",
        "choicetwo": "CL increases , while CD remains unaffected.\n",
        "choicethree": "CL decreases , while the centre of lift shifts forward.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Upon wing spoiler extension in straight and level flight , if the speed and load factor remain constant ;\n",
        "answer": "CD increases but CL remains unaffected.\n",
        "choiceone": "CL decreases but CD remains unaffected.\n",
        "choicetwo": "both CL and CD increase.\n",
        "choicethree": "CD increases but CL decreases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Upon wing spoiler extension in straight and level flight , if the speed and load factor remain constant ;\n",
        "answer": "drag increases but lift remains unaffected.\n",
        "choiceone": "lift decreases but drag remains unaffected.\n",
        "choicetwo": "drag increases but lift decreases.\n",
        "choicethree": "both lift and drag increase.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Upward deflection of a trim tab in the longitudinal control results in ;\n",
        "answer": "the stick position stability remaining constant.\n",
        "choiceone": "increasing the stick position stability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increasing the stick force stability.\n",
        "choicethree": "the stick force stability remaining constant.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 5 ) ( Diagram de\u011fi\u015fecek )\n Image 5\n Use graphic at reference. A rotating propeller blade element produces an aerodynamic force F that may be resolved into two\ncomponents ; - a force T perpendicular to the plane of rotation ( thrust ). - a force R generating a torque absorbed by engine power.\nThe diagram representing a windmilling propeller is ;\n",
        "answer": "diagram 4.\n",
        "choiceone": "diagram 1.\n",
        "choicetwo": "diagram 3.\n",
        "choicethree": "diagram 2.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 4 )\n Image 4\n Use graphic at reference. The angle of attack of a rotating propeller blade element shown in the annex is ;\n",
        "answer": "angle 1.\n",
        "choiceone": "not correctly indicated in the diagram.\n",
        "choicetwo": "angle 3.\n",
        "choicethree": "angle 2.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 4 )\n Image 4\n Use graphic at reference. The blade angle of a rotating propeller blade element shown in the annex is ;\n",
        "answer": "angle 2.\n",
        "choiceone": "not correctly indicated in the diagram.\n",
        "choicetwo": "angle 1.\n",
        "choicethree": "angle 3.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "VA is ;\n",
        "answer": "the maximum speed at which maximum elevator deflection up is allowed.\n",
        "choiceone": "the speed at which a heavy transport aeroplane should fly in turbulence.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the maximum speed at which rolls are allowed.\n",
        "choicethree": "the speed that should not be exceeded in the climb.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "VLE is defined as the ;\n",
        "answer": "maximum landing gear extended speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "maximum flap extended speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "maximum speed at which the landing gear may be extended or retracted.\n",
        "choicethree": "maximum authorised speed.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "VMCA is certified with a bank angle of not more than 5\u00b0 towards the operating engine ( live engine low ) because ;\n",
        "answer": "although more bank reduces VMCA , too much bank may lead to fin stall.\n",
        "choiceone": "more than 5\u00ba bank ( live engine low ) would not reduce VMCA.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the slip indicator at 5\u00ba bank ( live engine low ) is centred.\n",
        "choicethree": "at 5\u00ba bank ( live engine low ) , sideslip is zero.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "VMCA is the minimum speed at which directional control can be maintained when , amongst others ;\n 1. maximum take-off thrust was set and is maintained on the remaining engines.\n 2. a sudden engine failure occurs on the most critical engine.\n 3. flaps are in any position.\n 4. the gear is either up or down.\n 5. the aeroplane is either in or out of ground effect.\n The combination that regroups all of the correct statements is ;\n",
        "answer": "1 and 2 are correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 , 3 and 5 are correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 , 2 and 4 are correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "3 , 4 and 5 are correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "VMCL is the ;\n",
        "answer": "minimum control speed approach and landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "minimum speed during landing with all engines operating.\n",
        "choicetwo": "maximum speed in the landing configuration.\n",
        "choicethree": "minimum control speed - with landing gear down , flaps up and all engines operating.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "VMO ;\n",
        "answer": "should be not greater than VC.\n",
        "choiceone": "should not be less than VD.\n",
        "choicetwo": "should be chosen in between VC and VD.\n",
        "choicethree": "is equal to the design speed for maximum gust intensity.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vortex generators ;\n",
        "answer": "transfer energy from the free airflow into the boundary layer.\n",
        "choiceone": "reduce the spanwise flow on swept wing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "change the turbulent boundary layer into a laminar boundary layer.\n",
        "choicethree": "take kinetic energy out of the boundary layer to reduce separation.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vortex generators mounted on the upper wing surface will ;\n",
        "answer": "decrease the shock wave induced separation.\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease the interference drag of the trailing edge flaps.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decrease the stalling speed by increasing spanwise flow on the wing.\n",
        "choicethree": "increase the effectiveness of the spoiler due to increase in parasite drag.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vortex generators on the upper side of the wing ;\n",
        "answer": "decrease wave drag.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase wave drag.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase critical Mach Number.\n",
        "choicethree": "decrease critical Mach Number.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vortex generators on the upper side of the wing surface will ;\n",
        "answer": "decrease the intensity of shock wave induced air separation.\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease the span wise flow at high Mach Numbers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase the critical Mach Number.\n",
        "choicethree": "increase the magnitude of the shock wave.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vortex generators on the upper side of the wing surface will ;\n",
        "answer": "decrease shock wave induced flow separation.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase the critical Mach Number.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase the magnitude of the shock wave.\n",
        "choicethree": "decrease the span wise flow at high Mach Numbers.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "VRA is ;\n",
        "answer": "the recommended turbulence penetration airspeed.\n",
        "choiceone": "a sped just below Mach buffet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "tha stall speed in turbulent conditions.\n",
        "choicethree": "a speed just above low speed buffet.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the primary roll controls on a conventional aeroplane ?\n",
        "answer": "The ailerons.\n",
        "choiceone": "The rudder.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Asymmetrically extended leading edge flaps.\n",
        "choicethree": "Symmetrically deflected spoilers.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What can happen to the aeroplane structure flying at a speed just exceeding VA ?\n",
        "answer": "It may suffer permanent deformation if the elevator is fully deflected upwards.\n",
        "choiceone": "It may suffer permanent deformation because the flight is performed at too large dynamic pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It will collapse if a turn is made.\n",
        "choicethree": "It may break if the elevator is fully deflected upwards.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What data may be obtained from the Buffet Onset Boundary chart ?\n",
        "answer": "The values of the Mach Number at which low speed and Mach Buffet occur at different weights and\n altitudes.\n",
        "choiceone": "The values of MMO at different weights and altitudes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The values of Mcrit at different weights and altitudes.\n",
        "choicethree": "The values of the Mach Number at which low speed and shock-stall occur at different weights and altitudes.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What decreases the maximum ground distance during a glide with zero thrust ?\n",
        "answer": "A headwind with constant aeroplane mass.\n",
        "choiceone": "A decrease in aeroplane mass with zero wind.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A tailwind with constant aeroplane mass.\n",
        "choicethree": "An increase in aeoplane mass with zero wind.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What factors determine the distance travelled over the ground of an aeroplane in a glide ?\n",
        "answer": "The wind and the lift/drag ratio , which changes with angle of attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "The wind and weight together with power loading , which is the ratio of power output to the weight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The wind and CLmax.\n",
        "choicethree": "The wind and the aeroplane\u2019s mass.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What increases the critical angle of attack ? Use of ;\n",
        "answer": "slats.\n",
        "choiceone": "fuselage mounted speed-brakes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "spoilers.\n",
        "choicethree": "flaps.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What increases the stalling angle of attack ? Use of ;\n",
        "answer": "slats.\n",
        "choiceone": "flaps.\n",
        "choicetwo": "fuselage mounted speed-brakes.\n",
        "choicethree": "spoilers.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the approximate diameter of a steady , level , co-ordinated turn with a bank angle of 30 degrees and a speed ( TAS )\nof 500 kt ?\n",
        "answer": "23 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 km.\n",
        "choicetwo": "17 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "13 km.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the approximate radius of a steady horizontal co-ordinated turn at a bank angle of 45\u00b0 and a TAS of 200 kt ?\n",
        "answer": "1 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "1.5 km.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "2 km.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the approximate radius of a steady , level , co-ordinated turn with a bank angle of 30 degrees and a TAS of 500 kt ?\n",
        "answer": "12 km.\n",
        "choiceone": "7 km.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 km.\n",
        "choicethree": "24 km.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the approximate value of the lift of an aeroplane at a gross weight of 50 000 N , in a horizontal coordinated 45\ndegrees banked turn ?\n",
        "answer": "70 000 N\n",
        "choiceone": "80 000 N\n",
        "choicetwo": "50 000 N\n",
        "choicethree": "60 000 N\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the correct relationship between the true airspeed for (i) minimum sink rate and (ii) minimum glide angle , at a given\naltitude ?\n",
        "answer": "(i) is less than (ii)\n",
        "choiceone": "(i) can be greater than or less than (ii) depending on the type of aeroplane\n",
        "choicetwo": "(i) is equal to (ii)\n",
        "choicethree": "(i) is greater than (ii)\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the effect of aeroplane mass on shock wave intensity at constant Mach number ?\n",
        "answer": "Increasing mass increases shock wave intensity.\n",
        "choiceone": "Decreasing mass increases shock wave intensity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A change in mass does not influence shock wave intensity.\n",
        "choicethree": "Decreasing mass increases shock wave intensity at below standard temperatures.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the effect of an aft shift of the centre of gravity on (1) static longitudinal stability and (2) the required control\ndeflection for a given pitch change ?\n",
        "answer": "(1) reduces , (2) reduces\n",
        "choiceone": "(1) increases , (2) increases\n",
        "choicetwo": "(1) increases , (2) reduces\n",
        "choicethree": "(1) reduces , (2) increases\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the effect of elevator trim tab adjustment on the static longitudinal stability of an aeroplane ?\n",
        "answer": "No effect.\n",
        "choiceone": "Depends on the value of stick force/g.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aeroplane nose up trim increases the static longitudinal stability.\n",
        "choicethree": "Aeroplane nose down trim increases the static longitudinal stability.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the effect of exceeding Mcrit on the stick force stability of an aeroplane with swept-back wings without any form of\nstability augmentation ?\n",
        "answer": "A decrease , due to loss of lift in the wing root area.\n",
        "choiceone": "An increase , due to shock wave formation in the wing root area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No effect , because Mcrit is not relevant when considering stick force stability.\n",
        "choicethree": "No effect , because stick force stability is independent of Mach number.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the effect of high aspect ratio of an aeroplane\u2019s wing on induced drag ?\n",
        "answer": "It is reduced because the effect of wing-tip vortices is reduced.\n",
        "choiceone": "It is increased because high aspect ratio has greater frontal area.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It is increased because high aspect ratio produces greater downwash.\n",
        "choicethree": "It is unaffected because there is no relation between aspect ratio and induced drag.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the effect of winglets on the drag of the wing ?\n",
        "answer": "Increase parasite drag , decrease induced drag.\n",
        "choiceone": "Increase friction drag , decrease form drag.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Increase induced drag , decrease friction drag.\n",
        "choicethree": "Increase induced drag , decrease interference drag.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the effect on an aeroplane\u2019s characteristics of extending Fowler flaps to their fully extended position ?\n",
        "answer": "wing area and camber increase.\n",
        "choiceone": "CD remains constant for a given angle of attack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "CLMAX occurs at a higher angle of attack.\n",
        "choicethree": "wing area remains constant but camber increases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the effect on induced drag of an increase in aspect ratio ?\n",
        "answer": "Induced drag decreases , because the effect of tip vortices decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "Induced drag decreases , because a larger aspect ratio causes more downwash.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Induced drag increases , because a larger aspect ratio increases the frontal area.\n",
        "choicethree": "Induced drag increases , because the effect of tip vortices increases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the effect on induced drag of mass and speed changes ? ( all other factors of importance remaining constant )\n",
        "answer": "Decreases with increasing speed and decreasing mass.\n",
        "choiceone": "Increases with increasing speed and decreasing mass.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Decreases with decreasing speed and decreasing mass.\n",
        "choicethree": "Increases with increasing speed and increasing mass.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the effect on landing speed when a trimmable horizontal stabiliser jams at high IAS ?\n",
        "answer": "In most cases , a higher than normal landing speed is required.\n",
        "choiceone": "No effect with a forward CG.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No effect when landing on a high elevation runway.\n",
        "choicethree": "In most cases , no effect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the fundamental difference between a trim tab and a servo tab ?\n",
        "answer": "The purpose of a trim tab is to reduce continuous stick force to zero , a servo tab only reduces stick force.\n",
        "choiceone": "The functioning of a trim tab is based on aerodynamic balancing , whereas a servo tab is usually adjusted via\n a screwjack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A servo tab affects the stick force stability , whereas a trim tab does not.\n",
        "choicethree": "A trim tab is automatically adjusted when its particular control surface moves , whereas a servo tab is moved\n independently of its particular control surface.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the heading change after 10 seconds of an aeroplane performing a rate one turn ?\n",
        "answer": "30 degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "90 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "10 degrees.\n",
        "choicethree": "180 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the highest speed possible without supersonic flow over the wing ?\n",
        "answer": "Critical Mach number.\n",
        "choiceone": "Initial Mach buffet speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Tuck under speed.\n",
        "choicethree": "M = 1.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the influence of decreasing aeroplane weight on Mcrit at constant IAS ?\n",
        "answer": "Mcrit increases as a result of flying at a smaller angle of attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "Mcrit increases as a result of compressibility effects.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Mcrit decreases.\n",
        "choicethree": "Mcrit decreases as a result of flying at a greater angle of attack.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the limit load factor of a large transport aeroplane in the manoeuvring diagram ?\n",
        "answer": "2.5\n",
        "choiceone": "3.75\n",
        "choicetwo": "6\n",
        "choicethree": "1.5\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the most effective flap system ?\n",
        "answer": "Fowler flap.\n",
        "choiceone": "Plain flap.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Single slotted flap.\n",
        "choicethree": "Split flap.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the position of the elevator in relation to the trimmable horizontal stabiliser of a power assisted aeroplane that is in\ntrim ?\n",
        "answer": "The position depends on speed , the position of slats and flaps and the position of the centre of gravity.\n",
        "choiceone": "The elevator deflection ( compared to the stabilizer position ) is always zero.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At a forward CG the elevator is deflected upward and at an aft CG the elevator is deflected downward.\n",
        "choicethree": "The elevator is always deflected slightly downwards in order to have sufficient remaining flare capability.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the position of the elevator in relation to the trimmable horizontal stabiliser of an aeroplane with fully hydraulically\noperated flight controls that is in trim ?\n",
        "answer": "Elevator deflection is zero.\n",
        "choiceone": "At a forward CG , the elevator is deflected upward and at an aft CG , it is deflected downward.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The position depends on speed , the position of flaps and slats and the position of the centre of gravity.\n",
        "choicethree": "The elevator is always deflected slightly downwards in order to have sufficient remaining flare capability.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the primary input for an artificial feel system ?\n",
        "answer": "IAS.\n",
        "choiceone": "TAS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Mach number.\n",
        "choicethree": "Static pressure.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of an auto-slat system ?\n",
        "answer": "extend automatically when a certain value of angle of attack is exceeded.\n",
        "choiceone": "assist the ailerons during rolling.\n",
        "choicetwo": "provide automatically slat IN selection after take-off.\n",
        "choicethree": "ensures that the slats are always extended when the ground/flight system is in the \u201cground\u201d position.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the recommended action following failure of the yaw damper(s) of a jet aeroplane , flying at normal cruise altitude\nand speed prior to encountering Dutch roll problems ?\n",
        "answer": "Reduce altitude and Mach number.\n",
        "choiceone": "Manually recover any subsequent Dutch roll motion using rudder.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Increase Mach number to improve aerodynamic damping of any subsequent Dutch roll motion.\n",
        "choicethree": "No action is required.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the relation between the mach angle ( mu ) and the corresponding mach number ?\n",
        "answer": "sin mu = 1/M\n",
        "choiceone": "sin mu = M\n",
        "choicetwo": "sin2 mu = 1/M\n",
        "choicethree": "tan mu = 1/M\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the SI unit of measurement for power ?\n",
        "answer": "Nm/s.\n",
        "choiceone": "N/m.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pa/m2.\n",
        "choicethree": "kgm/s2.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the significance of the maximum allowed cruising altitude , based on the 1.3 g margin ? At this altitude ;\n",
        "answer": "a manoeuvre with a load factor of 1.3 will cause buffet onset.\n",
        "choiceone": "a manoeuvre with a load factor of 1.3 will cause a Mach number at which accelerated low speed stall occurs.\n",
        "choicetwo": "a manoeuvre with a load factor of 1.3 will cause Mcrit to be exceeded.\n",
        "choicethree": "exceeding a load factor of 1.3 will cause permanent deformation of this aeroplane.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the stagnation point ?\n",
        "answer": "The point where the velocity of the relative airflow is reduced to zero.\n",
        "choiceone": "The intersection of the total aerodynamic foce and the chord line.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The intersection of the thrust vector and the chord line.\n",
        "choicethree": "The point , relative to which the sumtotal of all moments is independent of angle of attack.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the unit of measurement for power ?\n",
        "answer": "Nm/s\n",
        "choiceone": "kgm/s\u00b2\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pa/m\u00b2\n",
        "choicethree": "N/m\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the value of the Mach number if the Mach angle equals 45\u00b0 ?\n",
        "answer": "1.4\n",
        "choiceone": "2.0\n",
        "choicetwo": "1.2\n",
        "choicethree": "0.7\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 13 )\n Image 13\n What kind of horizontal control surface is shown in the figure ?\n",
        "answer": "All-flying tail.\n",
        "choiceone": "Frise type control.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Canard.\n",
        "choicethree": "Elevator.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What may happen if the \u201cultimate load factor\u201d is exceeded ?\n",
        "answer": "Structural failure.\n",
        "choiceone": "Elastic or temporary deformation only.\n",
        "choicetwo": "No structural failure , only plastic or permanent deformation.\n",
        "choicethree": "Flutter.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What should be usually done to perform a landing with the stabilizer jammed in the cruise flight position ?\n",
        "answer": "choose a higher landing speed than normal and/or use a lower flap setting for landing.\n",
        "choiceone": "if possible , relocate as many passengers as possible to the front of the cabin.\n",
        "choicetwo": "choose a lower landing speed than normal.\n",
        "choicethree": "use the Mach trimmer until after landing.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will happen if a large transport aeroplane slowly decelerates in level flight from its cruise speed in still air at high\naltitude ?\n",
        "answer": "Stick shaker activation or low speed buffeting.\n",
        "choiceone": "CLMAX will increase due to shock stall.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An accelerated stall.\n",
        "choicethree": "High speed buffet.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will happen in ground effect ?\n",
        "answer": "The induced angle of attack and induced drag decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "The thrust required will increase significantly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The wing downwash on the tail surfaces increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "The wing tip vortices increase in strength.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will increase the sensitivity to Dutch Roll ?\n",
        "answer": "An increased static lateral stability.\n",
        "choiceone": "An increased static directional stability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An increased anhedral.\n",
        "choicethree": "A forward movement of the centre of gravity.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What wing shape or wing characteristic is the least sensitive to turbulence ;\n",
        "answer": "swept wings.\n",
        "choiceone": "wing dihedral.\n",
        "choicetwo": "straight wings.\n",
        "choicethree": "elliptical wing.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a jet transport aeroplane takes off with the CG at the aft limit and the trimmable horizontal stabiliser ( THS ) is\npositioned at the maximum allowable nose down position for take-off ;\n",
        "answer": "rotation will be normal using the normal rotation technique.\n",
        "choiceone": "there will be a tendency to under-rotate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "rotation will require higher than normal stick force.\n",
        "choicethree": "early nose wheel raising will take place.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a jet transport aeroplane takes off with the CG at the aft limit and the trimmable horizontal stabiliser ( THS ) is\npositioned at the maximum allowable nose up position for take-off ;\n",
        "answer": "early nose wheel raising will take place.\n",
        "choiceone": "rotation will require higher than normal stick force.\n",
        "choicetwo": "rotation will be normal using the normal rotation technique.\n",
        "choicethree": "there will be a tendency to under-rotate.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a jet transport aeroplane takes off with the CG at the forward limit and the trimmable horizontal stabiliser ( THS ) is\npositioned at the maximum allowable nose down position for take-off ;\n",
        "answer": "rotation will require a higher than normal stick force.\n",
        "choiceone": "early nose wheel raising will take place.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there will be a tendency to over-rotate.\n",
        "choicethree": "rotation will be normal using the normal rotation technique.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a jet transport aeroplane takes off with the CG at the forward limit and the trimmable horizontal stabiliser ( THS ) is\npositioned at the maximum allowable nose up position for take-off ;\n",
        "answer": "rotation will be normal using the normal rotation technique.\n",
        "choiceone": "rotation will require a higher than normal stick force.\n",
        "choicetwo": "there will be a tendency to over-rotate.\n",
        "choicethree": "early nose wheel raising will take place.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a pilot makes a turn in horizontal flight , the stall speed ;\n",
        "answer": "increases with the square root of load factor\n",
        "choiceone": "increases with the load factor squared\n",
        "choicetwo": "increases with flap extension\n",
        "choicethree": "decreases with increasing bank angle\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a strongly swept back wing stalls and the wake of the wing contacts the horizontal tail , the effect on the stall\nbehaviour can be a(n) ;\n",
        "answer": "nose up tendency and/or lack of elevator response.\n",
        "choiceone": "tendency to increase speed after initial stall.\n",
        "choicetwo": "nose down tendency.\n",
        "choicethree": "increase in sensitivity of elevator inputs.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a turn is initiated , adverse yaw is ;\n",
        "answer": "the tendency of an aeroplane to yaw in the opposite direction of turn mainly due to the difference in induced\n drag on each wing.\n",
        "choiceone": "the tendency of an aeroplane to yaw in the opposite direction of turn mainly due to the difference in aileron\n form drag.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the tendency of an aeroplane to yaw in the same direction of turn due to the different wing speeds.\n",
        "choicethree": "a momentary yawing motion opposite to the turn due to an incorrect differential aileron movement.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When a wing spoiler is extended at constant angle of attack ;\n",
        "answer": "drag increases but lift decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "drag increases but lift remains constant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "both drag and lift increase.\n",
        "choicethree": "both drag and lift decrease.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When air has passed an expansion wave , the static pressure is ;\n",
        "answer": "decreased.\n",
        "choiceone": "increased.\n",
        "choicetwo": "unchanged.\n",
        "choicethree": "decreased or increased , depending on Mach Number.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When air has passed through a shock wave the local speed of sound is ;\n",
        "answer": "increased.\n",
        "choiceone": "not affected\n",
        "choicetwo": "decreased.\n",
        "choicethree": "decreased and beyond a certain Mach number start increasing again\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When altitude increases , the stall speed ( IAS ) will ;\n",
        "answer": "increase due to increasing compressibility effects as a result of increasing Mach number.\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease due to decreasing temperature and decreasing Mach number.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decrease due to increasing Mcrit.\n",
        "choicethree": "increase due to decreasing Mcrit.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aerofoil section has accelerated from subsonic to supersonic speeds , its aerodynamic centre will have ;\n",
        "answer": "shifted from approximately 25% to about 50% of the chord.\n",
        "choiceone": "shifted slightly forward.\n",
        "choicetwo": "shifted aft by about 10%.\n",
        "choicethree": "not moved.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aeroplane enters ground effect ;\n",
        "answer": "the lift is increased and the drag is decreased.\n",
        "choiceone": "drag an lift are reduced.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the effective angle of attack is decreased.\n",
        "choicethree": "the induced angle of attack is increased.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aeroplane has zero static longitudinal stability , the Cm versus angle of attack line ;\n",
        "answer": "is horizontal.\n",
        "choiceone": "has a positive slope.\n",
        "choicetwo": "has a negative slope.\n",
        "choicethree": "is vertical.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aeroplane is flying at an airspeed which is 1.3 times its basic stalling speed , the coefficient of lift as a percentage of\nthe maximum lift coefficient ( CLmax ) would be ;\n",
        "answer": "59%.\n",
        "choiceone": "169%.\n",
        "choicetwo": "130%.\n",
        "choicethree": "77%.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aeroplane performs a straight steady climb with a 20% climb gradient , the load factor is equal to ;\n",
        "answer": "0.98.\n",
        "choiceone": "1.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1.02.\n",
        "choicethree": "0.83.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When an aeroplane with the centre of gravity forward of the centre of pressure of the combined wing / fuselage is in straight\nand level flight , the vertical load on the tailplane will be ;\n",
        "answer": "downwards.\n",
        "choiceone": "upwards.\n",
        "choicetwo": "downwards because it is always negative regardless of the position of the centre of gravity.\n",
        "choicethree": "zero because in steady flight all loads are in equilibrium.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When are outboard ailerons ( if present ) de-activated ?\n",
        "answer": "Flaps ( and slats ) retracted or speed above a certain value.\n",
        "choiceone": "Landing gear retracted.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flaps ( and/or slats ) extended or speed below a certain value.\n",
        "choicethree": "Landing gear extended.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When comparing a rectangular wing and a swept back wing of the same wing area and wing loading , ( assume all other\nfactors of imprtance remain constant ) , the swept back wing has the advantage of ;\n",
        "answer": "higher critical Mach number\n",
        "choiceone": "increased longitudinal stability\n",
        "choicetwo": "greater strength\n",
        "choicethree": "lower stalling speed\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When comparing a stabiliser trim system with an elevator trim system , which of these statements is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "a stabiliser trim is able to compensate larger changes in pitching moments.\n",
        "choiceone": "a stabiliser trim is more sensitive to flutter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an elevator trim is more suitable for aeroplanes with a large CG range.\n",
        "choicethree": "an elevator trim is able to compensate larger changes in pitching moments.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When comparing a stabiliser trim system with an elevator trim system , which of these statements is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "an elevator trim is less suitable for aeroplanes with a large CG range.\n",
        "choiceone": "a stabiliser trim is more sensitive to flutter.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an elevator trim is more suitable for aeroplanes with a large CG range.\n",
        "choicethree": "an elevator trim is able to compensate larger changes in pitching moments.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When comparing an elevator trim system with a stabiliser trim system , which of these statements is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "an elevator trim is more sensitive to flutter.\n",
        "choiceone": "an elevator trim is able to compensate larger changes in pitching moments.\n",
        "choicetwo": "an elevator trim is more suitable for aeroplanes with a large CG range.\n",
        "choicethree": "an elevator trim produces lower trim drag.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When considering a swept-back wing , without corrective design features , at the stall ;\n",
        "answer": "tip stall will occur first , which produces a nose-up pitching moment.\n",
        "choiceone": "wing root stall will occur first , which produces a rolling moment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "tip stall will occur first , which produces a nose-down pitching moment.\n",
        "choicethree": "leading edge stall will occur first , which produces a nose-down pitching moment.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When flaps are deployed at constant angle of attack the lift coefficient will ;\n",
        "answer": "increase.\n",
        "choiceone": "vary as the square of IAS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "remain the same.\n",
        "choicethree": "decrease.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When flaps are extended in a straight and level flight at constant IAS , the lift coefficient will eventually ;\n",
        "answer": "remain the same.\n",
        "choiceone": "increase.\n",
        "choicetwo": "first increase and then decrease.\n",
        "choicethree": "decrease.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When flutter damping of control surfaces is obtained by mass balancing , these weights will be located with respect to the\nhinge of the control surface ;\n",
        "answer": "in front of the hinge.\n",
        "choiceone": "above the hinge.\n",
        "choicetwo": "below the hinge.\n",
        "choicethree": "behind the hinge.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When Fowler type trailing edge flaps are extended at a constant angle of attack , the following changes will occur ;\n",
        "answer": "CL and CD increase.\n",
        "choiceone": "CL increases and the centre of pressure moves forward.\n",
        "choicetwo": "CD decreases and the centre of pressure moves aft.\n",
        "choicethree": "CL increases and CD remains constant.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is a turn co-ordinated ?\n",
        "answer": "When the longitudinal axis of the aeroplane at the CG is tangential to the flight path.\n",
        "choiceone": "If no rudder deflection is required during the turn.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When only minor elevator pull force is required.\n",
        "choicethree": "If no aileron deflection is required during the turn.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When moving the centre of gravity forward the stick force per g will ;\n",
        "answer": "increase.\n",
        "choiceone": "change but only at very high speeds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decrease.\n",
        "choicethree": "not change.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When power assisted controls are used for pitch control ;\n",
        "answer": "a part of the aerodynamic forces is still felt on the column.\n",
        "choiceone": "aerodynamic balancing of the control surfaces is meaningless.\n",
        "choicetwo": "they only function in combination with an elevator trim tab.\n",
        "choicethree": "trimming is superfluous.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When roll spoilers are extended , the part of the wing on which they are mounted ;\n",
        "answer": "experiences a reduction in lift , which generates the desired rolling moment. In addition there is a local\n increase in drag , which suppresses adverse yaw.\n",
        "choiceone": "experiences extra drag , which generates a yawing moment. The speed difference between both wings\n generates the desired rolling moment.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is forced downwards as a reaction to the increased drag.\n",
        "choicethree": "stalls. This causes a diference in lift between both wins , which generates the desired rolling moment.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When shock stall occurs , lift will decrease because ;\n",
        "answer": "flow separation occurs behind the shock wave.\n",
        "choiceone": "of the existence of a shock wave being located at the trailing edge of the wing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Mcrit reached.\n",
        "choicethree": "the bow wave appears.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When speed is increased in straight and level flight on a positively cambered aerofoil , what happens to the ;\n 1. centre of pressure and\n 2. the magnitude of the total lift force ?\n",
        "answer": "1 moves aft and 2 remains constant.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 moves forward and 2 remains constant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 moves aft and 2 increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "1 moves forward and 2 decreases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When \u201cspoilers\u201d are used as speed brakes ;\n",
        "answer": "at same angle of attack , CD is increased and CL is decreased.\n",
        "choiceone": "at same angle of attack , CL remains unaffected.\n",
        "choicetwo": "CLmax of the polar curve is not affected.\n",
        "choicethree": "they do not affect wheel braking action during landing.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When supersonic airflow passes through an oblique shock wave , how do (1) static pressure , (2) density , and (3) local speed\nof sound change ?\n",
        "answer": "(1) increases , (2) increases , (3) increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "(1) increases , (2) increases , (3) decreases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "(1) remains constant , (2) decreases , (3) increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "(1) decreases , (2) decreases , (3) decreases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the air has passed through a normal shock wave the Mach number is ;\n",
        "answer": "less than 1.\n",
        "choiceone": "higher than before.\n",
        "choicetwo": "equal to 1.\n",
        "choicethree": "lower than before but still greater than 1.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the air is passing through a shock wave the density will ;\n",
        "answer": "increase.\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "stay constant.\n",
        "choicethree": "decrease and beyond a certain Mach number start increasing again\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the air is passing through a shock wave the static temperature will ;\n",
        "answer": "increase.\n",
        "choiceone": "stay constant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decrease.\n",
        "choicethree": "decrease and beyond a certain Mach number start increasing again.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the air is passing through an expansion wave the local speed of sound will ;\n",
        "answer": "decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "stay constant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase.\n",
        "choicethree": "decrease and beyond a certain Mach number start increasing again.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the air is passing through an expansion wave the Mach number will ;\n",
        "answer": "increase.\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decrease and beyond a certain Mach number start increasing again.\n",
        "choicethree": "stay constant.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the air is passing through an expansion wave the static temperature will ;\n",
        "answer": "decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "stay constant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increase.\n",
        "choicethree": "decrease and beyond a certain Mach number start increasing again.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the blades of a propeller are in the feathered position ;\n",
        "answer": "the drag of the propeller is then minimal.\n",
        "choiceone": "the RPM is then just sufficient to lubricate the engine.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the windmilling RPM is the maximum.\n",
        "choicethree": "the propeller produces an optimal windmilling RPM.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the cg position is moved forward , the elevator deflection for a manoeuvre with a given load factor greater than 1 will\nbe ;\n",
        "answer": "larger.\n",
        "choiceone": "dependent on trim position.\n",
        "choicetwo": "unchanged.\n",
        "choicethree": "smaller.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the lift coefficient Cl of a negatively cambered aerofoil section is zero , the pitching moment is ;\n",
        "answer": "nose up ( positive ).\n",
        "choiceone": "maximum.\n",
        "choicetwo": "nose down ( negative ).\n",
        "choicethree": "zero.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the lift coefficient Cl of a positively cambered aerofoil section is zero , the pitching moment is ;\n",
        "answer": "nose down ( negative ).\n",
        "choiceone": "maximum.\n",
        "choicetwo": "nose up ( positive ).\n",
        "choicethree": "zero.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the lift coefficient Cl of a symmetrical aerofoil section is zero , the pitching moment is ;\n",
        "answer": "zero.\n",
        "choiceone": "nose up ( positive ).\n",
        "choicetwo": "maximum.\n",
        "choicethree": "nose down ( negative ).\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the Mach number is slowly increased in straight and level flight the first shock waves will occur ;\n",
        "answer": "on the upper surface at the wing root.\n",
        "choiceone": "somewhere on the horizontal tail.\n",
        "choicetwo": "on the lower surface of the wing.\n",
        "choicethree": "somewhere on the fin.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the speed over an aerofoil section increases from subsonic to supersonic , its aerodynamic centre ;\n",
        "answer": "moves from approximately 25% to about 50% of the chord.\n",
        "choiceone": "does not move.\n",
        "choicetwo": "moves slightly forward.\n",
        "choicethree": "moves aft by approximately 10% of the chord.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When trailing edge flaps are extended in level flight , the change in pitching moment , ignoring any effects on the tailplane ,\nwill be ;\n",
        "answer": "nose down.\n",
        "choiceone": "dependent on cg location.\n",
        "choicetwo": "zero.\n",
        "choicethree": "nose up.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When trailing edge flaps are extended whilst maintaining straight and level flight at constant IAS ;\n",
        "answer": "the centre of pressure moves aft.\n",
        "choiceone": "the lift coefficient and the drag coefficient increase.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the stall speed increases.\n",
        "choicethree": "the total boundary layer becomes laminar.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "When wing lift is zero , its induced drag is ;\n",
        "answer": "zero.\n",
        "choiceone": "maximum.\n",
        "choicetwo": "low.\n",
        "choicethree": "high.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where , on a convential low speed aerofoil , will flow separation normally start as angle of attack is increased ?\n",
        "answer": "Upper surface trailing edge.\n",
        "choiceone": "Lower surface trailing edge.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Upper surface leading edge.\n",
        "choicethree": "Lower surface leading edge.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 18 )\n Image 18\n Where on the curve in the diagram does the aeroplane exhibit neutral static longitudinal stability ?\n",
        "answer": "Point 2.\n",
        "choiceone": "Part 1.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The whole curve.\n",
        "choicethree": "Part 3.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 18 )\n Image 18\n Where on the curve in the diagram does the aeroplane exhibit static longitudinal instability ?\n",
        "answer": "Part 3.\n",
        "choiceone": "The whole curve.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Point 2.\n",
        "choicethree": "Part 1.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 18 )\n Image 18\n Where on the curve in the diagram does the aeroplane exhibit static longitudinal stability ?\n",
        "answer": "Part 1.\n",
        "choiceone": "Point 2.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The whole curve.\n",
        "choicethree": "Part 3.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where on the surface of a typical aerofoil will flow separation normally start at high angles of attack ?\n",
        "answer": "upper side trailing edge.\n",
        "choiceone": "lower side leading edge.\n",
        "choicetwo": "lower side trailing edge.\n",
        "choicethree": "upper side leading edge.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which aerodynamic design features can be used to reduce control forces ?\n",
        "answer": "Horn balance , balance tab , servo tab.\n",
        "choiceone": "Mass balance , horn balance , artificial feel system.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Balance tab , control surfaces with increased area behind the hinge , artificial feel system.\n",
        "choicethree": "Servo tab , bobweight , control surfaces with increased area.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which aeroplane behaviour will be corrected by a yaw damper ?\n",
        "answer": "Dutch roll.\n",
        "choiceone": "Buffeting.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Tuck under.\n",
        "choicethree": "Spiral dive.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which aeroplane design has the highest probability of a super stall ?\n",
        "answer": "A T-tail.\n",
        "choiceone": "Swept wings.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A canard wing.\n",
        "choicethree": "A low horizontal tail.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which combination of design features is known to be responsible for deep stall ?\n",
        "answer": "Swept back wings and a T-tail.\n",
        "choiceone": "Straight wings and a T-tail.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Straight wings and aft fuselage mounted engines\n",
        "choicethree": "Swept back wings and wing mounted engines.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which boundary layer , when considering its velocity profile perpendicular to the flow , has the greatest change in velocity\nclose to the surface ?\n",
        "answer": "Turbulent boundary layer.\n",
        "choiceone": "No difference.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Laminar boundary layer.\n",
        "choicethree": "The boundary layer in the transition between turbulent and laminar.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which CG position with respect to the neutral point ensures static longitudinal stability ?\n",
        "answer": "CG ahead of the neutral point.\n",
        "choiceone": "CG and neutral point atthe same station.\n",
        "choicetwo": "CG behind the neutral point.\n",
        "choicethree": "CG can be ahead of or behind the neutral point as long as the forward or aft CG limits are not exceeded.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which combination of speeds is applicable for structural strength in gust ( clean configuration ) ?\n",
        "answer": "50 ft/sec and VC.\n",
        "choiceone": "65 ft/sec at all speeds.\n",
        "choicetwo": "55 ft/sec and VB.\n",
        "choicethree": "66 ft/sec and VD.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which component of drag increases most when an aileron is deflected upwards ?\n",
        "answer": "Form drag.\n",
        "choiceone": "Interference drag.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wave drag.\n",
        "choicethree": "Induced drag.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which definition of propeller parameters is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Geometric pitch is the theoretical distance a propeller blade element would travel in a forward direction\n during one revolution.\n",
        "choiceone": "Blade angle is the angle between the blade chord line and the propeller axis.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Critical tip velocity is the propeller speed at which flow separation first occurs at some part of the blade.\n",
        "choicethree": "Angle of attack is the angle between the blade chord line and the propeller vertical plane.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which design features improve static lateral stability ?\n 1. Anhedral.\n 2. Dihedral.\n 3. Forward sweep.\n 4. Sweepback.\n The combination that regroups all of the correct statements is ;\n",
        "answer": "2 , 4.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 , 3.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 , 4.\n",
        "choicethree": "1 , 3.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which design features improve static lateral stability ?\n 1. High wing.\n 2. Low wing.\n 3. Large and high vertical fin.\n 4. Ventral fin.\n The combination that regroups all of the correct statements is ;\n",
        "answer": "1 , 3.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 , 3.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2 , 4.\n",
        "choicethree": "1 , 4.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which design features reduce static lateral stability ?\n 1. Anhedral.\n 2. Dihedral.\n 3. Forward sweep.\n 4. Sweepback.\n The combination that regroups all of the correct statements is ;\n",
        "answer": "1 , 3.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 , 4.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2 , 4.\n",
        "choicethree": "2 , 3.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which design features reduce static lateral stability ?\n 1. High wing.\n 2. Low wing.\n 3. Large and high vertical fin.\n 4. Ventral fin.\n The combination that regroups all of the correct statements is ;\n",
        "answer": "2 , 4.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 , 3.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2 , 3.\n",
        "choicethree": "1 , 4.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which drag components make up parasite drag ?\n 1. pressure drag.\n 2. friction drag.\n 3. induced drag.\n 4. interference drag.\n The combination that regroups all of the correct statements is ;\n",
        "answer": "1 , 2 , 4.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 , 3 , 4.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 , 2 , 3 , 4.\n",
        "choicethree": "2 , 3 , 4.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which factor should be taken into account when determining VA ?\n",
        "answer": "The limit load factor.\n",
        "choiceone": "The calculation factor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The safety factor.\n",
        "choicethree": "The ultimate load factor.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which formula or equation describes the relationship between force (F) , acceleration (a) and mass (m) ?\n",
        "answer": "F=m.a\n",
        "choiceone": "F=m/a\n",
        "choicetwo": "m=F.a\n",
        "choicethree": "a=F.m\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which has the effect of increasing load factor ? ( all other relevant factors being constant )\n",
        "answer": "Vertical gusts.\n",
        "choiceone": "Increased aeroplane mass.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Increased air density.\n",
        "choicethree": "Rearward CG location.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is one of the disadvantages of increasing the number of propeller blades ?\n",
        "answer": "Decrease propeller efficiency.\n",
        "choiceone": "Higher tip-speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Increased noise.\n",
        "choicethree": "Less power can be absorbed by the propeller.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which kind of boundary layer has the strongest change in velocity close to the surface ?\n",
        "answer": "Turbulent boundary layer\n",
        "choiceone": "No difference\n",
        "choicetwo": "Transition boundary layer\n",
        "choicethree": "Laminar boundary layer\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which kind of flow separation occurs at the smallest angle of attack ?\n",
        "answer": "Shockstall.\n",
        "choiceone": "Accelerated stall.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Low-speed stall.\n",
        "choicethree": "Deep stall.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which kind of \u201ctab\u201d is commonly used in case of manual reversion of fully powered flight controls ?\n",
        "answer": "Servo tab\n",
        "choiceone": "Spring tab\n",
        "choicetwo": "Anti-balance tab\n",
        "choicethree": "Balance tab\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 17 )\n Image 17\n Which line in the diagram illustrates an aeroplane with neutral static longitudinal stability at all angles of attack ?\n",
        "answer": "Line 2.\n",
        "choiceone": "Line 4.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Line 3.\n",
        "choicethree": "Line 1.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 17 )\n Image 17\n Which line in the diagram illustrates an aeroplane which is statically longitudinally stable at all angles of attack ?\n",
        "answer": "Line 4.\n",
        "choiceone": "Line 3.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Line 1.\n",
        "choicethree": "Line 2.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 17 )\n Image 17\n Which line in the diagram represents an aeroplane with static longitudinal instability at all angles of attack ?\n",
        "answer": "Line 1.\n",
        "choiceone": "Line 3.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Line 2.\n",
        "choicethree": "Line 4.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 17 )\n Image 17\n Which line in the diagram represents decreasing positive static longitudinal stability at higher angles of attack ?\n",
        "answer": "Line 3.\n",
        "choiceone": "Line 1.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Line 2.\n",
        "choicethree": "Line 4.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 16 )\n Image 16\n Which line in the graphic of Cm versus angle of attack graph shows a statically stable aeroplane ?\n",
        "answer": "Line 3.\n",
        "choiceone": "Line 4.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Line 2.\n",
        "choicethree": "Line 1.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 081-6249A )\n Annex 081-6249A\n Which line represents the total drag line of an aeroplane ?\n",
        "answer": "Line c\n",
        "choiceone": "Line a\n",
        "choicetwo": "Line b\n",
        "choicethree": "Line d\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which load factor determines VA ?\n",
        "answer": "manoeuvring limit load factor.\n",
        "choiceone": "manoeuvring ultimate load factor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "gust load factor at 66 ft/sec gust.\n",
        "choicethree": "manoeuvring flap limit load factor.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which moments or motions interact in a dutch roll ?\n",
        "answer": "Rolling and yawing.\n",
        "choiceone": "Pitching and yawing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Pitching and rolling.\n",
        "choicethree": "Pitching and adverse yaw.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following (1) aerofoils and (2) angles of attack will produce the lowest Mcrit values ?\n",
        "answer": "(1) thick and (2) large.\n",
        "choiceone": "(1) thin and (2) small.\n",
        "choicetwo": "(1) thin and (2) large.\n",
        "choicethree": "(1) thick and (2) small.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following aeroplane parts affect induced drag most ?\n",
        "answer": "Wing tip.\n",
        "choiceone": "Landing gear.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Engine cowling.\n",
        "choicethree": "Wing root junction.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following are used as stall warning devices ?\n",
        "answer": "Stick shaker and stallstrip.\n",
        "choiceone": "Angle of attack sensor and stallstrip.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Angle of attack indicator and speed indicator.\n",
        "choicethree": "Stick shaker and angle of attack indicator.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following flight phenomena can occur at Mach numbers below the critical Mach number ?\n",
        "answer": "Dutch roll.\n",
        "choiceone": "Shock stall.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Mach buffet.\n",
        "choicethree": "Tuck under.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following flight phenomena can only occur at Mach numbers above the critical Mach number ?\n",
        "answer": "Mach buffet.\n",
        "choiceone": "Dutch roll.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Elevator stall.\n",
        "choicethree": "Speed instability.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following increases the maximum duration of a glide ?\n",
        "answer": "A decrease in mass.\n",
        "choiceone": "An increase in mass.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A tailwind.\n",
        "choicethree": "A headwind.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following lists contain aeroplane design features that all increase static lateral stability ?\n",
        "answer": "High wing , sweep back , large and high vertical fin.\n",
        "choiceone": "Low wing , dihedral , elliptical wing planform.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fuselage mounted engines , dihedral , T-tail.\n",
        "choicethree": "Sweep back , under wing mounted engines , winglets.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following parameters can be read from the parabolic polar diagram of an aeroplane ?\n",
        "answer": "The minimum glide angle and the parasite drag coefficient.\n",
        "choiceone": "The induced drag and the parasite drag.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The minimum rate of descent and the induced drag.\n",
        "choicethree": "The aspect ratio of the wing and the induced drag coefficient.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following provides a positive contribution to static directional stability ?\n",
        "answer": "A dorsal fin.\n",
        "choiceone": "A low wing as compared with a high wing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A forward swept wing.\n",
        "choicethree": "Moving the center of gravity aft.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following situations leads to a decreasing stall speed ( IAS ) ?\n",
        "answer": "decreasing weight.\n",
        "choiceone": "increasing air density.\n",
        "choicetwo": "increasing altitude.\n",
        "choicethree": "increasing load factor.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about a constant speed propeller is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The blade angle increases with increasing aeroplane speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "The propeller system keeps the aeroplane speed constant.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The selected RPM is kept constant by the manifold pressure.\n",
        "choicethree": "The RPM decreases with increasing aeroplane speed.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about a Mach trimmer is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "A Mach trimmer corrects the change in stick force stability of a swept wing aeroplane above a certain Mach\n number.\n",
        "choiceone": "A straight wing aeroplane always needs a Mach trimmer for flying at Mach numbers close to MMO.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A Mach trimmer reduces the stick force stability of a straight wing aeroplane to zero at high Mach numbers.\n",
        "choicethree": "The Mach trimmer corrects the natural tendency of a swept wing aeroplane to pitch-up.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about a venturi in a subsonic airflow are correct ?\n 1. The dynamic pressures in the undisturbed flow and in the throat are equal.\n 2. The total pressures in the undisturbed flow and in the throat are equal.\n",
        "answer": "1 is incorrect and 2 is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 is correct and 2 is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 and 2 are incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "1 and 2 are correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about boundary layers is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The turbulent boundary layer has more kinetic energy than the laminar boundary layer.\n",
        "choiceone": "The turbulent boundary layer will separate more easily than the laminar boundary layer.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The turbulent boundary layer is thinner than the laminar boundary layer.\n",
        "choicethree": "The turbulent boundary layer gives a lower skin friction than the laminar boundary layer.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about dihedral is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The \u201ceffective dihedral\u201d of an aeroplane component means the contribution of that component to the static\n lateral stability.\n",
        "choiceone": "Dihedral is necessary for the execution of slip-free turns.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Effective dihedral is the angle between the 1/4-chord line and the lateral axis of the aeroplane.\n",
        "choicethree": "Dihedral contributes to dynamic but not to static lateral stability.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about stall speed is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Decreasing the angle of sweep of the wing will decrease the stall speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Increasing the angle of sweep of the wing will decrease the stall speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Increasing the anhedral of the wing will decrease the stall speed.\n",
        "choicethree": "Use of a T-tail will decrease the stall speed.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about static lateral and directional stability is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "An aeroplane with an excessive static directional stability in relation to its static lateral stability , will be\n prone to spiral dive ( spiral instability ).\n",
        "choiceone": "The effects of static lateral and static directional stability are completely independent of each other because\n they take place about different axes.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Static directional stability can be increased by installing more powerful engines.\n",
        "choicethree": "An aeroplane with an excessive static directional stability in relation to its static lateral stability , will be\n prone to \u201cDutch roll\u201d.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about static longitudinal stability is correct ?\n I. A requirement for positive static longitudinal stability of an aeroplane is , that the neutral point is\n behind the centre of gravity.\n II. A wing with positive camber provides a positive contribution to static longitudinal stability , when the\n centre of gravity of the aeroplane is in front of the aerodynamic centre of the wing.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the difference between Krueger flaps and slats is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Deploying a slat will form a slot , deploying a Krueger flap does not.\n",
        "choiceone": "Deploying a Krueger flap will form a slot , deploying a slat does not.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Deploying a slat will increase critical angle of attack , deploying a Krueger flap does not.\n",
        "choicethree": "Deploying a Krueger flap will increase critical angle of attack , deploying a slat does not.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the spin is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "During spin recovery the ailerons should be kept in the neutral position.\n",
        "choiceone": "Every aeroplane should be designed such that it can never enter a spin.\n",
        "choicetwo": "An aeroplane is prone to spin when the stall starts at the wing root.\n",
        "choicethree": "In the spin , airspeed continuously increases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the stall of a straight wing aeroplane is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Just before the stall the aeroplane will be have an increased nose-down tendency.\n",
        "choiceone": "The horizontal tail will stall at a higher speed than the wing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Buffeting is the result of tailplane flow separation..\n",
        "choicethree": "The nose down effect is the result of increasing downwash , due to flow separation.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements concerning control is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "In a differential aileron control system the control surfaces have a larger upward than downward maximum\n deflection.\n",
        "choiceone": "On some aeroplanes , the servo tab also serves as a trim tab.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Hydraulically powered control surfaces do not need mass balancing.\n",
        "choicethree": "In general the maximum downward elevator deflection is larger than upward.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct ?\n I. A high limit load factor enables the manufacturer to design for a lower stick force per g.\n II. The stick force per g is a limitation on the use of an aeroplane , which the pilot should determine from\n the Aeroplane Flight Manual.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct and II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect and II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct and II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect and II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct ?\n I. VMCL is the minimum control speed in the landing configuration.\n II. The speed VMCL always limited by maximum rudder deflection.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct ?\n I. VMCL is the minimum control speed in the landing configuration.\n II. The speed VMCL can be limited by the available maximum roll rate.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct ?\n I. When the critical engine fails during take-off the speed VMCL can be limiting.\n II. The speed VMCL can be limited by the available maximum roll rate.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct ?\n I. When the critical engine fails during take-off the speed VMCL can be limiting.\n II. The speed VMCL is always limited by maximum rudder deflection.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct ?\n I. A dorsal fin increases the contribution of the vertical tail plane to the static directional stability , in\n particular at large angles of sideslip.\n II. A dorsal and a ventral fin both have a positive effect on static lateral stability.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is true ?\n",
        "answer": "Flight in severe turbulence may lead to a stall and/or structural limitations being exceeded\n",
        "choiceone": "By increasing the flap setting in severe turbulence at constant speed the stall speed will be reduced and the\n risk for exceeding the structural limits will be decreased\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flap extension in severe turbulence at constant speed increases both the stall speed and the structural\n limitation margins\n",
        "choicethree": "Flap extension in severe turbulence at constant speed moves the centre of pressure aft , which increases the\n structural limitation margins\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following variables are required to calculate lift from the lift formula ?\n",
        "answer": "Dynamic pressure , lift coefficient and wing area.\n",
        "choiceone": "Angle of attack , aspect ratio and dynamic pressure.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Square root of wing area , density and wing loading.\n",
        "choicethree": "Total pressure and wing area only.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following will reduce induced drag ?\n",
        "answer": "Elliptical lift distribution.\n",
        "choiceone": "Extending the flaps.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Low aspect ratio.\n",
        "choicethree": "Flying at high angles of attack.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following wing planforms gives the highest local lift coefficient at the wing root ?\n",
        "answer": "Rectangular.\n",
        "choiceone": "Positive angle of sweep.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Elliptical.\n",
        "choicethree": "Tapered.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following wing planforms produces the lowest induced drag ? ( all other relevant factors constant )\n",
        "answer": "Elliptical.\n",
        "choiceone": "Rectangular.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Circular.\n",
        "choicethree": "Tapered.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these definitions of propeller parameters is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Geometric propeller pitch = the theoretical distance a propeller blade element is travelling in forward\n direction in one propeller revolution.\n",
        "choiceone": "Blade angle = angle between blade chord line and propeller axis.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Propeller angle of attack = angle between blade chord line and propeller vertical plane.\n",
        "choicethree": "Critical tip velocity = propeller speed at which risk of flow separation at some parts of propeller blade occurs.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about a trimmable horizontal stabiliser is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "A trimmed aeroplane with an aft CG requires the stabiliser leading edge to be higher than in the case of a\n forward CG in the same condition.\n",
        "choiceone": "At the aft CG limit , stabiliser trim is adjusted fully nose up to obtain maximum elevator authority at rotation\n during take-off.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A trimmed aeroplane with an aft CG requires the stabiliser leading edge to be lower than in the case of a\n forward CG in the same condition.\n",
        "choicethree": "Because take-off speeds do not vary with CG position , the need for stabiliser adjustment is dependent on\n flap position only.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about an oblique shock wave are correct or incorrect ?\n I. The density behind an oblique shock wave is higher than in front of it.\n II. The local speed of sound behind an oblique shock wave is higher than in front of it.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about an oblique shock wave are correct or incorrect ?\n I. The density behind an oblique shock wave is higher than in front of it.\n II. The local speed of sound behind an oblique shock wave is lower than in front of it.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about an oblique shock wave are correct or incorrect ?\n I. The density behind an oblique shock wave is lower than in front of it.\n II. The local speed of sound behind an oblique shock wave is higher than in front of it.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about an oblique shock wave are correct or incorrect ?\n I. The density behind an oblique shock wave is lower than in front of it.\n II. The local speed of sound behind an oblique shock wave is lower than in front of it.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about an oblique shock wave are correct or incorrect ?\n I. The density in front of an oblique shock wave is higher than behind it.\n II. The total pressure in front of an oblique shock wave is higher than behind it.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about an oblique shock wave are correct or incorrect ?\n I. The density in front of an oblique shock wave is higher than behind it.\n II. The total pressure in front of an oblique shock wave is lower than behind it.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about an oblique shock wave are correct or incorrect ?\n I. The density in front of an oblique shock wave is lower than behind it.\n II. The total pressure in front of an oblique shock wave is higher than behind it.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about an oblique shock wave are correct or incorrect ?\n I. The density in front of an oblique shock wave is lower than behind it.\n II. The total pressure in front of an oblique shock wave is lower than behind it.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about an oblique shock wave are correct or incorrect ?\n I. The local speed of sound in front of an oblique shock wave is higher than behind it.\n II. The Mach number in front of an oblique shock wave is higher than behind it.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about an oblique shock wave are correct or incorrect ?\n I. The local speed of sound in front of an oblique shock wave is higher than behind it.\n II. The Mach number in front of an oblique shock wave is lower than behind it.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about an oblique shock wave are correct or incorrect ?\n I. The local speed of sound in front of an oblique shock wave is lower than behind it.\n II. The Mach number in front of an oblique shock wave is higher than behind it.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about an oblique shock wave are correct or incorrect ?\n I. The local speed of sound in front of an oblique shock wave is lower than behind it.\n II. The Mach number in front of an oblique shock wave is lower than behind it.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about an oblique shock wave are correct or incorrect ?\n I. The Mach number behind an oblique shock wave is higher than in front of it.\n II. The total pressure behind an oblique shock wave is higher than in front of it.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about an oblique shock wave are correct or incorrect ?\n I. The Mach number behind an oblique shock wave is higher than in front of it.\n II. The total pressure behind an oblique shock wave is lower than in front of it.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about an oblique shock wave are correct or incorrect ?\n I. The Mach number behind an oblique shock wave is lower than in front of it.\n II. The total pressure behind an oblique shock wave is higher than in front of it.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about an oblique shock wave are correct or incorrect ?\n I. The Mach number behind an oblique shock wave is lower than in front of it.\n II. The total pressure behind an oblique shock wave is lower than in front of it.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about an oblique shock wave are correct or incorrect ?\n I. The static temperature behind an oblique shock wave is higher than in front of it.\n II. The static pressure behind an oblique shock wave is higher than in front of it.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about an oblique shock wave are correct or incorrect ?\n I. The static temperature behind an oblique shock wave is higher than in front of it.\n II. The static pressure behind an oblique shock wave is lower than in front of it.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about an oblique shock wave are correct or incorrect ?\n I. The static temperature behind an oblique shock wave is lower than in front of it.\n II. The static pressure behind an oblique shock wave is higher than in front of it.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about an oblique shock wave are correct or incorrect ?\n I. The static temperature behind an oblique shock wave is lower than in front of it.\n II. The static pressure behind an oblique shock wave is lower than in front of it.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about an oblique shock wave are correct or incorrect ?\n I. The static temperature in front of an oblique shock wave is higher than behind it.\n II. The static pressure in front of an oblique shock wave is higher than behind it.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about an oblique shock wave are correct or incorrect ?\n I. The static temperature in front of an oblique shock wave is higher than behind it.\n II. The static pressure in front of an oblique shock wave is lower than behind it.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about an oblique shock wave are correct or incorrect ?\n I. The static temperature in front of an oblique shock wave is lower than behind it.\n II. The static pressure in front of an oblique shock wave is higher than behind it.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about an oblique shock wave are correct or incorrect ?\n I. The static temperature in front of an oblique shock wave is lower than behind it.\n II. The static pressure in front of an oblique shock wave is lower than behind it.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about boundary layers is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "A laminar boundary layer turns into a turbulent one at the transition point.\n",
        "choiceone": "A turbulent boundary layer produces less friction drag than a laminar one.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A laminar boundary layer is thicker than a turbulent one.\n",
        "choicethree": "Compared with a turbulent boundary layer , a laminar boundary layer is better able to resist a positive\n pressure gradient before it separates.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about boundary layers is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "A turbulent boundary layer produces more friction drag than a laminar one.\n",
        "choiceone": "A laminar boundary layer is thicker than a turbulent one.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A turbulent boundary layer turns into a laminar one at the transition point.\n",
        "choicethree": "Compared with a turbulent boundary layer , a laminar boundary layer is better able to resist a positive\n pressure gradient before it separates.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about boundary layers is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "A laminar boundary layer is thinner than a turbulent one.\n",
        "choiceone": "A turbulent boundary layer produces less friction drag than a laminar one.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Compared with a turbulent boundary layer , a laminar boundary layer is better able to resist a positive\n pressure gradient before it separates.\n",
        "choicethree": "A turbulent boundary layer turns into a laminar one at the transition point.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about boundary layers is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Compared with a laminar boundary layer , a turbulent boundary layer is better able to resist a positive\n pressure gradient before it separates.\n",
        "choiceone": "A turbulent boundary layer becomes laminar at the transition point.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A laminar boundary layer is thicker than a turbulent one.\n",
        "choicethree": "A turbulent boundary layer produces less friction drag than a laminar one.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about flutter are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Aero-elastic coupling affects flutter characteristics.\n II. The risk of flutter increases as IAS increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about flutter are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Aero-elastic coupling affects flutter characteristics.\n II. Occurrence of flutter is independent of IAS.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about flutter are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Aero-elastic coupling does not affect flutter characteristics.\n II. Occurrence of flutter is independent of IAS.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about flutter are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Aero-elastic coupling does not affect flutter characteristics.\n II. The risk of flutter increases as IAS increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about flutter are correct or incorrect ?\n I. If flutter occurs , IAS should be kept constant.\n II. Resistance to flutter increases with increasing wing stiffness.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about flutter are correct or incorrect ?\n I. If flutter occurs , IAS should be kept constant.\n II. Resistance to flutter increases with reducing wing stiffness.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about flutter are correct or incorrect ?\n I. If flutter occurs , IAS should be reduced.\n II. Resistance to flutter increases with increasing wing stiffness.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about flutter are correct or incorrect ?\n I. If flutter occurs , IAS should be reduced.\n II. Resistance to flutter increases with reducing wing stiffness.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about flutter are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Moving the engines from the wing to the aft fuselage improves wing flutter suppression.\n II. Excessive free play or backlash increases the speed at which control surface flutter occurs.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about flutter are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Moving the engines from the wing to the aft fuselage improves wing flutter suppression.\n II. Excessive free play or backlash reduces the speed at which control surface flutter occurs.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about flutter are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Wing mounted engines extending ahead of the wing contribute to wing flutter suppression.\n II. Excessive free play or backlash increases the speed at which control surface flutter occurs.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about flutter are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Wing mounted engines extending ahead of the wing contribute to wing flutter suppression.\n II. Excessive free play or backlash reduces the speed at which control surface flutter occurs.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about induced drag are correct or incorrect ?\n I. A rectangular spanwise lift distribution generates less induced drag than an elliptical lift distribution.\n II. Induced drag decreases with increasing aspect ratio.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about induced drag are correct or incorrect ?\n I. A rectangular spanwise lift distribution generates less induced drag than an elliptical lift distribution.\n II. Induced drag increases with increasing aspect ratio.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about induced drag are correct or incorrect ?\n I. A rectangular spanwise lift distribution generates more induced drag than an elliptical lift distribution.\n II. Induced drag decreases with increasing aspect ratio.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about induced drag are correct or incorrect ?\n I. A rectangular spanwise lift distribution generates more induced drag than an elliptical lift distribution.\n II. Induced drag increases with increasing aspect ratio.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about induced drag are correct or incorrect ?\n I. An elliptical spanwise lift distribution generates less induced drag than a rectangular lift distribution.\n II. Induced drag decreases with decreasing aspect ratio.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about induced drag are correct or incorrect ?\n I. An elliptical spanwise lift distribution generates less induced drag than a rectangular lift distribution.\n II. Induced drag increases with decreasing aspect ratio.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about induced drag are correct or incorrect ?\n I. An elliptical spanwise lift distribution generates more induced drag than a rectangular lift distribution.\n II. Induced drag decreases with decreasing aspect ratio.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about induced drag are correct or incorrect?\n I. An elliptical spanwise lift distribution generates more induced drag than a rectangular lift distribution.\n II. Induced drag increases with decreasing aspect ratio.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about induced drag are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Induced drag decreases as angle of attack decreases.\n II. At constant load factor , induced drag decreases with decreasing aeroplane mass.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about induced drag are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Induced drag decreases as angle of attack decreases.\n II. At constant load factor , induced drag increases with decreasing aeroplane mass.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about induced drag are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Induced drag decreases as angle of attack increases.\n II. At constant load factor , induced drag decreases with increasing aeroplane mass.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about induced drag are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Induced drag decreases as angle of attack increases.\n II. At constant load factor , induced drag increases with increasing aeroplane mass.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about induced drag are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Induced drag increases as angle of attack decreases.\n II. At constant load factor , induced drag decreases with decreasing aeroplane mass.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about induced drag are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Induced drag increases as angle of attack decreases.\n II. At constant load factor , induced drag increases with decreasing aeroplane mass.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about induced drag are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Induced drag increases as angle of attack increases.\n II. At constant load factor , induced drag increases with increasing aeroplane mass.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about Mcrit is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Shock waves cannot occur at speeds below Mcrit.\n",
        "choiceone": "As speed increases above Mcrit. , parasite drag decreases rapidly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flight at any speed above Mcrit causes severe vibration of the aeroplane.\n",
        "choicethree": "Mcrit is always greater than 1.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about propellers is correct or incorrect ?\n I. A cruise propeller has a greater geometric pitch when compared with a climb propeller.\n II. A coarse pitch propeller is less efficient during take-off and in the climb , but more efficient in the\n cruise , when compared with a fine pitch propeller.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about propellers is correct or incorrect ?\n I. A cruise propeller has a greater geometric pitch when compared with a climb propeller.\n II. A coarse pitch propeller is more efficient during take-off and in the climb , but is less efficient in the\n cruise , when compared with a fine pitch propeller.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about propellers is correct or incorrect ?\n I. A cruise propeller has a smaller geometric pitch when compared with a climb propeller.\n II. A coarse pitch propeller is less efficient during take-off and in the climb , but more efficient in the\n cruise , when compared with a fine pitch propeller.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about propellers is correct or incorrect ?\n I. A cruise propeller has a smaller geometric pitch when compared with a climb propeller.\n II. A coarse pitch propeller is more efficient during take-off and in the climb , but is less efficient in the\n cruise , when compared with a fine pitch propeller.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about stall speed is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Decreasing sweepback decreases stall speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Decreasing wing anhedral decreases stall speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Decreasing sweepback increases stall speed.\n",
        "choicethree": "Increasing wing anhedral decreases stall speed.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about stall speed is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Increasing forward sweep increases stall speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Increasing wing anhedral decreases stall speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Increasing forward sweep decreases stall speed.\n",
        "choicethree": "Decreasing wing anhedral decreases stall speed.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about stall speed is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Decreasing forward sweep increases stall speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "Increasing wing anhedral decreases stall speed.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Decreasing wing anhedral decreases stall speed.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the effect of wing sweep on centre of pressure location are correct or incorrect ?\n I. The centre of pressure on a straight wing moves aft as the angle of attack approaches and exceeds the\n critical angle of attack.\n II. The centre of pressure on a strongly swept back wing moves forward as the angle of attack approaches\n and exceeds the critical angle of attack.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the equilibrium of forces and moments at VMCA are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Because VMCA must be determined for the case where the critical engine suddenly fails , there is no\n need to obtain equilibrium of moments about the normal axis.\n II. Equilibrium of forces along the lateral axis does not require any side slip during a wings level\n condition.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the equilibrium of forces and moments at VMCA are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Because VMCA must be determined for the case where the critical engine suddenly fails , there is no\n need to obtain equilibrium of moments about the normal axis.\n II. Equilibrium of forces along the lateral axis requires either bank angle or side slip or a combination of\n both.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the equilibrium of forces and moments at VMCA are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Equilibrium of moments about the normal axis is provided by rudder deflection.\n II. Equilibrium of forces along the lateral axis does not require any side slip during a wings level\n condition.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the equilibrium of forces and moments at VMCA are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Equilibrium of moments about the normal axis is provided by rudder deflection.\n II. Equilibrium of forces along the lateral axis requires either bank angle or side slip or a combination of\n both.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the gust load factor on an aeroplane are correct or incorrect ?\n I. When the mass decreases , the gust load factor decreases.\n II. When the altitude decreases , the gust load factor decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the gust load factor on an aeroplane are correct or incorrect ?\n I. When the mass decreases , the gust load factor decreases.\n II. When the altitude increases , the gust load factor decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the gust load factor on an aeroplane are correct or incorrect ?\n I. When the mass decreases , the gust load factor increases.\n II. When the altitude decreases , the gust load factor increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the gust load factor on an aeroplane are correct or incorrect ?\n I. When the mass increases , the gust load factor decreases.\n II. When the altitude decreases , the gust load factor decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the gust load factor on an aeroplane are correct or incorrect ?\n I. When the mass increases , the gust load factor decreases.\n II. When the altitude increases , the gust load factor decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the gust load factor on an aeroplane are correct or incorrect ?\n I. When the mass increases , the gust load factor increases.\n II. When the altitude increases , the gust load factor increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the gust load factor on an aeroplane are correct or incorrect ?\n I. When the slope of the lift versus angle of attack curve decreases , the gust load factor decreases.\n II. When the wing loading decreases , the gust load factor increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the gust load factor on an aeroplane are correct or incorrect ?\n I. When the slope of the lift versus angle of attack curve decreases , the gust load factor increases.\n II. When the wing loading decreases , the gust load factor decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the gust load factor on an aeroplane are correct or incorrect ?\n I. When the slope of the lift versus angle of attack curve decreases , the gust load factor increases.\n II. When the wing loading decreases , the gust load factor increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the gust load factor on an aeroplane are correct or incorrect ?\n I. When the slope of the lift versus angle of attack curve increases , the gust load factor decreases.\n II. When the wing loading decreases , the gust load factor decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the gust load factor on an aeroplane are correct or incorrect ?\n I. When the slope of the lift versus angle of attack curve increases , the gust load factor decreases.\n II. When the wing loading increases , the gust load factor decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the gust load factor on an aeroplane are correct or incorrect ?\n I. When the slope of the lift versus angle of attack curve increases , the gust load factor increases.\n II. When the wing loading increases , the gust load factor decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the gust load factor on an aeroplane are correct or incorrect ?\n I. When the wing area decreases , the gust load factor decreases.\n II. When the EAS decreases , the gust load factor decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the gust load factor on an aeroplane are correct or incorrect ?\n I. When the wing area decreases , the gust load factor decreases.\n II. When the EAS decreases , the gust load factor increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the gust load factor on an aeroplane are correct or incorrect ?\n I. When the wing area decreases , the gust load factor increases.\n II. When the EAS decreases , the gust load factor decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the gust load factor on an aeroplane are correct or incorrect ?\n I. When the wing area decreases , the gust load factor increases.\n II. When the EAS decreases , the gust load factor increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the gust load factor on an aeroplane are correct or incorrect ?\n I. When the wing area increases , the gust load factor decreases.\n II. When the EAS increases , the gust load factor decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the gust load factor on an aeroplane are correct or incorrect ?\n I. When the wing area increases , the gust load factor decreases.\n II. When the EAS increases , the gust load factor increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the gust load factor on an aeroplane are correct or incorrect ?\n I. When the wing area increases , the gust load factor increases.\n II. When the EAS increases , the gust load factor decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the gust load factor on an aeroplane are correct or incorrect ?\n I. When the wing area increases , the gust load factor increases.\n II. When the EAS increases , the gust load factor increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the limiting value of 5 degrees bank angle during VMCA determination are correct or\nincorrect ?\n I. As the bank angle is decreased from 5 degrees to 0 degrees , the value of VMCA increases.\n II. At any bank angle beyond 5 degrees , there is an increasing risk of fin stall.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the limiting value of 5 degrees bank angle during VMCA determination are correct or\nincorrect ?\n I. As the bank angle is decreased from 5 degrees to 0 degrees , the value of VMCA increases.\n II. When the bank angle is increased beyond 5 degrees , there is an increasing risk of fin stall.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the limiting value of 5 degrees bank angle during VMCA determination are correct or\nincorrect ?\n I. When the bank angle is decreased from 5 degrees to 0 degrees , the value of VMCA will remain\n approximately constant.\n II. At any bank angle above 5 degrees , VMCA will decrease correspondingly.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the limiting value of 5 degrees bank angle during VMCA determination are correct or\nincorrect ?\n I. When the bank angle is decreased from 5 degrees to 0 degrees , the value of VMCA will remain\n approximately constant.\n II. When the bank angle is increased beyond 5 degrees , there is a increasing risk of fin stall.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 15 )\n Image 15\n Which of these statements about the pitching moment coefficient versus angle of attack lines in the annex is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "In its curved part at high angles of attack line 2 illustrates increasing static longitudinal stability.\n",
        "choiceone": "The CG position is further aft at line 4 when compared with line 1.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The horizontal part of line 2 illustrates static longitudinal instability.\n",
        "choicethree": "Static longitudinal stability is greater at line 3 when compared with line 4 at low and moderate angles of\n attack.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 15 )\n Image 15\n Which of these statements about the pitching moment coefficient versus angle of attack lines in the annex is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The CG position is further forward at line 4 when compared with line 1.\n",
        "choiceone": "Static longitudinal stability is greater at line 3 when compared with line 4 at low and moderate angles of\n attack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The CG position is further aft at line 4 when compared with line 1.\n",
        "choicethree": "In its curved part line 2 illustrates a decreasing static longitudinal stability at high angles of attack.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 15 )\n Image 15\n Which of these statements about the pitching moment coefficient versus angle of attack lines in the annex is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Static longitudinal stability is greater at line 4 when compared with line 3 at low and moderate angles of\n attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "The CG position is further forward at line 1 when compared with line 4.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Static longitudinal stability is greater at line 3 compared with line 4 at low and moderate angles of attack.\n",
        "choicethree": "In its curved part line 2 illustrates a decreasing static longitudinal stability at high angles of attack.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 15 )\n Image 15\n Which of these statements about the pitching moment coefficient versus angle of attack lines in the annex is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The CG position is further aft at line 1 when compared with line 4.\n",
        "choiceone": "In its curved part at high angles of attack line 2 illustrates a decreasing static longitudinal stability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The CG position is further forward at line 1 when compared with line 4.\n",
        "choicethree": "Static longitudinal stability is greater at line 3 when compared with line 4 at low and moderate angles of\n attack.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the strength of wing tip vortices are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Assuming no flow separation , the strength of wing tip vortices decreases as the angle of attack\n decreases.\n II. The strength of wing tip vortices decreases as the aspect ratio decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the strength of wing tip vortices are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Assuming no flow separation , the strength of wing tip vortices decreases as the angle of attack\n decreases.\n II. The strength of wing tip vortices decreases as the aspect ratio increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the strength of wing tip vortices are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Assuming no flow separation , the strength of wing tip vortices decreases as the angle of attack\n decreases.\n II. The strength of wing tip vortices increases as the aspect ratio decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the strength of wing tip vortices are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Assuming no flow separation , the strength of wing tip vortices decreases as the angle of attack\n decreases.\n II. The strength of wing tip vortices is not affected by aspect ratio decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the strength of wing tip vortices are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Assuming no flow separation , the strength of wing tip vortices decreases as the angle of attack\n increases.\n II. The strength of wing tip vortices decreases as the aspect ratio decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the strength of wing tip vortices are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Assuming no flow separation , the strength of wing tip vortices decreases as the angle of attack\n increases.\n II. The strength of wing tip vortices decreases as the aspect ratio increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the strength of wing tip vortices are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Assuming no flow separation , the strength of wing tip vortices decreases as the angle of attack\n increases.\n II. The strength of wing tip vortices increases as the aspect ratio decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the strength of wing tip vortices are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Assuming no flow separation , the strength of wing tip vortices decreases as the angle of attack\n increases.\n II. The strength of wing tip vortices increases as the aspect ratio increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the strength of wing tip vortices are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Assuming no flow separation , the strength of wing tip vortices decreases as the angle of attack\n increases.\n II. The strength of wing tip vortices is not affected by aspect ratio.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the strength of wing tip vortices are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Assuming no flow separation , the strength of wing tip vortices increases as the angle of attack\n decreases.\n II. The strength of wing tip vortices decreases as the aspect ratio decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the strength of wing tip vortices are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Assuming no flow separation , the strength of wing tip vortices increases as the angle of attack\n decreases.\n II. The strength of wing tip vortices decreases as the aspect ratio increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the strength of wing tip vortices are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Assuming no flow separation , the strength of wing tip vortices increases as the angle of attack\n decreases.\n II. The strength of wing tip vortices increases as the aspect ratio decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the strength of wing tip vortices are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Assuming no flow separation , the strength of wing tip vortices increases as the angle of attack\n decreases.\n II. The strength of wing tip vortices increases as the aspect ratio increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the strength of wing tip vortices are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Assuming no flow separation , the strength of wing tip vortices increases as the angle of attack\n decreases.\n II. The strength of wing tip vortices is not affected by aspect ratio decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the strength of wing tip vortices are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Assuming no flow separation , the strength of wing tip vortices increases as the angle of attack\n increases.\n II. The strength of wing tip vortices decreases as the aspect ratio increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the strength of wing tip vortices are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Assuming no flow separation , the strength of wing tip vortices increases as the angle of attack\n increases.\n II. The strength of wing tip vortices increases as the aspect ratio decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the strength of wing tip vortices are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Assuming no flow separation , the strength of wing tip vortices increases as the angle of attack\n increases.\n II. The strength of wing tip vortices increases as the aspect ratio increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the strength of wing tip vortices are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Assuming no flow separation , the strength of wing tip vortices increases as the angle of attack\n increases.\n II. The strength of wing tip vortices is not affected by aspect ratio.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the strength of wing tip vortices are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Assuming no flow separation , the strength of wing tip vortices is not affected by angle of attack.\n II. The strength of wing tip vortices decreases as the aspect ratio decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the strength of wing tip vortices are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Assuming no flow separation , the strength of wing tip vortices is not affected by the angle of attack.\n II. The strength of wing tip vortices decreases as the aspect ratio increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the strength of wing tip vortices are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Assuming no flow separation , the strength of wing tip vortices is not affected by angle of attack.\n II. The strength of wing tip vortices increases as the aspect ratio decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the strength of wing tip vortices are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Assuming no flow separation , the strength of wing tip vortices is not affected by angle of attack.\n II. The strength of wing tip vortices increases as the aspect ratio increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the strength of wing tip vortices are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Assuming no flow separation , the strength of wing tip vortices is not affected by angle of attack.\n II. The strength of wing tip vortices is not affected by aspect ratio.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the supersonic speed range is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The airflow everywhere around the aeroplane is supersonic.\n",
        "choiceone": "The supersonic speed range starts at a Mach number below M = 1 and extends to Mach numbers above\n M = 1.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The airflow around the aeroplane is transonic.\n",
        "choicethree": "The supersonic speed range starts at M = 1 and ends at Mcrit.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about the transonic speed range is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The transonic speed range starts at Mcrit and extends to Mach numbers above M = 1.\n",
        "choiceone": "The transonic speed range starts at M = 0.5 and ends at Mcrit.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The airflow everywhere around the aeroplane is subsonic.\n",
        "choicethree": "The airflow everywhere around the aeroplane is supersonic.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about \u201ctuck under\u201d are correct or incorrect ?\n I. A contributing factor to \u201ctuck under\u201d is an forward movement of the centre of pressure of the wing.\n II. A contributing factor to \u201ctuck under\u201d is a reduction in the downwash angle at the location of the\n horizontal stabiliser.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about \u201ctuck under\u201d are correct or incorrect ?\n I. A contributing factor to \u201ctuck under\u201d is a forward movement of the centre of pressure of the wing.\n II. A contributing factor to \u201ctuck under\u201d is an increase in the downwash angle at the location of the\n horizontal stabiliser.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about \u201ctuck under\u201d are correct or incorrect ?\n I. A contributing factor to \u201ctuck under\u201d is an aft movement of the centre of pressure of the wing.\n II. A contributing factor to \u201ctuck under\u201d is an increase in the downwash angle at the location of the\n horizontal stabiliser.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about \u201ctuck under\u201d are correct or incorrect ?\n I. \u201cTuck under\u201d is caused by an aft movement of the centre of pressure of the wing.\n II. \u201cTuck under\u201d is caused by a reduction in the downwash angle at the location of the horizontal\n stabiliser.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about VMCG determination are correct or incorrect ?\n I. During VMCG determination , nose wheel steering may be used.\n II. During VMCG determination , the CG should be on the aft limit.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about VMCG determination are correct or incorrect ?\n I. During VMCG determination , nose wheel steering may be used.\n II. During VMCG determination , the CG should be on the forward limit.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about VMCG determination are correct or incorrect ?\n I. In order to simulate a wet runway , nose wheel steering may not be used during VMCG determination.\n II. During VMCG determination , the CG should be on the aft limit.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about VMCG determination are correct or incorrect?\n I. In order to simulate a wet runway , nose wheel steering may not be used during VMCG determination.\n II. During VMCG determination , the CG should be on the forward limit.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about VMCG determination are correct or incorrect ?\n I. VMCG may be determined using both lateral and directional control.\n II. During VMCG determination , the lateral deviation from the runway centreline may be not more than\n 30 ft.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about VMCG determination are correct or incorrect ?\n I. VMCG may be determined using both lateral and directional control.\n II. During VMCG determination , the lateral deviation from the runway centreline may be not more than\n half the distance between the runway centreline and runway edge.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about VMCG determination are correct or incorrect ?\n I. VMCG must be determined using rudder control alone.\n II. During VMCG determination , the lateral deviation from the runway centreline may be not more than\n 30 ft.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about VMCG determination are correct or incorrect ?\n I. VMCG must be determined using rudder control alone.\n II. During VMCG determination , the lateral deviation from the runway centreline may be not more than\n half the distance between centreline and runway edge.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about weight or mass is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "In SI system the unit of measurement for mass is the kilogram.\n",
        "choiceone": "In SI system the unit of measurement for weight is the kilogram.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The mass of an object depends on the acceleration due to gravity.\n",
        "choicethree": "The weight of an object is independent of the acceleration due to gravity.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about weight or mass is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The mass of a body can be determined by dividing its weight by the acceleration due to gravity.\n",
        "choiceone": "The weight of a body can be determined by dividing the acceleration due to gravity by its mass.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The mass of a body can be determined by multiplying its weight by the acceleration due to gravity.\n",
        "choicethree": "The weight of a body can be determined by dividing its mass by the acceleration due to gravity.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about weight or mass is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "In the SI system the unit of measurement for weight is the Newton.\n",
        "choiceone": "The mass of an object depends on the acceleration due to gravity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The weight of an object is independent of the acceleration due to gravity.\n",
        "choicethree": "In the SI system the unit of measurement for weight is the kilogram.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about weight or mass is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The mass of an object is independent of the acceleration due to gravity.\n",
        "choiceone": "Mass = weight * volume.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The weight of an object is independent of the acceleration due to gravity.\n",
        "choicethree": "In SI system the unit of measurement for weight is the kilogram.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about weight or mass is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The weight of a body can be determined by multiplying its mass by the acceleration due to gravity.\n",
        "choiceone": "The weight of a body can be determined by dividing its mass by the acceleration due to gravity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The weight of a body can be determined by dividing the acceleration due to gravity by its mass.\n",
        "choicethree": "The mass of a body can be determined by multiplying its weight by the acceleration due to gravity.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about weight or mass is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The weight of an object depends on the acceleration due to gravity.\n",
        "choiceone": "The mass of an object depends on the acceleration due to gravity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Mass = weight * volume.\n",
        "choicethree": "In SI system the unit of measurement for weight is the kilogram.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about weight or mass is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Weight is a force.\n",
        "choiceone": "The weight of an object is independent of the acceleration due to gravity.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Mass = weight * volume.\n",
        "choicethree": "The mass of an object depends on the acceleration due to gravity.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about wing sweepback are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Decreasing wing sweepback decreases Mcrit.\n II. Decreasing wing sweepback decreases the drag divergence Mach number.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about wing sweepback are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Decreasing wing sweepback decreases Mcrit.\n II. Decreasing wing sweepback increases the drag divergence Mach number.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about wing sweepback are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Decreasing wing sweepback increases Mcrit.\n II. Decreasing wing sweepback decreases the drag divergence Mach number.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about wing sweepback are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Decreasing wing sweepback increases Mcrit.\n II. Decreasing wing sweepback increases the drag divergence Mach number.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about wing sweepback are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Increasing wing sweepback decreases Mcrit.\n II. Increasing wing sweepback decreases the drag divergence Mach number.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about wing sweepback are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Increasing wing sweepback decreases Mcrit.\n II. Increasing wing sweepback increases the drag divergence Mach number.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about wing sweepback are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Increasing wing sweepback increases Mcrit.\n II. Increasing wing sweepback decreases the drag divergence Mach number.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements about wing sweepback are correct or incorrect ?\n I. Increasing wing sweepback increases Mcrit.\n II. Increasing wing sweepback increases the drag divergence Mach number.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements are correct or incorrect regarding a sideslip , with the relative airflow coming from the left , on an\naeroplane that exhibits both directional and lateral stability ?\n I. The initial tendency of the nose of the aeroplane is to move to the left.\n II. The initial tendency of the left wing is to move down.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements are correct or incorrect regarding a sideslip , with the relative airflow coming from the left , on an\naeroplane that exhibits both directional and lateral stability ?\n I. The initial tendency of the nose of the aeroplane is to move to the left.\n II. The initial tendency of the right wing is to move down.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements are correct or incorrect regarding a sideslip , with the relative airflow coming from the left , on an\naeroplane that exhibits both directional and lateral stability ?\n I. The initial tendency of the nose of the aeroplane is to move to the right.\n II. The initial tendency of the left wing is to move down.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements are correct or incorrect regarding a sideslip , with the relative airflow coming from the left , on an\naeroplane that exhibits both directional and lateral stability ?\n I. The initial tendency of the nose of the aeroplane is to move to the right.\n II. The initial tendency of the right wing is to move down.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements are correct or incorrect regarding a sideslip , with the relative airflow coming from the right , on\nan aeroplane that exhibits both directional and lateral stability ?\n I. The initial tendency of the nose of the aeroplane is to move to the left.\n II. The initial tendency of the left wing is to move down.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements are correct or incorrect regarding a sideslip , with the relative airflow coming from the right , on\nan aeroplane that exhibits both directional and lateral stability ?\n I. The initial tendency of the nose of the aeroplane is to move to the left.\n II. The initial tendency of the right wing is to move down.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements are correct or incorrect regarding a sideslip , with the relative airflow coming from the right , on\nan aeroplane that exhibits both directional and lateral stability ?\n I. The initial tendency of the nose of the aeroplane is to move to the right.\n II. The initial tendency of the left wing is to move down.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements are correct or incorrect regarding a sideslip , with the relative airflow coming from the right , on\nan aeroplane that exhibits both directional and lateral stability ?\n I. The initial tendency of the nose of the aeroplane is to move to the right.\n II. The initial tendency of the right wing is to move down.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements concerning flight in turbulence is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The load factor in turbulence may fluctuate above and below 1 and can even become negative.\n",
        "choiceone": "In severe turbulence , speed should be reduced to approximately 1.2 VS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Above VB the aeroplane can never be overstressed by a gust.\n",
        "choicethree": "When encountering turbulence during flight , the speed should be adjusted to the desgn speed for maximum\n gust intensity VB.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements concerning flight in turbulence is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "VRA is the recommended turbulence penetration air speed.\n",
        "choiceone": "The load factor in turbulence may fluctuate above and below 1 , but will not become negative.\n",
        "choicetwo": "In severe turbulence , speed should be reduced to approximately 1.2 VS.\n",
        "choicethree": "VB is the recommended turbulence penetration air speed.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements concerning flight in turbulence is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "VB is the design speed for maximum gust intensity.\n",
        "choiceone": "In severe turbulence , speed should be reduced to approximately 1.2 VS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The load factor in turbulence cannot exceed the ultimate load factor.\n",
        "choicethree": "The load factor in turbulence may fluctuate above and below 1 , but will not become negative.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements concerning propellers is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The blade angle of a feathered propeller is approximately 90 degrees.\n",
        "choiceone": "An unfeathered propeller causes less drag than a feathered propeller.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The blade angle of a feathered propeller is approximately 0 degrees.\n",
        "choicethree": "A windmilling propeller causes less drag than a feathered propeller.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements concerning propellers is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "A feathered propeller causes less drag than a windmilling propeller.\n",
        "choiceone": "The blade angle of a feathered propeller is approximately 180 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A windmilling propeller causes less drag than a feathered propeller.\n",
        "choicethree": "The blade angle of a feathered propeller is approximately 0 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements concerning propellers is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "When compared with a non-feathered propeller , a feathered propeller improves the handling of a multi-\n engine aeroplane with one engine inoperative.\n",
        "choiceone": "The blade angle of a feathered propeller is approximately 180 degrees.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A windmilling propeller causes less drag than a feathered propeller.\n",
        "choicethree": "The blade angle of a feathered propeller is approximately 0 degrees.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these statements on shock stall is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Shock stall is a stall due to flow separation caused by a shock wave.\n",
        "choiceone": "Shock stall is caused by sudden loss of lift due to a rise in load factor.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Shock stall is a stall due to flow separation at high angles of attack.\n",
        "choicethree": "CLmax does not change as the Mach number increases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 081-6239A )\n Annex 081-6239A\n Which one of the bodies in motion ( all bodies have the same cross section area ) will have lowest drag ?\n",
        "answer": "Body c\n",
        "choiceone": "Body a\n",
        "choicetwo": "Body b\n",
        "choicethree": "Body d\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following statements about Bernoulli\u2019s theorem is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The dynamic pressure increases as static pressure decreases.\n",
        "choiceone": "The total pressure is zero when the velocity of the stream is zero.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The dynamic pressure is maximum in the stagnation point.\n",
        "choicethree": "The dynamic pressure decreases as static pressure decreases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following statements about the lift-to-drag ratio in straight and level flight is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "At the highest value of the lift/drag ratio the total drag is lowest.\n",
        "choiceone": "The highest value of the lift/drag ratio is reached when the lift is zero.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The lift/drag ratio always increases as the lift decreases.\n",
        "choicethree": "The highest value of the lift/drag ratio is reached when the lift is equal to the aircraft weight.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following systems suppresses the tendency to \u201cDutch roll\u201d ?\n",
        "answer": "Yaw damper.\n",
        "choiceone": "Roll spoilers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Spoiler mixer.\n",
        "choicethree": "Rudder limiter.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which part of an aeroplane provides the greatest positive contribution to the static longitudinal stability ?\n",
        "answer": "The horizontal tailplane.\n",
        "choiceone": "The engine.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The wing.\n",
        "choicethree": "The fuselage.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which part of the aeroplane has the largest effect on induced drag ?\n",
        "answer": "Wing tip.\n",
        "choiceone": "Landing gear.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Wing root junction.\n",
        "choicethree": "Engine cowling.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which phenomenon is counteracted with differential aileron deflection ?\n",
        "answer": "Adverse yaw.\n",
        "choiceone": "Turn co-ordination.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Aileron reversal.\n",
        "choicethree": "Sensitivity for spiral dive.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 081-6262A )\n Annex 081-6262A\n Which point in the diagram corresponds to the minimum ( zero thrust ) glide angle ?\n",
        "answer": "Point 2\n",
        "choiceone": "Point 3\n",
        "choicetwo": "Point 1\n",
        "choicethree": "Point 4\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 081-6262A )\n Annex 081-6262A\n Which point in the diagram gives the lowest speed in horizontal flight ?\n",
        "answer": "Point 4\n",
        "choiceone": "Point 2\n",
        "choicetwo": "Point 3\n",
        "choicethree": "Point 1\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 2 )\n Image 2\n Which point in the diagram gives the lowest speed in horizontal flight ?\n",
        "answer": "Point d\n",
        "choiceone": "Point a\n",
        "choicetwo": "Point b\n",
        "choicethree": "Point c\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 081-6262A )\n Annex 081-6262A\n Which point marks the value for minimum sink rate ( assume zero thrust ) ?\n",
        "answer": "Point 3\n",
        "choiceone": "Point 2\n",
        "choicetwo": "Point 1\n",
        "choicethree": "Point 4\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 081-6261A )\n Annex 081-6261A\n Which point shown in the figure corresponds with CL for minimum horizontal flight speed ?\n",
        "answer": "Point d\n",
        "choiceone": "Point b\n",
        "choicetwo": "Point a\n",
        "choicethree": "Point c\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which speeds are used and in which sequence if an emergency descent is carried out from the normal cruise altitude of a\nlarge jet transport aeroplane ?\n",
        "answer": "MMO , VMO.\n",
        "choiceone": "VMO , MMO.\n",
        "choicetwo": "MNE , VNE.\n",
        "choicethree": "MD , VD.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about a jet transport aeroplane is correct during take-off with the cg at the forward limit and the trimmable\nhorizontal stabiliser ( THS ) positioned at the maximum allowable aeroplane nose down position ?\n",
        "answer": "The rotation will require extra stick force.\n",
        "choiceone": "Rotation will be normal.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Early nose wheel raising will take place.\n",
        "choicethree": "If the THS position is just within the limits of the green band , the take off warning system will be activated.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about a primary control surface controlled by a servo tab , is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The position is undetermined during taxiing , in particular with tailwind.\n",
        "choiceone": "The control effectiveness of the primary surface is increased by servo tab deflection.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Due to the effectiveness of the servo tab the control surface area can be smaller.\n",
        "choicethree": "The servo tab can also be used as a balance tab.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about a propeller is correct ?\n I. Asymmetric blade effect increases when engine power is increased.\n II. Asymmetric blade effect increases when the angle between the propeller axis and airflow through the\n propeller disc increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about a propeller is correct ?\n I. Asymmetric blade effect increases when engine power is increased.\n II. Asymmetric blade effect is independent of the angle between the propeller axis and the airflow\n through the propeller disc.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about a propeller is correct ?\n I. Asymmetric blade effect increases when engine power is increased.\n II. Asymmetric blade effect reduces when the angle between the propeller axis and the airflow through\n the propeller disc increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about a propeller is correct ?\n I. Asymmetric blade effect is unaffected when engine power is increased.\n II. Asymmetric blade effect increases when the angle between the propeller axis and the airflow through\n the propeller disc increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about a propeller is correct ?\n I. Asymmetric blade effect is unaffected when engine power is increased.\n II. Asymmetric blade effect is independent of the angle between the propeller axis and the airflow\n through the propeller disc.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about a propeller is correct?\n I. Asymmetric blade effect is unaffected when engine power is increased.\n II. Asymmetric blade effect reduces when the angle between the propeller axis and the airflow through\n the propeller disc increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about a propeller is correct ?\n I. Asymmetric blade effect reduces when engine power is increased.\n II. Asymmetric blade effect increases when the angle between the propeller axis and the airflow through\n the propeller disc increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about a propeller is correct ?\n I. Asymmetric blade effect reduces when engine power is increased.\n II. Asymmetric blade effect is independent of the angle between the propeller axis and the airflow\n through the propeller disc.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about a propeller is correct ?\n I. Asymmetric blade effect reduces when engine power is increased.\n II. Asymmetric blade effect reduces when the angle between the propeller axis and the airflow through\n the propeller disc increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement , about an aeroplane entering ground effect at constant angle of attack , is correct ?\n I. The lift coefficient CL decreases.\n II. The induced drag coefficient CDi decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement , about an aeroplane entering ground effect at constant angle of attack , is correct ?\n I. The lift coefficient CL decreases.\n II. The induced drag coefficient CDi increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement , about an aeroplane entering ground effect at constant angle of attack , is correct ?\n I. The lift coefficient CL decreases.\n II. The induced drag coefficient CDi remains constant.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement , about an aeroplane entering ground effect at constant angle of attack , is correct ?\n I. The lift coefficient CL increases.\n II. The induced drag coefficient CDi decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement , about an aeroplane entering ground effect at constant angle of attack , is correct ?\n I. The lift coefficient CL increases.\n II. The induced drag coefficient CDi increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement , about an aeroplane entering ground effect at constant angle of attack , is correct ?\n I. The lift coefficient CL increases.\n II. The induced drag coefficient CDi remains constant.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement , about an aeroplane entering ground effect at constant angle of attack , is correct ?\n I. The lift coefficient CL remains constant.\n II. The induced drag coefficient CDi decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement , about an aeroplane entering ground effect at constant angle of attack , is correct ?\n I. The lift coefficient CL remains constant.\n II. The induced drag coefficient CDi increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about an aeroplane entering ground effect is correct ?\n I. The downwash angle decreases.\n II. The induced angle of attack decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about an aeroplane entering ground effect is correct ?\n I. The downwash angle decreases.\n II. The induced angle of attack increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about an aeroplane entering ground effect is correct ?\n I. The downwash angle decreases.\n II. The induced angle of attack remains constant.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about an aeroplane entering ground effect is correct ?\n I. The downwash angle increases.\n II. The induced angle of attack decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about an aeroplane entering ground effect is correct ?\n I. The downwash angle increases.\n II. The induced angle of attack increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about an aeroplane entering ground effect is correct ?\n I. The downwash angle increases.\n II. The induced angle of attack remains constant.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about an aeroplane entering ground effect is correct ?\n I. The downwash angle remains constant.\n II. The induced angle of attack decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about an aeroplane entering ground effect is correct ?\n I. The downwash angle remains constant.\n II. The induced angle of attack increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement , about an aeroplane leaving ground effect at constant angle of attack , is correct ?\n I. The lift coefficient CL decreases.\n II. The induced drag coefficient CDi decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement , about an aeroplane leaving ground effect at constant angle of attack , is correct ?\n I. The lift coefficient CL decreases.\n II. The induced drag coefficient CDi increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement , about an aeroplane leaving ground effect at constant angle of attack , is correct ?\n I. The lift coefficient CL decreases.\n II. The induced drag coefficient CDi remains constant.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement , about an aeroplane leaving ground effect at constant angle of attack , is correct ?\n I. The lift coefficient CL increases.\n II. The induced drag coefficient CDi decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement , about an aeroplane leaving ground effect at constant angle of attack , is correct ?\n I. The lift coefficient CL increases.\n II. The induced drag coefficient CDi increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement , about an aeroplane leaving ground effect at constant angle of attack , is correct ?\n I. The lift coefficient CL increases.\n II. The induced drag coefficient CDi remains constant.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement , about an aeroplane leaving ground effect at constant angle of attack , is correct ?\n I. The lift coefficient CL remains constant.\n II. The induced drag coefficient CDi decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement , about an aeroplane leaving ground effect at constant angle of attack , is correct ?\n I. The lift coefficient CL remains constant.\n II. The induced drag coefficient CDi increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about an aeroplane leaving ground effect is correct ?\n I. The downwash angle decreases.\n II. The induced angle of attack decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about an aeroplane leaving ground effect is correct ?\n I. The downwash angle decreases.\n II. The induced angle of attack increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about an aeroplane leaving ground effect is correct ?\n I. The downwash angle decreases.\n II. The induced angle of attack remains constant.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about an aeroplane leaving ground effect is correct?\n I. The downwash angle increases.\n II. The induced angle of attack decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about an aeroplane leaving ground effect is correct ?\n I. The downwash angle increases.\n II. The induced angle of attack increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about an aeroplane leaving ground effect is correct ?\n I. The downwash angle increases.\n II. The induced angle of attack remains constant.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about an aeroplane leaving ground effect is correct ?\n I. The downwash angle remains constant.\n II. The induced angle of attack decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about an aeroplane leaving ground effect is correct ?\n I. The downwash angle remains constant.\n II. The induced angle of attack increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about elevators is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The elevator is the primary control surface for control about the lateral axis and is operated by a forward or\n backward movement of the control wheel or stick.\n",
        "choiceone": "The elevator is the primary control surface for control about the longitudinal axis and is operated by a\n forward or backward movement of the control wheel or stick.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The elevator is the primary control surface for control about the longitudinal axis and is operated by a left or\n right rotation of the control wheel.\n",
        "choicethree": "The elevator is used only to trim an aeroplane and is normally operated by a dedicated control wheel , which\n is usually situated close to the throttle.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about induced drag and tip vortices is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The flow direction at the upper side of the wing has a component in wing root direction , the flow at the\n underside of the wing in wing tip direction.\n",
        "choiceone": "The flow direction at the upper and under side of the wing , both deviate in wing tip direction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Tip vortices can be diminished by vortex generators.\n",
        "choicethree": "The wing tip vortices and the induced drag decrease at increasing angle of attack.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about induced drag is correct ?\n I. Induced drag increases as angle at attack increases.\n II. At constant load factor , induced drag decreases with increasing aeroplane mass.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about minimum control speed is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "VMCA depends on the airport density altitude , and the location of the engine on the aeroplane ( aft fuselage\n or wing ).\n",
        "choiceone": "The nose wheel steering control may used to determine VMCG.\n",
        "choicetwo": "VMCA may not be lower than VMCL.\n",
        "choicethree": "Crosswind is taken into account to determine VMCG.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about minimum control speed is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "VMCA depends on the airport density altitude , and the location of the engine on the aeroplane ( aft fuselage\n or wing ).\n",
        "choiceone": "The nose wheel steering control may used to determine VMCG.\n",
        "choicetwo": "VMCL is determined by maximum rudder only.\n",
        "choicethree": "Crosswind is taken into account to determine VMCG.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about negative tail stall is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "When negative tail stall occurs , the aeroplane will show an uncontrollable pitch-down moment.\n",
        "choiceone": "Negative tail stall is a stall of the tailplane when the aerodynamic force is in upward direction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "When negative tail stall occurs , the aeroplane will show an uncontrollable pitch-up moment.\n",
        "choicethree": "Negative tail stall is a stall of the fin with a negative sideslip angle ( nose pointing to the right of the relative\n airflow ).\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about propeller icing is correct ?\n I. Propeller icing reduces blade element drag and increases blade element lift.\n II. Propeller icing reduces propeller efficiency.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , I is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , I is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , I is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , I is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about propeller icing is correct ?\n I. Propeller icing increases blade element drag and reduces blade element lift.\n II. Propeller icing does not affect propeller efficiency.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , I is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , I is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , I is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , I is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about propeller icing is correct ?\n I. Propeller icing increases blade element drag and reduces blade element lift.\n II. Propeller icing reduces propeller efficiency.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about propeller icing is correct ?\n I. Propeller icing reduces blade element drag and increases blade element lift.\n II. Propeller icing does not affect propeller efficiency.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about propeller noise is correct ?\n I. Propeller noise decreases when the blade tip speed increases.\n II. For a given engine and propeller blade shape , a decrease in the number of propeller blades allows for\n a reduction in propeller noise.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about propeller noise is correct?\n I. Propeller noise decreases when the blade tip speed increases.\n II. For a given engine and propeller blade shape , an increase in the number of propeller blades allows for\n a reduction in propeller noise.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about propeller noise is correct ?\n I. Propeller noise increases when the blade tip speed increases.\n II. For a given engine and propeller blade shape , a decrease in the number of propeller blades allows for\n a reduction in propeller noise.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about propeller noise is correct ?\n I. Propeller noise increases when the blade tip speed increases.\n II. For a given engine and propeller blade shape , an increase in the number of propeller blades allows for\n a reduction in propeller noise.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about propeller noise is correct ?\n I. Propeller noise remains the same when the blade tip speed increases.\n II. For a given engine and propeller blade shape , a decrease in the number of propeller blades allows for\n a reduction in propeller noise.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement about stick force per g is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The stick force per g must have both an upper and lower limit in order to ensure acceptable control\n characteristics.\n",
        "choiceone": "If the slope of the Fe-n line becomes negative , generally speaking this is not a problem for control of an\n aeroplane.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The stick force per g increases , when centre of gravity is moved aft.\n",
        "choicethree": "The stick force per g can only be corrected by means of electronic devices ( stability augmentation ) in case\n of an unacceptable value.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement , about the effects on drag of fitting external tip tanks to the wings of an aeroplane , is correct ?\n I. Parasite drag decreases.\n II. Induced drag decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement , about the effects on drag of fitting external tip tanks to the wings of an aeroplane , is correct ?\n I. Parasite drag decreases.\n II. Induced drag increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement , about the effects on drag of fitting external tip tanks to the wings of an aeroplane , is correct ?\n I. Parasite drag increases.\n II. Induced drag decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement , about the effects on drag of fitting external tip tanks to the wings of an aeroplane , is correct ?\n I. Parasite drag increases.\n II. Induced drag increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement , about the effects on drag of removing external tip tanks from the wings of an aeroplane , is correct ?\n I. Parasite drag decreases.\n II. Induced drag decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement , about the effects on drag of removing external tip tanks from the wings of an aeroplane , is correct ?\n I. Parasite drag decreases.\n II. Induced drag increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement , about the effects on drag of removing external tip tanks from the wings of an aeroplane , is correct ?\n I. Parasite drag increases.\n II. Induced drag decreases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement , about the effects on drag of removing external tip tanks to the wings of an aeroplane , is correct ?\n I. Parasite drag increases.\n II. Induced drag increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement concerning longitudinal stability and control is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "A bob weight and a down spring have the same effect on the stick force stability.\n",
        "choiceone": "A bob weight reduces the stick force per g.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A down spring has the same function as a stick pusher.\n",
        "choicethree": "A down spring only improves the manoeuvre stability.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement concerning sweepback is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Sweepback provides a positive contribution to static lateral stability.\n",
        "choiceone": "Sweepback increases speed stability at Mach numbers above Mcrit.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Sweepback is mainly intended to increase static directional stability.\n",
        "choicethree": "A disadvantages of sweepback is that it decreases Mcrit.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement concerning the local flow pattern around a wing is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "By fitting winglets to the wing tip , the strength of the wing tip vortices is reduced which in turn reduces\n induced drag.\n",
        "choiceone": "Sweepback reduces drag since , compared with a straight wing of equal area , the span increases.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Vortex generators on the wing partially block the spanwise flow over the wing leading to a reduction in\n induced drag.\n",
        "choicethree": "Slat extension , at a constant angle of attack and normal extension speeds , will increase the lift coefficient ,\n which will also increase the induced drag coefficient.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement in respect of a trimmable horizontal stabiliser is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "An aeroplane with a forward cg requires the stabiliser leading edge to be lower than for one with an aft cg in\n the same trimmed condition.\n",
        "choiceone": "An aeroplane with a forward cg requires the stabiliser leading edge to be higher than for one with an aft cg in\n the same trimmed condition.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Because take-off speeds do not vary with centre of gravity location , the need for stabiliser adjustment is\n dependant on flap position only.\n",
        "choicethree": "At the forward CG limit , stabiliser trim is adjusted fully nose down to obtain maximum elevator authority at\n rotation during take-off.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is about CG limits is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The forward CG limit is mainly determined by the amount of pitch control available from the elevator.\n",
        "choiceone": "The aft CG limit is determined by the maximum elevator deflection available.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The forward CG limit is determined by stability considerations only.\n",
        "choicethree": "If the aft CG limit is correctly chosen , the forward CG limit is automatically determined as well.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n I. A propeller with a small blade angle is referred to as being in coarse pitch.\n II. A propeller with a large blade angle is referred to as being in fine pitch.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n I. A propeller with a small blade angle is referred to as being in fine pitch.\n II. A propeller with significant blade twist is referred to as being in coarse pitch.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n I. A propeller with little blade twist is referred to as being in fine pitch.\n II. A propeller with a large blade angle is referred to as being in coarse pitch.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n I. A propeller with little blade twist is referred to as being in fine pitch.\n II. A propeller with significant blade twist is referred to as being in coarse pitch.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n I. A stick pusher activates at a higher angle of attack than a stick shaker.\n II. A stick pusher prevents the pilot from increasing the angle of attack further.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n I. A stick pusher activates at a higher angle of attack than a stick shaker.\n II. A stick shaker prevents the pilot from increasing the angle of attack further.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n I. A stick pusher activates at a lower angle of attack than a stick shaker.\n II. A stick pusher prevents the pilot from increasing the angle of attack further.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n I. A stick pusher activates at a lower angle of attack than a stick shaker.\n II. A stick shaker prevents the pilot from increasing the angle of attack further.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n I. At a given RPM the propeller efficiency of a fixed pitch propeller is maximum at only one value of\n TAS.\n II. A constant speed propeller maintains near maximum efficiency over a wider range of aeroplane speeds\n than a fixed pitch propeller.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n I. At a given RPM the propeller efficiency of a fixed pitch propeller is maximum at only one value of\n TAS.\n II. A fixed pitch propeller maintains near maximum efficiency over a wider range of aeroplane speeds\n than a constant speed propeller.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n I. On fully hydraulic powered flight controls there is no need for mass balancing.\n II. On fully hydraulic powered flight controls there is no need for trim tabs.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n I. Propeller gyroscopic effect occurs during aeroplane pitch changes.\n II. Propeller gyroscopic effect is most noticeable during low speed flight at high propeller RPM.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n I. Propeller gyroscopic effect occurs during aeroplane pitch changes.\n II. Propeller gyroscopic effect is most noticeable during low speed flight at low propeller RPM.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n I. Propeller gyroscopic effect occurs during aeroplane yaw changes.\n II. Propeller gyroscopic effect is most noticeable during low speed flight at high propeller RPM.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n I. Propeller gyroscopic effect occurs during aeroplane yaw changes.\n II. Propeller gyroscopic effect is most noticeable during low speed flight at low propeller RPM.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n I. Propeller gyroscopic effect occurs during flight at constant aeroplane attitude.\n II. Propeller gyroscopic effect is most noticeable during low speed flight at high propeller RPM.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n I. Propeller gyroscopic effect occurs during flight at constant aeroplane attitude.\n II. Propeller gyroscopic effect is most noticeable during low speed flight at low propeller RPM.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n I. Stall speeds are determined with the CG at the aft limit.\n II. Minimum control speeds are determined with the CG at the aft limit.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n I. Stall speeds are determined with the CG at the aft limit.\n II. Minimum control speeds are determined with the CG at the forward limit.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n I. Stall speeds are determined with the CG at the forward limit.\n II. Minimum control speeds are determined with the CG at the aft limit.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n I. Stall speeds are determined with the CG at the forward limit.\n II. Minimum control speeds are determined with the CG at the forward limit.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n I. Stick force per g is independent of altitude.\n II. Stick force per g increases when the centre of gravity moves forward.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "During a phugoid altitude varies significantly , but during a short period oscillation it remains approximately\n constant.\n",
        "choiceone": "During both a phugoid and a short period oscillation altitude varies significantly.\n",
        "choicetwo": "During both a phugoid and a short period oscillation altitude remains approximately constant.\n",
        "choicethree": "During a phugoid altitude remains approximately constant , but during a short period oscillation it varies\n significantly.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Dynamic stability is possible only when the aeroplane is statically stable about the relevant axis.\n",
        "choiceone": "Dynamic stability about the lateral axis implies that after being displaced from original equilibrium\n condition , the aeroplane will return to that condition without oscillation.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A dynamically stable aeroplane would be almost impossible to fly manually.\n",
        "choicethree": "Static stability means that the aeroplane is also dynamically stable about the relevant axis.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Flap extension causes a reduction in stall speed and the maximum glide distance.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flap extension has no influence on the minimum rate of descent , as only TAS has to be taken into account.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Spoiler extension causes a reduction in stall speed and the minimum rate of descent , but increases the\n minimum descent angle.\n",
        "choicethree": "Flap extension will increase ( CL/CD ) max thus causing a reduction in the minimum rate descent.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Spoiler extension increases the stallspeed , the minimum rate of descent and the minimum angle of descent.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flap extension has no effect on the minimum rate of descent as this is only affected by TAS.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Flap extension reduces the maximum lift/drag ratio thus reducing the minimum rate of descent.\n",
        "choicethree": "Flap extension reduces the stallspeed , which increases the maximum glide distance.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The flow on the upper surface of the wing has a component in wing root direction.\n",
        "choiceone": "The flows on the upper and lower surfaces of the wing are both in wing tip direction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Tip vortices and induced drag decrease with increasing angle of attack.\n",
        "choicethree": "Tip vortices can be diminished by vortex generators.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "The short period oscillation should always be heavily damped.\n",
        "choiceone": "The phugoid should always be heavily damped.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A slightly unstable shot period oscillation is no problem for an aeroplane.\n",
        "choicethree": "When the phugoid is slightly unstable , an aeroplane becomes uncontrollable.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "As the angle of attack increases , the stagnation point on the wing\u2019s profile moves downwards.\n",
        "choiceone": "The stagnation point is always situated on the chordline , the centre of pressure is not.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The centre of pressure is the point on the wing\u2019s leading edge where the airflow splits up.\n",
        "choicethree": "The stagnation point is another name for centre of pressure.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct about a normal shock wave ?\n",
        "answer": "The airflow changes from supersonic to subsonic.\n",
        "choiceone": "The airflow changes direction.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The airflow expands when passing the aerofoil.\n",
        "choicethree": "The airflow changes from subsonic to supersonic.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct about a spring tab ?\n",
        "answer": "At high IAS it behaves like a servo tab.\n",
        "choiceone": "Its main purpose is to increase stick force per g.\n",
        "choicetwo": "At low IAS it behaves like a servo tab.\n",
        "choicethree": "At high IAS it behaves like a fixed extension of the elevator.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct about an aeroplane , that has experienced a left engine failure and continues afterwards in straight\nand level cruise flight with wings level ?\n",
        "answer": "turn indicator neutral , slip indicator neutral.\n",
        "choiceone": "turn indicator left of neutral , slip indicator left of neutral.\n",
        "choicetwo": "turn indicator neutral , slip indicator left of neutral.\n",
        "choicethree": "turn indicator left of neutral , slip indicator neutral.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct about an expansion wave in supersonic flow ?\n 1. The static temperature in front of an expansion wave is higher than the static temperature behind it.\n 2. The speed in front of an expansion wave is higher than the speed behind it.\n",
        "answer": "1 is correct and 2 is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 and 2 are correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 is incorrect and 2 is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "1 and 2 are incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct about an expansion wave in a supersonic flow ?\n 1. The density in front of an expansion wave is higher than behind it.\n 2. The static pressure in front of an expansion wave is higher than behind it.\n",
        "answer": "1 and 2 are correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 is incorrect and 2 is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 is correct and 2 is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "1 and 2 are incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct about the gust load on an aeroplane ? ( IAS and all other factors of importance remaining\nconstant )\n 1. The gust load increases , when the weight decreases.\n 2. The gust load increases , when the altitude increases.\n",
        "answer": "1 is correct and 2 is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 is incorrect and 2 is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 and 2 are correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "1 and 2 are incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct about the gust load on an aeroplane , while all other factors of importance remain constant ?\n I. When the mass increases , the gust load increases.\n II. When the altitude decreases , the gust load increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct about the laminar and turbulent boundary layer ;\n",
        "answer": "friction drag is lower in the laminar layer.\n",
        "choiceone": "friction drag will be equal in both types of layers.\n",
        "choicetwo": "separation point will occur earlier in the turbulent layer.\n",
        "choicethree": "friction drag is lower in the turbulent layer.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct at the speed for minimum drag ( subsonic ) ?\n",
        "answer": "The gliding angle is minimum ( assume zero thrust ).\n",
        "choiceone": "Propeller aeroplanes fly at that speed at max. endurance.\n",
        "choicetwo": "The CL/CD ratio is minimum ( assume zero thrust ).\n",
        "choicethree": "Induced drag is greater than the parasite drag.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct for a propeller of given diameter and at constant RPM ?\n I. Assuming blade shape does not change power absorption increases if the number of blades increases.\n II. Power absorption decreases if the mean chord of the blades increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct for a propeller of given diameter and at constant RPM ?\n I. Assuming blade shape does not change power absorption increases if the number of blades increases.\n II. Power absorption increases if the mean chord of the blades increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct for a propeller of given diameter and at constant RPM ?\n I. Assuming blade shape does not change power absorption is independent of the number of blades.\n II. Power absorption decreases if the mean chord of the blades increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct for a propeller of given diameter and at constant RPM ?\n I. Assuming blade shape does not change power absorption is independent of the number of blades.\n II. Power absorption increases if the mean chord of the blades increases.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct for a side slip condition at constant speed and side slip angle , where the geometric dihedral of an\naeroplane is increased ?\n",
        "answer": "the required lateral control force increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "the required lateral control force does not change.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the required lateral control force decreases.\n",
        "choicethree": "the stick force per g decreases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct in respect of Cl and angle of attack ?\n",
        "answer": "For a symmetrical aerofoil , if the angle of attack is zero , Cl is zero.\n",
        "choiceone": "For an asymmetrical aerofoil with positive camber , if the angle of attack is greater than zero , Cl is zero.\n",
        "choicetwo": "For a symmetrical aerofoil , if the angle of attack is zero , Cl is not zero.\n",
        "choicethree": "For an asymmetrical aerofoil , if the angle of attack is zero , Cl is zero.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct regarding a propeller ?\n I. Increasing tip speed to supersonic speed does not affect propeller noise.\n II. Increasing tip speed to supersonic speed decreases propeller efficiency.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct regarding a propeller ?\n I. Increasing tip speed to supersonic speed does not affect propeller noise.\n II. Increasing tip speed to supersonic speed increases propeller efficiency.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct regarding a propeller ?\n I. Increasing tip speed to supersonic speed increases propeller noise.\n II. Increasing tip speed to supersonic speed decreases propeller efficiency.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct regarding a propeller ?\n I. Increasing tip speed to supersonic speed increases propeller noise.\n II. Increasing tip speed to supersonic speed increases propeller efficiency.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct regarding a shockwave on a lift generating wing ?\n",
        "answer": "It moves slightly aft when an aileron is deflected downward.\n",
        "choiceone": "It is located at the greatest wing thickness when the aeroplane reaches the speed of sound.\n",
        "choicetwo": "It reaches its highest strength when flying at the critical Mach number.\n",
        "choicethree": "It moves forward when the Mach number is increased.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct regarding a windmilling propeller on a multi-engine aeroplane ?\n",
        "answer": "The windmilling drag is much higher than for a feathered propeller.\n",
        "choiceone": "The drag of a windmilling and a feathered propeller is almost the same.\n",
        "choicetwo": "A windmilling propeller hardly affects low speed controllability.\n",
        "choicethree": "The windmilling drag is only significant at negative blade angles.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct regarding Cl angle of attack ?\n",
        "answer": "For a symmetrical aerofoil section , if the alpha is zero , Cl is zero.\n",
        "choiceone": "For an asymmetrical aerofoil section , if the alpha is zero , Cl is zero.\n",
        "choicetwo": "For a symmetrical aerofoil section , if the alpha is zero , Cl is not zero.\n",
        "choicethree": "For an asymmetrical aerofoil section with positive camber , if the alpha is greater than zero , Cl is zero.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct regarding the gyroscopic effect of a clockwise rotating propeller on a single engine aeroplane ?\n I. Pitch down produces left yaw.\n II. Left yaw produces pitch down.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct regarding the gyroscopic effect of a clockwise rotating propeller on a single engine aeroplane ?\n I. Pitch down produces left yaw.\n II. Left yaw produces pitch up.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct regarding the gyroscopic effect of a clockwise rotating propeller on a single engine aeroplane ?\n I. Pitch down produces right yaw.\n II. Left yaw produces pitch down.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct regarding the gyroscopic effect of a clockwise rotating propeller on a single engine aeroplane ?\n I. Pitch down produces right yaw.\n II. Left yaw produces pitch up.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct regarding the gyroscopic effect of a clockwise rotating propeller on a single engine aeroplane ?\n I. Pitch up produces left yaw.\n II. Right yaw produces pitch down.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct regarding the gyroscopic effect of a clockwise rotating propeller on a single engine aeroplane ?\n I. Pitch up produces left yaw.\n II. Right yaw produces pitch up.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct regarding the gyroscopic effect of a clockwise rotating propeller on a single engine aeroplane ?\n I. Pitch up produces right yaw.\n II. Right yaw produces pitch down.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct regarding the gyroscopic effect of a clockwise rotating propeller on a single engine aeroplane ?\n I. Pitch up produces right yaw.\n II. Right yaw produces pitch up.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 17 )\n Image 17\n Which statement is correct regarding the pitching moment coefficient Cm versus angle of attack diagram ?\n",
        "answer": "Line 4 shows an aeroplane with increasing static longitudinal stability at very high angles af attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "Line 4 shows an aeroplane with a greater static longitudinal stability at low angles af attack than that shown\n in line 3.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Line 3 shows an aeroplane with increasing static longitudinal stability at high angles af attack.\n",
        "choicethree": "Line 1 shows an aeroplane with increasing static longitudinal stability at very high angles af attack.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 17 )\n Image 17\n Which statement is correct regarding the pitching moment coefficient Cm versus angle of attack diagram ?\n",
        "answer": "Line 3 shows an aeroplane with greater static longitudinal stability at low angles af attack than that shown\n in line 4.\n",
        "choiceone": "Line 1 shows an aeroplane with increasing static longitudinal stability at very high angles af attack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Line 4 shows an aeroplane with reducing static longitudinal stability at very high angles af attack.\n",
        "choicethree": "Line 3 shows an aeroplane with increasing static longitudinal stability at very high angles af attack.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 17 )\n Image 17\n Which statement is correct regarding the pitching moment coefficient Cm versus angle of attack diagram ?\n",
        "answer": "Line 3 shows an aeroplane with reducing static longitudinal stability at high angles af attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "Line 4 shows an aeroplane with greater static longitudinal stability at low angles af attack than that shown\n in line 3.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Line 4 shows an aeroplane with reducing static longitudinal stability at very high angles af attack.\n",
        "choicethree": "Line 1 shows an aeroplane with increasing static longitudinal stability at very high angles af attack.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( Refer to Image 17 )\n Image 17\n Which statement is correct regarding the pitching moment coefficient Cm versus angle of attack diagram ?\n",
        "answer": "Line 1 shows an aeroplane with reducing static longitudinal instability at very high angles af attack.\n",
        "choiceone": "Line 4 shows an aeroplane with reducing static longitudinal stability at very high angles af attack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Line 3 shows an aeroplane with increasing static longitudinal stability at high angles af attack.\n",
        "choicethree": "Line 4 shows an aeroplane with a greater static longitudinal stability at low angles af attack than that shown\n in line 3.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct when comparing a fixed pitch propeller with a constant speed propeller ?\n I. A constant speed propeller improves propeller efficiency over a range of cruise speeds.\n II. A coarse fixed pitch propeller is more efficient during take-off.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct when comparing a fixed pitch propeller with a constant speed propeller ?\n I. A constant speed propeller reduces fuel consumption over a range of cruise speeds.\n II. A constant speed propeller improves take-off performance as compared with a coarse fixed pitch\n propeller.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct when comparing a fixed pitch propeller with a constant speed propeller ?\n I. A constant speed propeller reduces fuel consumption over a range of cruise speeds.\n II. A coarse fixed pitch propeller is more efficient during take-off.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct when comparing a fixed pitch propeller with a constant speed propeller ?\n I. A fixed pitch propeller improves propeller efficiency over a range of cruise speeds.\n II. A coarse fixed pitch propeller is more efficient during take-off.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement is correct when comparing a fixed pitch propeller with a constant speed propeller ?\n I. A fixed pitch propeller improves propeller efficiency over a range of cruise speeds.\n II. A constant speed propeller improves take-off performance as compared with a coarse fixed pitch\n propeller.\n",
        "answer": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement on dynamic longitudinal stability of a conventional aeroplane is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Damping of the phugoid is normally very weak.\n",
        "choiceone": "Speed remains constant during one period of the phugoid.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Damping of the short period oscillation is normally very weak.\n",
        "choicethree": "Period time of the phugoid is normally 5 sec.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement regarding the gust load factor on an aeroplane is correct ( all other factors of importance being constant ) ?\n 1. Increasing the aspect-ratio of the wing will increase the gust load factor.\n 2. Increasing the speed will increase the gust load factor.\n",
        "answer": "1 and 2 are correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 is incorrect and 2 is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "1 and 2 are incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "1 is correct and 2 is incorrect.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement regarding the manoeuvre and gust load diagram in the clean configuration is correct ?\n I. The gust load diagram has a symmetrical shape with respect to the n = 1 line for speeds above VB.\n II. The manoeuvre load diagram does not extend beyond the speed VC.\n",
        "answer": "I is correct , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choiceone": "I is incorrect , II is correct.\n",
        "choicetwo": "I is incorrect , II is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "I is correct , II is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statement with respect to the speed of sound is correct ?\n",
        "answer": "Varies with the square root of the absolute temperature.\n",
        "choiceone": "Is independent of altitude.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Doubles if the temperature increases from 9\u00b0 to 36\u00b0 Centigrade.\n",
        "choicethree": "Increases always if the density of the air decreases.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which statements are correct for a straight steady climb ?\n 1. lift is less than weight.\n 2. lift is greater than weight.\n 3. load factor is less than 1.\n 4. load factor is greater than 1.\n 5. lift is equal to weight.\n 6. load factor is equal to 1.\n Which of the following lists all the correct statements ?\n",
        "answer": "1 and 3.\n",
        "choiceone": "1 and 6.\n",
        "choicetwo": "2 and 4.\n",
        "choicethree": "5 and 6.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which three aerodynamic means decrease manoeuvring stick forces ?\n",
        "answer": "Servo tab - horn balance - spring tab.\n",
        "choiceone": "Spring tab - horn balance - bobweight.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Spring tab - trim tab - mass balancing weight.\n",
        "choicethree": "Servo tab - trim tab - balance tab.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of buffet will occur if a jet aeroplane slowly accelerates in level flight from its cruise speed in still air at high\naltitude ?\n",
        "answer": "Mach buffet.\n",
        "choiceone": "Flutter speed buffet.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Accelerated stall buffet.\n",
        "choicethree": "Low speed buffet.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 081-6269A )\n Annex 081-6269A\n Which type of flap is shown in the picture ?\n",
        "answer": "Fowler flap\n",
        "choiceone": "Split flap\n",
        "choicetwo": "Plain flap\n",
        "choicethree": "Double slotted flap\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "( For this question use annex 081-6270A )\n Annex 081-6270A\n Which type of flap is shown in the picture ?\n",
        "answer": "Split flap\n",
        "choiceone": "Plain flap\n",
        "choicetwo": "Fowler flap\n",
        "choicethree": "Single slotted flap\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of stall has the largest associated angle of attack ?\n",
        "answer": "Deep stall.\n",
        "choiceone": "Low speed stall.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Accelerated stall.\n",
        "choicethree": "Shock stall.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which wing design feature decreases the static lateral stability of an aeroplane ?\n",
        "answer": "Anhedral.\n",
        "choiceone": "Increased wing span.\n",
        "choicetwo": "High wing.\n",
        "choicethree": "Dihedral.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "While flying under icing conditions , the largest ice build-up will occur , principally , on ;\n",
        "answer": "the frontal areas of the aircraft.\n",
        "choiceone": "the upper and lower rudder surfaces.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the pitot and static probes only.\n",
        "choicethree": "the upper and lower surfaces on the rear of the wing.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whilst flying at a constant IAS and at n = 1 , as the aeroplane mass decreases the value of Mcrit ;\n",
        "answer": "increases.\n",
        "choiceone": "is independent of the angle of attack.\n",
        "choicetwo": "decreases.\n",
        "choicethree": "remains constant.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whilst maintaining straight and level flight with a lift coefficient CL=1 , what will be the new approximate value of CL after\nthe speed is increased by 30% ?\n",
        "answer": "0.60\n",
        "choiceone": "0.30\n",
        "choicetwo": "0.50\n",
        "choicethree": "0.25\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whilst maintaining straight and level flight with a lift coefficient CL=1 , what will be the new value of CL after the speed\nhas doubled ?\n",
        "answer": "0.25\n",
        "choiceone": "1.00\n",
        "choicetwo": "2.00\n",
        "choicethree": "0.50\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why is a propeller blade twisted from root to tip ?\n",
        "answer": "To maintain a constant angle of attack along the whole length of the propeller blade.\n",
        "choiceone": "To ensure that the root produces most thrust.\n",
        "choicetwo": "To ensure the angle of attack is greatest at the tip.\n",
        "choicethree": "To ensure that the tip produces most thrust.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why is VMCG determined with the nosewheel steering disconnected ?\n",
        "answer": "Because the value of VMCG must also be applicable on wet and/or slippery runways.\n",
        "choiceone": "Because it must be possible to abort the take-off even after the nosewheel has already been lifted off the\n ground.\n",
        "choicetwo": "Because nosewheel steering has no effect on the value of VMCG.\n",
        "choicethree": "Because the nosewheel steering could become inoperative after an engine has failed.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Wing dihedral ;\n",
        "answer": "contributes to static lateral stability.\n",
        "choiceone": "is the only way of ensuring static lateral stability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "is particularly applied on aeroplanes with high mounted wings.\n",
        "choicethree": "does not affect static lateral stability.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Wing flutter can be prevented by ;\n",
        "answer": "ensuring that the wing CG is ahead of its torsional axis.\n",
        "choiceone": "increasing the aspect ratio of the wing.\n",
        "choicetwo": "mounting the engines on the fuselage.\n",
        "choicethree": "increasing wing elasticity.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Wing loading is the ratio between ;\n",
        "answer": "aeroplane weight and wing area.\n",
        "choiceone": "aeroplane weight and lift coefficient.\n",
        "choicetwo": "aeroplane weight and wing span.\n",
        "choicethree": "chord and aeroplane weight.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Wing spoilers are deflected symmetrically in flight in order to ;\n",
        "answer": "decelerate the aeroplane and/or increase its rate of descent.\n",
        "choiceone": "assist the ailerons in obtaining a higher roll rate.\n",
        "choicetwo": "improve glide performance ( increase lift/drag ratio ).\n",
        "choicethree": "prevent aeroplane yaw.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Wing sweep angle is the angle between ;\n",
        "answer": "the quarter-chord line of the wing and the lateral axis.\n",
        "choiceone": "the wing plane and the horizontal with the aeroplane in an unbanked , level condition.\n",
        "choicetwo": "the leading edge of the wing and the lateral axis.\n",
        "choicethree": "the quarter-chord line of the wing and the normal axis.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Wing twist ( geometric and aerodynamic ) is used to ;\n 1. improve stall characteristics.\n 2. reduce induced drag.\n 3. reduce interference drag.\n 4. increase VMO.\n The combination that regroups all of the correct statements is ;\n",
        "answer": "1 , 2.\n",
        "choiceone": "2 , 3.\n",
        "choicetwo": "3 , 4.\n",
        "choicethree": "1 , 3.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Winglets ;\n",
        "answer": "decrease the induced drag.\n",
        "choiceone": "decrease the static lateral stability.\n",
        "choicetwo": "create an elliptical lift distribution.\n",
        "choicethree": "increase the manoeuvrability.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "With increasing altitude and constant IAS the static lateral stability (1) and the dynamic lateral/directional stability (2) of an\naeroplane with swept-back wing will ;\n",
        "answer": "(1) increase , (2) decrease.\n",
        "choiceone": "(1) increase , (2) increase.\n",
        "choicetwo": "(1) decrease , (2) increase.\n",
        "choicethree": "(1) decrease , (2) decrease.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "With increasing angle of attack , the stagnation point will move (I) ........ and the point of lowest pressure will move (II) ........\nRespectively (I) and (II) are ;\n",
        "answer": "(I) down , (II) forward.\n",
        "choiceone": "(I) up , (II) forward.\n",
        "choicetwo": "(I) down , (II) aft.\n",
        "choicethree": "(I) up , (II) aft.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "With respect to the gyroscopic effects of precession acting upon the clockwise rotating propeller of a single acting aeroplane\n( when viewed from behind ) ;\n i. The effect of pitch up is right yaw.\n ii. The effect of right yaw is pitch down.\n",
        "answer": "i. is correct , ii. is correct.\n",
        "choiceone": "i. is correct , ii. is incorrect.\n",
        "choicetwo": "i. is incorrect , ii. is incorrect.\n",
        "choicethree": "i. is incorrect , ii. is correct.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Yaw is followed by roll because the ;\n",
        "answer": "yawing motion generated by rudder deflection causes a speed increase of the outer wing , which increases the\n lift on that wing so the aeroplane starts to roll in the same direction as the yaw.\n",
        "choiceone": "rolling motion generated by rudder deflection causes a speed increase of the outer wing , which increases the\n lift on that wing so the aeroplane starts to roll in the direction of the turn.\n",
        "choicetwo": "yawing motion generated by rudder deflection causes a speed increase of the inner wing , which increase the\n lift on that wing so the aeroplane starts to roll in the same direction as the yaw.\n",
        "choicethree": "rudder is located above the longitudinal axis and when it is deflected , it causes a rolling moment in the same\n direction as the yaw.\n",
        "source": "Principles_of_Flight___1311_soru__.pdf-_1_.txt"
    }
]